 I have been reading the results of the ITL Research . A research made by Microsoft, UNESCO, INTEL, ... across 7 countries asking students, teachers and school leaders about how school is changing and moving towards the 21st century skills. Finland, Russia, Indonesia, Australia, UK, Mexico and Senegal The report is large but I'll just comment a few ideas that quickly came to mind mind while reading. "while ICT use in teaching is becoming more common, ICT use by students in their learning is still an exception" Teachers use technology but things didn't change that much with it. Of course we provided variety to our lessons and we are able to show videos, audio and animations which help students to understand better the concepts, but in principle is the same: we are talking and they are listening. Unless we extend our richer lessons beyond the classroom and our students can reach to the contents 24/7. These thing we couldn't do it before ICT in education. "even when the ICT are used by the students, the level of complexity of the uses is low and the tasks are  individual and used for personal improvement" Internet searches, report writing or practising routine skills don't give our students further knowledge. It is diffeent, which is good, but it is pretty much the same than we do before. The ITL research that these simple uses of the ICT in the lessons take the 79% of the uses, while the high level uses of the ICT, those that give our students skills to afford future works, are barely offered in a 20% of the cases. "21st century skills are not clearly defined, and there is no clear idea how to design associated learning activities" We are still teaching using a model that didn't change in the last 50 years; we are still preparing our students for works that don't exist. But the problem is that those skills that we are teaching are the easiest to evaluate. Routine task are very easy to assess. You know them or not. Project based learning, knowledge building or solving problems are not that easy. Students learn future skills when educators structure learning activities that require them. We have to trust that giving the skills we'll reach the contents with even more efficiency that using teachers based models. "using such a different countries in the researches we got consistent results and we realize that problems are basically the same everywhere" These results could be taken form every school in every country of the world no matter if it's public or private; if it's in a city or in a little village. What we need is to face this reality and try to develop skills and competences with the resources we have. "Nobody made a greater mistake than he who did nothing because he could do only a little." Edmond Burke Let me finish with antoher quote which gives the title of this post. It was said by Prof. Seymour Papert (1998) the father of educational computing: "My goal in life is to find ways in which children can use technology as a constructive medium to do things that they could not do before; to do things at a level of complexity that was not previously accessible to children ]] Ovi Barcelo (Spain, Microsoft certified trainer), Luis Fernandes (Portugal, Microsoft expert educator) and Joao Cunha (Portugal, Microsoft expert educator) have built a bilingual blog to help you choose the best applications for education available at Microsoft Store in Windows 8. We know you have little time to navigate through the thousands apps which are available, so we are selecting the most suitable for your lessons. Visit us at http://apps.teachnology.es/ and feel free to comment your experience. We are also looking for contributors in other languages, so, if you want to join the project, just tell us. We are partners in learning! ]] Since we have moved from live@edu to Office365 I have been looking for something like this. We all know that SharePoint is a professional environment and, sometimes, it is too "high level" to implement it in our school or lessons. With this template I have uploaded here, we can have a suitable environment ready to start our lessons. First of all, here is how it looks Classroom in SharePoint for Office365 Let's observe it closely. Document creation: Document creation On the upper right corner we have direct link to document creation. Using the Office Web-apps  our students can create easily Word documents, Excel spreadsheets, PowerPoint presentations, or a OneNote with a simple click. These documents are directly stored in "My documents" in this classroom. Links bar: Links bar There are three button on the left side of the page which must be personalized to make them useful. To do so, follow this simple steps. a) Go to Site Actions - View All Site Content-URL Settings (Under Lists) b) There you will find the three URL that need to be personalized. They are IM, Calendar and Outlook. c) Select an item and set it to point to where you want. NOTE: I didn't find necessary a link to point to IM, so this link (the one with the smile) I made it point to the main page of the site. Navigation bar: Navigation bar Automatically this template creates four sections which can be reached with its navigation bar. The sections are exactly what you need to start you classroom in a second. You can add more libraries or resources later; as many as you want. You can take a quick look at the last documents or posts in the different sections with the viewer at the bottom of the main page. Documents viewer: New documents viewer The sections are: Class materials : Two libraries where the common and the personal documents for this course can be stored Class Materials view Class wiki: Just a wiki where important concepts of the course can be created by the students or by the teachers. You can set, as a teacher, rules for it. Class Wiki view Class calendar : A common calendar for the whole group Class Calendar view Class discussions: A forum where, for example, questions or doubts can be solved by the community. Class Discussions view As we can see, with this template is very simple and quick to create a perfect virtual environment for your classroom. Installation process: First of all, obviously, download it here In the package you downloaded there are clear instructions about how to do it. I hope you fin it as useful as I have found it. ]] After watching this video one thought came to mind mind. What if  "We will no longer search for information and contents, they will find us via social media". I don't see it faraway from where we are right now. Students are recording their activity while they are surfing across different social media, and as the advertisement are changing depending on the webs they are visiting and the clicks that they are doing, the contents and information around their searches are changing depending on it. So, again, the information will look for us. Social media knows a lot about us, so, why this information will not be used to select what kind of information we want to know? But the question is: Where are we teachers in all this new environment? For me the answer is clear: In the school with our students, as always. What is changing (I believe it has already changed) is what are we doing there? If we are still the main source of information, we won't be outdated soon, we are already outdated! How can be compete against the information is in the Net? 10+1 tips to be a real 21st century (and beyond) teacher: Not all the information is found in the Internet is true. Help your students to be critical with the information they find. Is very pretentious to think that students will learn by their own. Motivate your students to learn and to build their own knowledge. The process is long. It is not only about getting information. Guide your students to the process of getting the information, processing it and assessing it, in order to get profit of it. Society today is practical. Focus your lessons in "Real-life" issues closer to your students. Play Probably this is the most difficult part, but assessment has to change. It will be a loss of time if we end it up with an regular exam. Assess the whole process of learning but not only the content . Listen to your students . They can help us to improve our methods. Update yourself . We all know how difficult is to be updated nowadays, but if we want to atlk their own language we have to know something about their world. Build knowledge relating different areas in your curriculum . Isolated subjects have less and less meaning these days. Social studies, languages or ICT skills, for example, are very difficult to forget while you want your students to do an Internet research. Be patient . Don't change the world in one day. Don't blame on the national standards, the lack of resources or your students behavior. As I said to my students. Take the plunge! Move one step ahead. It works ]] No chitchatting, let's get down to work A) Buy a domain and a hosting. There are many companies. I have my domain in 1and1. But this point is up to you. At this point you have finish the money investment during your LMS installation. B) Install a Moodle (1.9) in your domain. Now I will redirect the post to the official site where you can find the files and the best instructions. http://docs.moodle.org/19/en/Installing_Moodle C) Create a subdomain Depending on your hosting there are multiple options but they are mostly the same. Login into your host panel. Youll see the link domains Create a subdomain the the user interface. Youll find a button like create a subdomain or something like this Write the name of your subdomain. for example  edu.domain.com D) Start your live@edu campus Go to http://www.microsoft.com/liveatedu/enroll-and-deploy-process.aspx and click on the button "Enroll your school" at the upper right part of the screen. Click on the radio button Ready to enroll in the next screen. Step 1 of 2 . Fill the information required to identify your school. The most important part is the last field Domain Here you have to type the subdomain you would like to use in your live@edu mail address. For example, in this case the email addresses will be mary@edu.domain.com Step 2 of 2 . Fill the fields with the administrator information, password and ID E) Confirm ownership of the domain. This part could be a bit tricky if your are not familiar with domains and hostings. The easiest way is using an MX record. You will find the option in Alternative methods to prove domain ownership The MX record used to prove domain ownership must be in the exact format displayed when you are asked to prove ownership. For example, if your token is 0cbc8689f5394f86bc7b84983e30d3, specify the following: Target or Destination or Mail Server 0cbc8689f5394f86bc7b84983e30d3.msv1.invalid Priority 100 or Low Typically, DNS records that you create for new domains are detected quickly. Updates to the DNS records of existing domains may take longer to be detected. However, it should take no longer than 72 hours before the new record is detected. Until the new DNS record is detected, the Service Management Portal will display the message asking you to confirm domain ownership. To check if the DNS record has been detected, click Refresh. Detailed instructions for specific domain registrars Create DNS Records at 11 for Live@edu Create DNS Records at CentralNic for Live@edu Create DNS Records at eNom Central for Live@edu Create DNS Records at GoDaddy.com for Live@edu Create DNS Records at Network Solutions for Live@edu Create DNS Records at Register.com for Live@edu Create DNS Records at Yahoo! for Live@edu Create DNS Records using BIND for Live@edu Create DNS records using Windows-Based DNS for Live@edu Now click the refresh button in your admin page (Remember that it is in http://eduadmin.live.com ) your ownership will be confirmed. F) Create User Accounts After you set up a Live@edu domain and configure DNS to direct e-mail to it, you're ready to create user accounts. Each user account has its own Windows Live ID and a mailbox with 10 GB of storage. There are two ways to create user accounts with the Exchange Control Panel. Read on to decide which works best for you. Create accounts one at a time If you have to create a few test users or occasionally create a new user, use the Exchange Control Panel. To do this, sign in to the Exchange Control Panel, and select Manage My Organization Users Groups Mailboxes New. Create lots of user accounts If you have to create a lot of user accounts during initial user provisioning, you can use the Exchange Control Panel to import users using a CSV file. This is the easiest way to create lots of accounts. Again, sign in the Exchange Control Panel, and select Manage My Organization Users Groups Mailboxes Import users. Video: Exchange Online: How To: Bulk Import Users using a CSV file Watch this demo to learn how to import new users Here you can see an example of CSV file This table describes the attributes required to import new users. The import process will fail if any one of these attributes isn't included in the header row of the CSV import file. Note Type the attributes exactly as they are shown. Attributes can't contain spaces. They must be a single word. For example, First Name is invalid. You must use FirstName . Attribute Description Name Name specifies an identifier for the user. The value for Name must be unique in your domain. Important The value of Name is used as the display name in the list of mailboxes in the Exchange Control Panel and in the shared address book if you don't include the DisplayName attribute, which is an optional attribute. EmailAddress EmailAddress specifies the e-mail address of a new user. It is also used to create the corresponding Windows Live ID. The value of EmailAddress must be unique in your domain. FirstName FirstName specifies the user's first name. LastName LastName specifies the user's last name. Password Password is the initial password assigned to a new Windows Live ID that is created for a mailbox user. If you are a Live@edu organization, you can force users to change their password when they sign in to their account for the first time by using the ForceChangePassword attribute. Note The option to require users to change their password isn't available for Microsoft Office 365 e-mail organizations. Live@edu is set. A lot of features can be changed and personalized now, but with these steps you are ready to roll! G) Create users in Moodle You can use the same CSV file to import the users to Moodle, but with some changes. Copy and paste the CSVf file and your computer and change the name of the columns, like this. live@edu moodle Name username EmailAddress email FirstName firstname LastName lastname P assword password But a very important thing is to add 2 more columns in the CSV for Moodle. auth In this column you have to write liveid for all the users msn In this column you have to write the students live@edu mail address. H) Install the plugin in Moodle 1. Add the block live services to your moodle Download the plugin from its official site clicking on  Try it . Unzip it and upload it by FTP to your Moodle site. It will use many folders, but if you upload it directly with the distribution given in the .zip, all the files will be correctlly placed. This is how the folder looks: 2. Update moodle to recognise the block live id From the Moodle administration, click on "Notifications" The system will install the plugin automatically 3. Creating the app Now we have to login with our liveID into https://manage.dev.live.com/ to create an app Create new application (From  My apps  and  create application ) a) Give a name and set the language b) Our app has created a  Client ID  and a  Cliente Secret"  which well use later. c) Let's edit the app options so we need to go to  API settings  and edit, in  redirect domain  the URL of our Moodle site followed by /auth/liveid/webauth-handler.php 4. Configuring the block in moodle Now is the moment to activate all the work to make it run  in Moodle So we go to Users Authentication Manage authentication And show (clicking on the eye to open it) the option Windows Live ID  In the same screen, at the bottom we can add an html code to show an "liveID login box" in the login page of Moodle. It could be something like this. div style="font-size:120%" pspan style="font-family: 'Segoe UI Light', Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;font-size: 1.6em;color: #333333;"Utiliza tu img alt="Windows Live" height="23" longdesc="Windows Live Logo" src= http://yourdomain.com/blocks/live_services/shared/images/WindowsLive.png width="175" IDbr / para autenticarte en Moodle/spanspan style="font-family: 'Segoe Script', 'Felt Tip Roman', 'Comic Sans MS';font-size: 1.6em;color: #333333;" siempre!/span/p div style="line-height:32px" a href= http://yourdomain.com/auth/liveid/login.php style="background:transparent url( http://yourdomian.com/blocks/live_services/shared/images/glossybutton88.gif) no-repeat scroll top right;height: 32px;width:88px;display: block;float:left;margin-right: 0px;text-decoration: none;text-align:center;color: #333333;font-family: 'Segoe UI', Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;font-size:1.2em;font-weight:normal;"span style="height: 32px;display: block;float:left;margin-right: 0px;text-decoration: none;color: #333333;font-family: 'Segoe UI', Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;font-size:1.2em;font-weight:normal;line-height:12px;padding:9px 0px 11px 0px;background: transparent url( http://yourdomain.com/blocks/live_services/shared/images/glossybtn32.gif) no-repeat;; background-color: transparent"Entra/span/a /div 5. Set the secret key and application id to your Moodle Go to the options: Modules Blocks Microsoft Live Services a) Type the data of our app b) Mail and calendar. If you activate it your students will access to their mail and calendar with a simple click and without leaving the Moodle. In  Service Account  type the impersonation account (in the next step I will explain how to create an impersonation account ) of live@edu and its password and in the Outlook URL you should write the address of your inbox without the /owa part , not even the final /. b.1) Create an impersonation account. These kind of accounts allow the Outlook users to login into their mailboxes without typing again user and password and doing it from an external application Create in the control panel of live@edu ( http://domains.live.com ) an account like this impersonation@yourdomian.com Now run locally Windows PowerShell in administrator mode and type: $LiveCred = Get-Credential Login as live@edu administrator $Session = New-PSSession -ConfigurationName Microsoft.Exchange -ConnectionUri https://ps.outlook.com/powershell/ -Credential $LiveCred -Authentication Basic -AllowRedirection Get into the users administration Import-PSSession $Session And finally New-ManagementRoleAssignment -Name:EWSImpersonation -Role:ApplicationImpersonation -User:impersonation@yourdomain.com It will give permissions to impersonation . c) Messenger y Bing. If we want Bing and Messenger just activate both of them. About searching a couple of things: There are two buttons in the search bar The regular search in Bing. Typing and searching, Powerset Search . I didn't know it before. To use it, select a text and click on the button. The words highlighted will be searched in Bing. Note: The Java script in MS4M.zip is not working properly. I have fixed it  - search.js, here .- Just overwrite the file in http://yourdomain/blocks/live_services/services/search 7. Mesenger within the courses Set a   Sticky block  Just choose from the dropdown menu course page and the block Microsoft Live Services New " home-made " block I have programmed a HTML block to implement in moodle once you can access to it with your LiveID. With it, you can: Create a new document with just one click. ( Word, Excel, PowerPoint or OneNote) Upload a document Access to "Shared documents" Make a document search in Skydrive The first step is create a new HTML block. Let's see the code step-by step:: 1. To create a new document Jus liink the images you want to use (in this case Office icons) to the next URLs For Word: https://skydrive.live.com/?sc=documentsxt=docxref=1action=CreateWord For Excel: https://skydrive.live.com/?sc=documentsxt=xlsxref=1action=CreateExcel For PowerPoint: https://skydrive.live.com/?sc=documentsxt=xlsxref=1action=CreatePowerPoint For OneNote https://skydrive.live.com/?sc=documentsxt=xlsxref=1action=CreateOneNote 2. Upload a document Link the text you like with https://skydrive.live.com/P.mvc#!/choosefolder.aspx 3. Access to shared documents https://skydrive.live.com/?qt=shared 4. Searchj form This one is a bit complicated, but no so :) form class="c_search_mc" id="c_search_SearchBox_f" style="background-image: none;" onsubmit="function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { return $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].doSubmit(); } } } } }" action=" https://home.live.com/search " method="get" target="_top"/form/p p align="center" label for="c_search_SearchBox_box" /label input name="query" title="Buscar documentos y mas" class="c_search_box c_ml TextItalic" id="c_search_SearchBox_box" onfocus="function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].focus(); } } } } }" onblur="function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].blur(); } } } } }" type="text" maxlength="500" autocomplete="Off" / input title="Buscar" class="c_search_go" id="c_search_SearchBox_go" style="background-image: none;" type="submit" value="Buscar" / input name="mkt" type="hidden" value="es-ES" / input name="scope" type="hidden" value="Documents" / input name="consumerid" type="hidden" value="Live.Folders" / Here you have the whole HTML code: table style="width: 200px;" tbody tr td class="style2" colspan="4"Create a new online document with  Microsoft Office web apps...br /br / /td /tr tr td a title="New Word Document" href="https://office.live.com/newdocument.aspx/.Documents?xt=docxref=1" target="_blank" img width="32" height="32" alt="Create new Word document" src="http://URL/word.png" //a /td td a title="New Excel Document" href="https://office.live.com/newdocument.aspx/.Documents?xt=xlsxref=1" target="_blank" img width="32" height="32" alt="Create new Excel document" src="http://URL/excel.png" //a /td td a title="New PowerPoint Document" href="https://office.live.com/newdocument.aspx/.Documents?xt=pptxref=1" target="_blank" img width="32" height="32" alt="Create new PowerPoint document" src="http://URL/powerpoint.png" //a /td td a title="New OneNote Document" href="https://office.live.com/newdocument.aspx/.Documents?xt=oneref=1" target="_blank" img width="32" height="32" alt="Create new OneNote document" src="http://URL/onenote.png" //a /td /tr tr td colspan="4" a title="Upload a file" href="https://skydrive.live.com/choosefolder.aspx" target="_blank"Upload a file/a /td /tr tr td colspan="4"a title="Your shared folder" href="https://skydrive.live.com/#qt=shared" target="_blank"Your shared folder/a /td /tr/tbody /table p form class="c_search_mc" id="c_search_SearchBox_f" style="background-image: none;" onsubmit="function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { return $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].doSubmit(); } } } }" action="https://home.live.com/search" method="get" target="_top" p align="center" label for="c_search_SearchBox_box" /label input name="query" title="Buscar documentos y mas" class="c_search_box c_ml TextItalic" id="c_search_SearchBox_box" onfocus="function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].focus(); } } } }" onblur="function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].blur(); } } } }" type="text" maxlength="500" autocomplete="Off" / input title="Buscar" class="c_search_go" id="c_search_SearchBox_go" style="background-image: none;" type="submit" value="Buscar" / input name="mkt" type="hidden" value="es-ES" / input name="scope" type="hidden" value="Documents" / input name="consumerid" type="hidden" value="Live.Folders" / /p/form /p Well, this is just a new idea, but the thin is that once you have logged in with a LiveID account, the rest is just imagination. I believe this is it. Please comment if you have any problems or suggestions. Thanks. ]] Q: Teenagers today are always punching their cellphones. It is almost an addiction. A: We can not expect from schools and students to forget about their "addiction" and to get back into a life where mobile phones don't exist and they were not part of our daily life. Q: Young people have a very active virtual social life. They spend more time working in their virtual friends than with the real social interaction. A: If they are spending so much time within a social network, is it not an important part of their life? If we expect a global education taking care about every student perspective, we can't forget about their life in the social networks, as we can not forget about sports, arts or social skills. Q: Students today the can't afford frustration. A: I have seen them trying and trying after a "Game Over" screen in a video game. We have thousand different ways of introducing video games in the curriculum, why not? Q: They are passionate about what they like and don't care about the "important" things. A: Give them the opportunity of work about real life problems. Make them see the point of studying capitals of Europe, Physics or Mathematics. Q: I don't have time to learn about all the new software and hardware are coming out everyday. A: Your students do! give them the chance to use the tools they want to get where you want them to go. Q: Working the memory is very important. Don't tell me they don't have to learn the list of the kings. A: Completely agree. Memory is a skill we have to work in the school, but it can not be the only one. If maths teacher is working memory as science teacher, history teacher and language teacher, is not the memory a little bit over-trained? Q: MS Word corrects the misspellings of the students. A: What do you do when you find a word misspelled in a student notebook? Q: Underline it in red and tell the right way of doing it A: Same as Word! Anyway, you won't use only MS Word to write as you won't use the notebook to do so. Q: They don't listen to me! A: Maybe at the beginning they do, but we have been talking for years. There are many different ways of delivering content and many different ways to connect to different people (in your school and in the world) to  give variety to your lessons. Q: They are used to "right here, right now". A: Perfect! Upload your lessons to the cloud, they could access to them whenever and wherever they want. Q: They don't know any of the important things. A: I can't tell what is more important to know, the list of capitals of Europe or how to plan a trip to one of them. I can't tell, seriously. ]] English version | Version en espanol We did it! We love the way of thinking " Learning by doing" and keeping in this direction we have developed Julio Verne 2.0, our first Windows 8 application that you can download here. http://apps.microsoft.com/webpdp/app/2bc67eb5-a015-425c-a3d0-a7c6e0d9c112 In this app you can have a glimpse of our projects in the ICT department sorted by categories. A first step in this world which is going to be followed for many new apps to make our students get the most of this new way of working that Windows 8 offers to education. Here you have some shots. We hope you like it. Lo hicimos! Nos encanta la manera de pensar de "aprender haciendo" y, siguiendo esta direccion hemos desarrollado Julio Verne 2.0 , nuestra primera app para Windows 8 que puedes descargar aqui: http://apps.microsoft.com/webpdp/app/2bc67eb5-a015-425c-a3d0-a7c6e0d9c112 En esta aplicacion puedes echar un vistazo a nuestros proyectos en Nuevas Tecnologias listados por categorias. Un primer paso en este mundo que estara seguido por muchas nuevas aplicaciones para hacer que nuestros alumnos consigan el maximo de esta nueva manera de trabajar que Windows 8 ofrece para educacion. Arriba podeis ver algunas capturas de la aplicacion. Esperemos que os guste. ]] A week ago we've got the letter that confirmed that our live@edu campus was ready to move to Office365. I'm not and IT specialist, I just manage the IT department of my school, so I thought that it will be tough and very complicated. Nothing further from the truth The first thing I had to do was to follow a simple "clicks" path. Do you want to upgrade? Yes! In, no more than 10 minutes, all the process was finished and I found myself managing a professional Exchange, Lync and SharePoint site. The password issue Once you have migrated, Skydrive changes into a regular Live Service not managed anymore for the school, so you need two passwords to separate the services of Office365 and Skydrive. Every user of my school has to go to https://eduupgrade.office365.com and change his/her password. The new password will be used for Office365 More or less, it looks like this Login and services in live@edu Login and services of Office365 and Skydrive A little rock on the road Live@edu only managed and Exchange Service so it is what you find when you first go to Office365. There's no trace of Lync or SharePoint. After some questions in the forums, I realized that the license you got automatically is the A1 plan, which only includes the Exchange Service. What I did was to buy licenses of the A2 plan, which includes Lync and SharePoint. All my licences cost 0 , because the plan A2 is free for education. Then, just had to re-assign licenses to all my users and, voila!, Lync, Exchange and SharePoint free for my school. The world of DNS As I implemented live@edu in my school, I was used to manage DNS in my domain. A couple of new adjustments have to be done to make Lync and SharePoint work. A now... what? Well, the thing is that I'm a teacher, "just" a teacher. I mean, I'm not an IT specialist and I have in front of me such a professional tools as Lync or SharePoint to manage and implement in my school. But, guess what? I wish all my problems were like these ones. ]] Many devices can get into our classrooms nowadays, but depending on what you want get from your students and from the devices themselves you can use one or another. Here I show them in increasingly pedagogical potential Smartphone: Clearly they are not going to be the primary device for powerful learning, but they do allow for some basic level collaboration, communication, gathering of resources, and provide quick access to information. Internet search, dictionaries, twitting or shooting photos and videos are useful resources we can use in our lessons with just a phone. Today, almost everybody, is walking though life with powerful computers in their pockets, and, if your students have already know how to use them, why not take advantage from it? Slates: More powerful than mobiles, but in my point of view, there is not such a difference but the bigger screen. The level of collaboration is minimum and the control can teachers have over them are less than nothing. Almost same apps than mobiles and still reinforcing the isolation of individuals. But I have to say that, for some ages or disabilities are great. Storytelling for kindergarten, for example, or accessibility for certain disabilities are the perfect excuse to introduce these devices in our classrooms, but I can't see them none in primary or secondary school. For digital books are great as well, but they are still too expensive compering the investment to the possibilities they have. Laptops: The perfect device if you compare the price and the possibilities. They allow real multitasking, and serious creation. They allow the pulling of information from multiple sources simultaneously; manipulation of that information in many forms, and the creation of new knowledge and understandings. Tablet-PC What if you have the power of the apps in the slates and the multitasking and serious creation of the laptops in one device? I believe is the solution for education. You can have the individual variety of  the actual apps and the powerful learning possibilities of software. Now we've got an excuse to invest in digital textbooks, because, once you have work with them you can edit a presentation, share it or plug your usb to bring it somewhere else. You can print, get into a domain, control the access of your students, and with the digitized stylus make a real corrections of you lessons work. Until "yesterday" it was a dream. I believe (and I hope so) that Windows8 has many thing to say about this. The problem could be the price... keep your finger crossed. ]] As vice president of education for Microsoft Corp.s Worldwide Public Sector organization, Anthony Salcito works with education institutions and partners globally to embrace technology to optimize learning environments and student achievement. He has got a blog called DailyEdventures where everyday focused in one educator around the world who can help others to move formward in this difficult world of education and innovation. Today (August 14th) was my turn. A brief interview has been published here where you can reed some thought about my point of view in education. This success has been the fruit of working with Microsoft Partners in Learning for the past three years and of trying to innovate in my school everyday. Here you can see the moment when Anthony is giving me Julio Verne's award as a Mentor School in the Partners in Learning Microsoft Program. It is a great honor, sincerely. ]] STEM is the acronym for Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics. And why is so important? In United States realized that there is a shortage of skilled workers in these areas so they had? to look for them beyond their country limits. Deep studies determined that these areas are isolated in the schools curriculum, instead of being integrated in every area. So, is our future heading to a STEM education? This infographic can give us a clue. ]] I have been reading the results of the ITL Research . A research made by Microsoft, UNESCO, INTEL, ... across 7 countries asking students, teachers and school leaders about how school is changing and moving towards the 21st century skills. Finland, Russia, Indonesia, Australia, UK, Mexico and Senegal The report is large but I'll just comment a few ideas that quickly came to mind mind while reading. "while ICT use in teaching is becoming more common, ICT use by students in their learning is still an exception" Teachers use technology but things didn't change that much with it. Of course we provided variety to our lessons and we are able to show videos, audio and animations which help students to understand better the concepts, but in principle is the same: we are talking and they are listening. Unless we extend our richer lessons beyond the classroom and our students can reach to the contents 24/7. These thing we couldn't do it before ICT in education. "even when the ICT are used by the students, the level of complexity of the uses is low and the tasks are  individual and used for personal improvement" Internet searches, report writing or practising routine skills don't give our students further knowledge. It is diffeent, which is good, but it is pretty much the same than we do before. The ITL research that these simple uses of the ICT in the lessons take the 79% of the uses, while the high level uses of the ICT, those that give our students skills to afford future works, are barely offered in a 20% of the cases. "21st century skills are not clearly defined, and there is no clear idea how to design associated learning activities" We are still teaching using a model that didn't change in the last 50 years; we are still preparing our students for works that don't exist. But the problem is that those skills that we are teaching are the easiest to evaluate. Routine task are very easy to assess. You know them or not. Project based learning, knowledge building or solving problems are not that easy. Students learn future skills when educators structure learning activities that require them. We have to trust that giving the skills we'll reach the contents with even more efficiency that using teachers based models. "using such a different countries in the researches we got consistent results and we realize that problems are basically the same everywhere" These results could be taken form every school in every country of the world no matter if it's public or private; if it's in a city or in a little village. What we need is to face this reality and try to develop skills and competences with the resources we have. "Nobody made a greater mistake than he who did nothing because he could do only a little." Edmond Burke Let me finish with antoher quote which gives the title of this post. It was said by Prof. Seymour Papert (1998) the father of educational computing: "My goal in life is to find ways in which children can use technology as a constructive medium to do things that they could not do before; to do things at a level of complexity that was not previously accessible to children ]] Ovi Barcelo (Spain, Microsoft certified trainer), Luis Fernandes (Portugal, Microsoft expert educator) and Joao Cunha (Portugal, Microsoft expert educator) have built a bilingual blog to help you choose the best applications for education available at Microsoft Store in Windows 8. We know you have little time to navigate through the thousands apps which are available, so we are selecting the most suitable for your lessons. Visit us at http://apps.teachnology.es/ and feel free to comment your experience. We are also looking for contributors in other languages, so, if you want to join the project, just tell us. We are partners in learning! ]] Since we have moved from live@edu to Office365 I have been looking for something like this. We all know that SharePoint is a professional environment and, sometimes, it is too "high level" to implement it in our school or lessons. With this template I have uploaded here, we can have a suitable environment ready to start our lessons. First of all, here is how it looks Classroom in SharePoint for Office365 Let's observe it closely. Document creation: Document creation On the upper right corner we have direct link to document creation. Using the Office Web-apps  our students can create easily Word documents, Excel spreadsheets, PowerPoint presentations, or a OneNote with a simple click. These documents are directly stored in "My documents" in this classroom. Links bar: Links bar There are three button on the left side of the page which must be personalized to make them useful. To do so, follow this simple steps. a) Go to Site Actions - View All Site Content-URL Settings (Under Lists) b) There you will find the three URL that need to be personalized. They are IM, Calendar and Outlook. c) Select an item and set it to point to where you want. NOTE: I didn't find necessary a link to point to IM, so this link (the one with the smile) I made it point to the main page of the site. Navigation bar: Navigation bar Automatically this template creates four sections which can be reached with its navigation bar. The sections are exactly what you need to start you classroom in a second. You can add more libraries or resources later; as many as you want. You can take a quick look at the last documents or posts in the different sections with the viewer at the bottom of the main page. Documents viewer: New documents viewer The sections are: Class materials : Two libraries where the common and the personal documents for this course can be stored Class Materials view Class wiki: Just a wiki where important concepts of the course can be created by the students or by the teachers. You can set, as a teacher, rules for it. Class Wiki view Class calendar : A common calendar for the whole group Class Calendar view Class discussions: A forum where, for example, questions or doubts can be solved by the community. Class Discussions view As we can see, with this template is very simple and quick to create a perfect virtual environment for your classroom. Installation process: First of all, obviously, download it here In the package you downloaded there are clear instructions about how to do it. I hope you fin it as useful as I have found it. ]] After watching this video one thought came to mind mind. What if  "We will no longer search for information and contents, they will find us via social media". I don't see it faraway from where we are right now. Students are recording their activity while they are surfing across different social media, and as the advertisement are changing depending on the webs they are visiting and the clicks that they are doing, the contents and information around their searches are changing depending on it. So, again, the information will look for us. Social media knows a lot about us, so, why this information will not be used to select what kind of information we want to know? But the question is: Where are we teachers in all this new environment? For me the answer is clear: In the school with our students, as always. What is changing (I believe it has already changed) is what are we doing there? If we are still the main source of information, we won't be outdated soon, we are already outdated! How can be compete against the information is in the Net? 10+1 tips to be a real 21st century (and beyond) teacher: Not all the information is found in the Internet is true. Help your students to be critical with the information they find. Is very pretentious to think that students will learn by their own. Motivate your students to learn and to build their own knowledge. The process is long. It is not only about getting information. Guide your students to the process of getting the information, processing it and assessing it, in order to get profit of it. Society today is practical. Focus your lessons in "Real-life" issues closer to your students. Play Probably this is the most difficult part, but assessment has to change. It will be a loss of time if we end it up with an regular exam. Assess the whole process of learning but not only the content . Listen to your students . They can help us to improve our methods. Update yourself . We all know how difficult is to be updated nowadays, but if we want to atlk their own language we have to know something about their world. Build knowledge relating different areas in your curriculum . Isolated subjects have less and less meaning these days. Social studies, languages or ICT skills, for example, are very difficult to forget while you want your students to do an Internet research. Be patient . Don't change the world in one day. Don't blame on the national standards, the lack of resources or your students behavior. As I said to my students. Take the plunge! Move one step ahead. It works ]] No chitchatting, let's get down to work A) Buy a domain and a hosting. There are many companies. I have my domain in 1and1. But this point is up to you. At this point you have finish the money investment during your LMS installation. B) Install a Moodle (1.9) in your domain. Now I will redirect the post to the official site where you can find the files and the best instructions. http://docs.moodle.org/19/en/Installing_Moodle C) Create a subdomain Depending on your hosting there are multiple options but they are mostly the same. Login into your host panel. Youll see the link domains Create a subdomain the the user interface. Youll find a button like create a subdomain or something like this Write the name of your subdomain. for example  edu.domain.com D) Start your live@edu campus Go to http://www.microsoft.com/liveatedu/enroll-and-deploy-process.aspx and click on the button "Enroll your school" at the upper right part of the screen. Click on the radio button Ready to enroll in the next screen. Step 1 of 2 . Fill the information required to identify your school. The most important part is the last field Domain Here you have to type the subdomain you would like to use in your live@edu mail address. For example, in this case the email addresses will be mary@edu.domain.com Step 2 of 2 . Fill the fields with the administrator information, password and ID E) Confirm ownership of the domain. This part could be a bit tricky if your are not familiar with domains and hostings. The easiest way is using an MX record. You will find the option in Alternative methods to prove domain ownership The MX record used to prove domain ownership must be in the exact format displayed when you are asked to prove ownership. For example, if your token is 0cbc8689f5394f86bc7b84983e30d3, specify the following: Target or Destination or Mail Server 0cbc8689f5394f86bc7b84983e30d3.msv1.invalid Priority 100 or Low Typically, DNS records that you create for new domains are detected quickly. Updates to the DNS records of existing domains may take longer to be detected. However, it should take no longer than 72 hours before the new record is detected. Until the new DNS record is detected, the Service Management Portal will display the message asking you to confirm domain ownership. To check if the DNS record has been detected, click Refresh. Detailed instructions for specific domain registrars Create DNS Records at 11 for Live@edu Create DNS Records at CentralNic for Live@edu Create DNS Records at eNom Central for Live@edu Create DNS Records at GoDaddy.com for Live@edu Create DNS Records at Network Solutions for Live@edu Create DNS Records at Register.com for Live@edu Create DNS Records at Yahoo! for Live@edu Create DNS Records using BIND for Live@edu Create DNS records using Windows-Based DNS for Live@edu Now click the refresh button in your admin page (Remember that it is in http://eduadmin.live.com ) your ownership will be confirmed. F) Create User Accounts After you set up a Live@edu domain and configure DNS to direct e-mail to it, you're ready to create user accounts. Each user account has its own Windows Live ID and a mailbox with 10 GB of storage. There are two ways to create user accounts with the Exchange Control Panel. Read on to decide which works best for you. Create accounts one at a time If you have to create a few test users or occasionally create a new user, use the Exchange Control Panel. To do this, sign in to the Exchange Control Panel, and select Manage My Organization Users Groups Mailboxes New. Create lots of user accounts If you have to create a lot of user accounts during initial user provisioning, you can use the Exchange Control Panel to import users using a CSV file. This is the easiest way to create lots of accounts. Again, sign in the Exchange Control Panel, and select Manage My Organization Users Groups Mailboxes Import users. Video: Exchange Online: How To: Bulk Import Users using a CSV file Watch this demo to learn how to import new users Here you can see an example of CSV file This table describes the attributes required to import new users. The import process will fail if any one of these attributes isn't included in the header row of the CSV import file. Note Type the attributes exactly as they are shown. Attributes can't contain spaces. They must be a single word. For example, First Name is invalid. You must use FirstName . Attribute Description Name Name specifies an identifier for the user. The value for Name must be unique in your domain. Important The value of Name is used as the display name in the list of mailboxes in the Exchange Control Panel and in the shared address book if you don't include the DisplayName attribute, which is an optional attribute. EmailAddress EmailAddress specifies the e-mail address of a new user. It is also used to create the corresponding Windows Live ID. The value of EmailAddress must be unique in your domain. FirstName FirstName specifies the user's first name. LastName LastName specifies the user's last name. Password Password is the initial password assigned to a new Windows Live ID that is created for a mailbox user. If you are a Live@edu organization, you can force users to change their password when they sign in to their account for the first time by using the ForceChangePassword attribute. Note The option to require users to change their password isn't available for Microsoft Office 365 e-mail organizations. Live@edu is set. A lot of features can be changed and personalized now, but with these steps you are ready to roll! G) Create users in Moodle You can use the same CSV file to import the users to Moodle, but with some changes. Copy and paste the CSVf file and your computer and change the name of the columns, like this. live@edu moodle Name username EmailAddress email FirstName firstname LastName lastname P assword password But a very important thing is to add 2 more columns in the CSV for Moodle. auth In this column you have to write liveid for all the users msn In this column you have to write the students live@edu mail address. H) Install the plugin in Moodle 1. Add the block live services to your moodle Download the plugin from its official site clicking on  Try it . Unzip it and upload it by FTP to your Moodle site. It will use many folders, but if you upload it directly with the distribution given in the .zip, all the files will be correctlly placed. This is how the folder looks: 2. Update moodle to recognise the block live id From the Moodle administration, click on "Notifications" The system will install the plugin automatically 3. Creating the app Now we have to login with our liveID into https://manage.dev.live.com/ to create an app Create new application (From  My apps  and  create application ) a) Give a name and set the language b) Our app has created a  Client ID  and a  Cliente Secret"  which well use later. c) Let's edit the app options so we need to go to  API settings  and edit, in  redirect domain  the URL of our Moodle site followed by /auth/liveid/webauth-handler.php 4. Configuring the block in moodle Now is the moment to activate all the work to make it run  in Moodle So we go to Users Authentication Manage authentication And show (clicking on the eye to open it) the option Windows Live ID  In the same screen, at the bottom we can add an html code to show an "liveID login box" in the login page of Moodle. It could be something like this. div style="font-size:120%" pspan style="font-family: 'Segoe UI Light', Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;font-size: 1.6em;color: #333333;"Utiliza tu img alt="Windows Live" height="23" longdesc="Windows Live Logo" src= http://yourdomain.com/blocks/live_services/shared/images/WindowsLive.png width="175" IDbr / para autenticarte en Moodle/spanspan style="font-family: 'Segoe Script', 'Felt Tip Roman', 'Comic Sans MS';font-size: 1.6em;color: #333333;" siempre!/span/p div style="line-height:32px" a href= http://yourdomain.com/auth/liveid/login.php style="background:transparent url( http://yourdomian.com/blocks/live_services/shared/images/glossybutton88.gif) no-repeat scroll top right;height: 32px;width:88px;display: block;float:left;margin-right: 0px;text-decoration: none;text-align:center;color: #333333;font-family: 'Segoe UI', Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;font-size:1.2em;font-weight:normal;"span style="height: 32px;display: block;float:left;margin-right: 0px;text-decoration: none;color: #333333;font-family: 'Segoe UI', Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;font-size:1.2em;font-weight:normal;line-height:12px;padding:9px 0px 11px 0px;background: transparent url( http://yourdomain.com/blocks/live_services/shared/images/glossybtn32.gif) no-repeat;; background-color: transparent"Entra/span/a /div 5. Set the secret key and application id to your Moodle Go to the options: Modules Blocks Microsoft Live Services a) Type the data of our app b) Mail and calendar. If you activate it your students will access to their mail and calendar with a simple click and without leaving the Moodle. In  Service Account  type the impersonation account (in the next step I will explain how to create an impersonation account ) of live@edu and its password and in the Outlook URL you should write the address of your inbox without the /owa part , not even the final /. b.1) Create an impersonation account. These kind of accounts allow the Outlook users to login into their mailboxes without typing again user and password and doing it from an external application Create in the control panel of live@edu ( http://domains.live.com ) an account like this impersonation@yourdomian.com Now run locally Windows PowerShell in administrator mode and type: $LiveCred = Get-Credential Login as live@edu administrator $Session = New-PSSession -ConfigurationName Microsoft.Exchange -ConnectionUri https://ps.outlook.com/powershell/ -Credential $LiveCred -Authentication Basic -AllowRedirection Get into the users administration Import-PSSession $Session And finally New-ManagementRoleAssignment -Name:EWSImpersonation -Role:ApplicationImpersonation -User:impersonation@yourdomain.com It will give permissions to impersonation . c) Messenger y Bing. If we want Bing and Messenger just activate both of them. About searching a couple of things: There are two buttons in the search bar The regular search in Bing. Typing and searching, Powerset Search . I didn't know it before. To use it, select a text and click on the button. The words highlighted will be searched in Bing. Note: The Java script in MS4M.zip is not working properly. I have fixed it  - search.js, here .- Just overwrite the file in http://yourdomain/blocks/live_services/services/search 7. Mesenger within the courses Set a   Sticky block  Just choose from the dropdown menu course page and the block Microsoft Live Services New " home-made " block I have programmed a HTML block to implement in moodle once you can access to it with your LiveID. With it, you can: Create a new document with just one click. ( Word, Excel, PowerPoint or OneNote) Upload a document Access to "Shared documents" Make a document search in Skydrive The first step is create a new HTML block. Let's see the code step-by step:: 1. To create a new document Jus liink the images you want to use (in this case Office icons) to the next URLs For Word: https://skydrive.live.com/?sc=documentsxt=docxref=1action=CreateWord For Excel: https://skydrive.live.com/?sc=documentsxt=xlsxref=1action=CreateExcel For PowerPoint: https://skydrive.live.com/?sc=documentsxt=xlsxref=1action=CreatePowerPoint For OneNote https://skydrive.live.com/?sc=documentsxt=xlsxref=1action=CreateOneNote 2. Upload a document Link the text you like with https://skydrive.live.com/P.mvc#!/choosefolder.aspx 3. Access to shared documents https://skydrive.live.com/?qt=shared 4. Searchj form This one is a bit complicated, but no so :) form class="c_search_mc" id="c_search_SearchBox_f" style="background-image: none;" onsubmit="function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { return $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].doSubmit(); } } } } }" action=" https://home.live.com/search " method="get" target="_top"/form/p p align="center" label for="c_search_SearchBox_box" /label input name="query" title="Buscar documentos y mas" class="c_search_box c_ml TextItalic" id="c_search_SearchBox_box" onfocus="function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].focus(); } } } } }" onblur="function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].blur(); } } } } }" type="text" maxlength="500" autocomplete="Off" / input title="Buscar" class="c_search_go" id="c_search_SearchBox_go" style="background-image: none;" type="submit" value="Buscar" / input name="mkt" type="hidden" value="es-ES" / input name="scope" type="hidden" value="Documents" / input name="consumerid" type="hidden" value="Live.Folders" / Here you have the whole HTML code: table style="width: 200px;" tbody tr td class="style2" colspan="4"Create a new online document with  Microsoft Office web apps...br /br / /td /tr tr td a title="New Word Document" href="https://office.live.com/newdocument.aspx/.Documents?xt=docxref=1" target="_blank" img width="32" height="32" alt="Create new Word document" src="http://URL/word.png" //a /td td a title="New Excel Document" href="https://office.live.com/newdocument.aspx/.Documents?xt=xlsxref=1" target="_blank" img width="32" height="32" alt="Create new Excel document" src="http://URL/excel.png" //a /td td a title="New PowerPoint Document" href="https://office.live.com/newdocument.aspx/.Documents?xt=pptxref=1" target="_blank" img width="32" height="32" alt="Create new PowerPoint document" src="http://URL/powerpoint.png" //a /td td a title="New OneNote Document" href="https://office.live.com/newdocument.aspx/.Documents?xt=oneref=1" target="_blank" img width="32" height="32" alt="Create new OneNote document" src="http://URL/onenote.png" //a /td /tr tr td colspan="4" a title="Upload a file" href="https://skydrive.live.com/choosefolder.aspx" target="_blank"Upload a file/a /td /tr tr td colspan="4"a title="Your shared folder" href="https://skydrive.live.com/#qt=shared" target="_blank"Your shared folder/a /td /tr/tbody /table p form class="c_search_mc" id="c_search_SearchBox_f" style="background-image: none;" onsubmit="function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { function onsubmit(event) { return $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].doSubmit(); } } } }" action="https://home.live.com/search" method="get" target="_top" p align="center" label for="c_search_SearchBox_box" /label input name="query" title="Buscar documentos y mas" class="c_search_box c_ml TextItalic" id="c_search_SearchBox_box" onfocus="function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { function onfocus(event) { $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].focus(); } } } }" onblur="function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { function onblur(event) { $SB.sbs['c_search_SearchBox_box'].blur(); } } } }" type="text" maxlength="500" autocomplete="Off" / input title="Buscar" class="c_search_go" id="c_search_SearchBox_go" style="background-image: none;" type="submit" value="Buscar" / input name="mkt" type="hidden" value="es-ES" / input name="scope" type="hidden" value="Documents" / input name="consumerid" type="hidden" value="Live.Folders" / /p/form /p Well, this is just a new idea, but the thin is that once you have logged in with a LiveID account, the rest is just imagination. I believe this is it. Please comment if you have any problems or suggestions. Thanks. ]] Q: Teenagers today are always punching their cellphones. It is almost an addiction. A: We can not expect from schools and students to forget about their "addiction" and to get back into a life where mobile phones don't exist and they were not part of our daily life. Q: Young people have a very active virtual social life. They spend more time working in their virtual friends than with the real social interaction. A: If they are spending so much time within a social network, is it not an important part of their life? If we expect a global education taking care about every student perspective, we can't forget about their life in the social networks, as we can not forget about sports, arts or social skills. Q: Students today the can't afford frustration. A: I have seen them trying and trying after a "Game Over" screen in a video game. We have thousand different ways of introducing video games in the curriculum, why not? Q: They are passionate about what they like and don't care about the "important" things. A: Give them the opportunity of work about real life problems. Make them see the point of studying capitals of Europe, Physics or Mathematics. Q: I don't have time to learn about all the new software and hardware are coming out everyday. A: Your students do! give them the chance to use the tools they want to get where you want them to go. Q: Working the memory is very important. Don't tell me they don't have to learn the list of the kings. A: Completely agree. Memory is a skill we have to work in the school, but it can not be the only one. If maths teacher is working memory as science teacher, history teacher and language teacher, is not the memory a little bit over-trained? Q: MS Word corrects the misspellings of the students. A: What do you do when you find a word misspelled in a student notebook? Q: Underline it in red and tell the right way of doing it A: Same as Word! Anyway, you won't use only MS Word to write as you won't use the notebook to do so. Q: They don't listen to me! A: Maybe at the beginning they do, but we have been talking for years. There are many different ways of delivering content and many different ways to connect to different people (in your school and in the world) to  give variety to your lessons. Q: They are used to "right here, right now". A: Perfect! Upload your lessons to the cloud, they could access to them whenever and wherever they want. Q: They don't know any of the important things. A: I can't tell what is more important to know, the list of capitals of Europe or how to plan a trip to one of them. I can't tell, seriously. ]] English version | Version en espanol We did it! We love the way of thinking " Learning by doing" and keeping in this direction we have developed Julio Verne 2.0, our first Windows 8 application that you can download here. http://apps.microsoft.com/webpdp/app/2bc67eb5-a015-425c-a3d0-a7c6e0d9c112 In this app you can have a glimpse of our projects in the ICT department sorted by categories. A first step in this world which is going to be followed for many new apps to make our students get the most of this new way of working that Windows 8 offers to education. Here you have some shots. We hope you like it. Lo hicimos! Nos encanta la manera de pensar de "aprender haciendo" y, siguiendo esta direccion hemos desarrollado Julio Verne 2.0 , nuestra primera app para Windows 8 que puedes descargar aqui: http://apps.microsoft.com/webpdp/app/2bc67eb5-a015-425c-a3d0-a7c6e0d9c112 En esta aplicacion puedes echar un vistazo a nuestros proyectos en Nuevas Tecnologias listados por categorias. Un primer paso en este mundo que estara seguido por muchas nuevas aplicaciones para hacer que nuestros alumnos consigan el maximo de esta nueva manera de trabajar que Windows 8 ofrece para educacion. Arriba podeis ver algunas capturas de la aplicacion. Esperemos que os guste. ]] A week ago we've got the letter that confirmed that our live@edu campus was ready to move to Office365. I'm not and IT specialist, I just manage the IT department of my school, so I thought that it will be tough and very complicated. Nothing further from the truth The first thing I had to do was to follow a simple "clicks" path. Do you want to upgrade? Yes! In, no more than 10 minutes, all the process was finished and I found myself managing a professional Exchange, Lync and SharePoint site. The password issue Once you have migrated, Skydrive changes into a regular Live Service not managed anymore for the school, so you need two passwords to separate the services of Office365 and Skydrive. Every user of my school has to go to https://eduupgrade.office365.com and change his/her password. The new password will be used for Office365 More or less, it looks like this Login and services in live@edu Login and services of Office365 and Skydrive A little rock on the road Live@edu only managed and Exchange Service so it is what you find when you first go to Office365. There's no trace of Lync or SharePoint. After some questions in the forums, I realized that the license you got automatically is the A1 plan, which only includes the Exchange Service. What I did was to buy licenses of the A2 plan, which includes Lync and SharePoint. All my licences cost 0 , because the plan A2 is free for education. Then, just had to re-assign licenses to all my users and, voila!, Lync, Exchange and SharePoint free for my school. The world of DNS As I implemented live@edu in my school, I was used to manage DNS in my domain. A couple of new adjustments have to be done to make Lync and SharePoint work. A now... what? Well, the thing is that I'm a teacher, "just" a teacher. I mean, I'm not an IT specialist and I have in front of me such a professional tools as Lync or SharePoint to manage and implement in my school. But, guess what? I wish all my problems were like these ones. ]] Many devices can get into our classrooms nowadays, but depending on what you want get from your students and from the devices themselves you can use one or another. Here I show them in increasingly pedagogical potential Smartphone: Clearly they are not going to be the primary device for powerful learning, but they do allow for some basic level collaboration, communication, gathering of resources, and provide quick access to information. Internet search, dictionaries, twitting or shooting photos and videos are useful resources we can use in our lessons with just a phone. Today, almost everybody, is walking though life with powerful computers in their pockets, and, if your students have already know how to use them, why not take advantage from it? Slates: More powerful than mobiles, but in my point of view, there is not such a difference but the bigger screen. The level of collaboration is minimum and the control can teachers have over them are less than nothing. Almost same apps than mobiles and still reinforcing the isolation of individuals. But I have to say that, for some ages or disabilities are great. Storytelling for kindergarten, for example, or accessibility for certain disabilities are the perfect excuse to introduce these devices in our classrooms, but I can't see them none in primary or secondary school. For digital books are great as well, but they are still too expensive compering the investment to the possibilities they have. Laptops: The perfect device if you compare the price and the possibilities. They allow real multitasking, and serious creation. They allow the pulling of information from multiple sources simultaneously; manipulation of that information in many forms, and the creation of new knowledge and understandings. Tablet-PC What if you have the power of the apps in the slates and the multitasking and serious creation of the laptops in one device? I believe is the solution for education. You can have the individual variety of  the actual apps and the powerful learning possibilities of software. Now we've got an excuse to invest in digital textbooks, because, once you have work with them you can edit a presentation, share it or plug your usb to bring it somewhere else. You can print, get into a domain, control the access of your students, and with the digitized stylus make a real corrections of you lessons work. Until "yesterday" it was a dream. I believe (and I hope so) that Windows8 has many thing to say about this. The problem could be the price... keep your finger crossed. ]] As vice president of education for Microsoft Corp.s Worldwide Public Sector organization, Anthony Salcito works with education institutions and partners globally to embrace technology to optimize learning environments and student achievement. He has got a blog called DailyEdventures where everyday focused in one educator around the world who can help others to move formward in this difficult world of education and innovation. Today (August 14th) was my turn. A brief interview has been published here where you can reed some thought about my point of view in education. This success has been the fruit of working with Microsoft Partners in Learning for the past three years and of trying to innovate in my school everyday. Here you can see the moment when Anthony is giving me Julio Verne's award as a Mentor School in the Partners in Learning Microsoft Program. It is a great honor, sincerely. ]] STEM is the acronym for Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics. And why is so important? In United States realized that there is a shortage of skilled workers in these areas so they had? to look for them beyond their country limits. Deep studies determined that these areas are isolated in the schools curriculum, instead of being integrated in every area. So, is our future heading to a STEM education? This infographic can give us a clue. ]] 