 This was taken as Lily and Bryan were climbing down the ladder into the basement hole of some Mesa Verde ruins. Aren't they cute!? ]] Edits: Adjusted blacks, lights. Saturation on the faces to make not as red. "healed" brady's scratch on his nose. Adjusted contrast of the tree trunk. Adjusted contrast of the boys' lashes. This one was taken awhile back at Meme and Pepe's house. The boys climbed up in a tree...and I snapped. I love Hayden in this shot - like...here I am, here I am!! Too cute! ]] Digging for gold. ]] This picture tells a lot. I love to color. I've always loved to color. I could color for hours as a child. I could color for hours now. The cuties...they love to color. I also LOVED strawberry shortcake. I had a SS doll. She smelled delicious. I LOVE SS. So does Lil. ]] Unedited Adjusted Blacks Adjusted Lights Adjusted the tint Adjusted brightness a bit Adjusted saturation on skin Eliminated a bit of strawberry via the heal tool Softened skin Noise Reduction Made virtual copy of the edited picture above and added Sepia preset Adjusted brightness ]] Bryan. AKA The Hottie. ]] Blacks, Lights, Soften Skin, Pinken lips, Added some contrast to hair, Enhanced the eyes a teensy bit, noise control. Charlie's blues. We love her blues. ]] Last weekend we went to Greer and saw this. Amazing. A-Mazing. ]] This little boy made my job as photographer sooooo darn easy. He was so calm and relaxed. We only heard him make one little whimper at the very end of the shoot. What a true little angel. Isn't he so stinkin' adorable!!?? I only wish I could have snapped some photos with both him and his big sister. Unfortunately, she wasn't feeling so well and was a little camera shy. Definitely next time! Thank you Ashley - it was an absolute joy to take these photos!!! ]] I had the privilege taking some photos of a very old friends newest little one. How fun! I'm still working on them...but, here is one. ]] ]] here I gave a sneak peek into the newborn session with this cute little guy, Brody. Then...I slacked and never posted the rest of the pictures! Man oh man is he a super cutie patootie. He was wide-eyed pretty much the entire session. He is so stinking cute! He is going to be a mover that's for sure. He was just about 2 weeks old and already strong as could be! What a joy! Thanks Jeremy and Tara for sharing your little boy with me for a few hours. ]] Our definite family favorite right now is Carsyn. O. M. G! She is so darn A-Dorable!! Shooting and editing these photos has been so much fun! I'm just about done, but I know my sister has been dying to see some photos of her newest bundle! I'm waiting to finish cleaning up the black and white backgrounds on several photos - so, I'll save those for the next post. And, some of those are my favorites...so stay tuned! But, until then - here are some gorgeous shots of Carsyn! ]] So...I'm by no means a professional...but, I do love photography. I'm taking photos of some family and friends for the holidays - you know, for those coveted photo Christmas cards that we all send out!!?? And, I'd be happy to take YOUR family photos, too. This will help me to 1) practice what I love and 2) build my portfolio. This will help YOU to get family photos with full rights and permission for a very, very LOW price! So - if you're interested - give me a call! ]] I LOVE school pictures. It's so exciting. It brings back the days of when I would plan out my outfits (not always the best choices), my hair, etc. And then...it's like old school film. You have absolutely NO idea what they look like until the pictures come home. Surprise!!! School pictures are now digital. With the digital technology - you can now pay for touch ups and buy the disk straight from the studio. Last year I paid $6 to have a scratch removed from Brady's cheek. Call me vain - I don't care. It was a gross scabby scratch and I didn't want that hanging up on the walls. Well...I got what I paid for. Yes, it was removed. But...I'm guessing the studio had preset colors that they just stamped on over a scratch and didn't really take the time to properly edit the photo. So...we ended up with a cute picture of Brady with a noticeable (but, not too too bad) edit of a scratch on his cheek. It wasn't bad enough to warrant re-takes, so we lived with it. This year was Lily's first official picture day as a Pre-K student. And guess what...she had a cold. Not only that - but, she had this ginormous scratch/scab in the corner of her eye from being hit with a hula hoop at a Labor Day party. Yes...only our Lily gets hit with a hula hoop...but, that's a whole other story from our klutzy girl. Her nose was red - her lips chapped and her eye scabbed. Makes for a reaaaaaaaalllllly nice first picture, right? So, I was filling out the picture day form and I was about to check the box for the edit and I remembered Brady's "standard" skin color edit. I decided I'd try to edit it myself. So - I bought the disk and hoped that I would have the permission to edit the photo and send them to Costco. Whew! I do. We got the pictures yesterday. Boy oh, boy - I forgot how much that scabby scratch was visible. So - I took a few minutes and edited away in my good 'ole trusty Lightroom that I so, so love and...... Voila!! Perfect? No. But, definitely not just the "fair skin, white child" preset that I'm sure was used last year on Brady's scratch. I'm avoiding retakes! Yahoooooooooooooooooo!! p.s. - Buying the disk is soooooooo the way to go. You get the disk for $25 and then you can send them to Costco to print the sizes that you really need for a fraction of the cost. The packages at the school always sell me on too many sizes (for waaaaaaaaay too much money) that I don't even need. This way - I order EXACTLY what I need for literally pennies. LOVE it! ]] Ok. There are no words for how flipping adorable our newest family favorite is!!! I am still in the middle of editing (sorry Ash, I'm a bit slow) but, here is a sneak peek of my newest niece - Carsyn Marie Paige. Just kidding Ashley - don't get mad :) Seriously...she is so darn cute I could stare at this picture all.day.long. Literally. No photography skills necessary - she is just so beautiful! Love her!!! ]] Ok...my sister has been dying for the rest of these. I am sooooo sorry that I took so long! But - seriously...I'm not sure if I'm biased - but, Carsyn just might be the absolute cutest baby EVER. OMG!!! ]] Anyway - this weekend I took some photos for one of my oldest friends and her family. We go waaaaaay back to 4th grade and Scottsdale Miss Softball. We were the Babes. Brennan's Babes. Her dad was our coach and those few years of softball were some of the best times EVER! You might remember this little guy. Well, now he is 4 months old with a 2 year old sister. Aren't they all just darling??!! ]] ]] My cousin Ray and his wife, Angela, recently had their first baby...a girl. She is the 9th grandchild in that part of my family and the very first girl. Sooooo sweet! She is so precious. She is this little bubbly little girl that I can absolutely tell is probably the happiest baby on the planet. What an angel. Her little grin - really a big grin - is so cute and her mommy sure knows how to get her to smile. Well...my Aunt Barbara was in town visiting her very first granddaughter and i got to snap a few photos. First here is one of my Aunt Barbara :) And now...the star of the shoot... ]] Carsyn's photos and now I got to take the photos of the whole family!!! I love them all!! What you don't know is that Ashley and Brett took home Brady and Lily the night before for a sleepover...and they were still able to be up and dressed with all 5 kids looking adorable at 10am. What a perfect day for photos!! ]] ]] Love, The Campbells Bryan | Dawn Brady | Lily | Charlie ]] Holy cow - has it really been this long since I blogged on my photo site? My goodness!!! Well....then I can't think of a better post than this one of Skylie. My cousin (well, really 2nd cousin...but, who's counting) Rainie just had her second little cutie patootie. She had a girl...Skylie Ryann. So cute - right!!?? Her oldest is just a few weeks older than our Charlie. They're BCF's - Best Cousins Forever :) Well - this time, I was super excited to take the newborn pictures of this little adorable cutie pants. OMG!! Is she not the cutest little thing ever!!?? She was literally a perfect little angel. She slept pretty much the entire time. Even when we'd put her in new little poses, she'd just keep sleeping. So perfect. Of course her room is super adorable - too bad I didn't get any shots of that...maybe next time. Hold on peeps - there are some really good ones!! Maybe I'm biased...but, she sure is stinkin' adorable!!! ]] So...we were supposed to do these pictures awhile back - but, OMG!! I'm so glad we waited. She was the absolute perfect age and seriously...can you get any cuter? I totally don't think so! ]] 