 The intestines of travel today are severely backed up by the faltering colon of the Bay Area, Oakland.  Nothing passes through easily due to a massive fire on the BART tracks near West Oakland BART station.  You can push all you like, but you are only going to cause further problems up the line. ]] Utilize Ur Utility boxes! Oaktown knows how its done, son. ]] Gotta love Oakland #oakland ]] My elementary school sweetheart. (Taken with Instagram ) ]] Kelp plays a tree once washed on the beach ]] The beach only speaks in third person. ]] My loves lovely red locks (at Bed) ]] Chateau Routon Mourvedre 2005 Amador County. Deep, impenetrable purple. Smooth, rich. Dark cherry, raspberry, chocolate, anise, and nice minerality. Great with our vegan cheese quesadillas. ]] Rain boots in full use! (at Todos Santos Plaza) ]] Beach snail nom ]] Oakland Art murmur December 2012. Loakal on 2nd St and Clay. (at lOAKal) ]] LAbbe Rous 2009 Cornet et Cie Rouge Collioure AOC: a very nice Cotes du Rhone that I am enjoying on my 30th Birthday dinner including Veal and Winter Black Truffles. It has intense, pleasurable flavor on the front of the palate.  Alcohol well balanced, acidity a little strong.  Vanilla on the nose, cherry blossom, smoky black licorice, cassis, gosh I dont know. It smells great, like victory, like printemps Chocolate covered cherries but not so sweet, a deep rich quality from the oak I think.  Just damn smooth and tasty. A bit acidic, maybe itll open up more, its only been 10 min or so. Im pretty stoked. Salut! ]] Full Moon Sunset ]] In the glass: deep purple garnet Nose: dark rich cassis, blackberry, violets, cool, subtle Palate: red berries, good acidity with balanced alcohol smooth, long lasting back of palate A bit oxidized although not unpalatable, it could be intentional...definitely worth the $9.99 cost at Grocery Outlet ]] Rest stop restroom closed, so we left the only message we could on the board. ]] Smooth Sangiovese from Dry Creek Valley. Rich and pleasing, ripe berry fruit, vanilla, smooth minerals. ]] Mt. Diablo: the crown of morning (at Walnut Creek BART Station) ]] Rome Valley Vineyards sits atop a hill, over 3,000 ft elevation, less than a mile from where I was raised. This amazing country, El Dorado, never ceases to amaze me. The 2011 White Lotus is a delightful blend of Grenache Blanc and Vermentino. Floral and aromatic, sweet and smooth with hints of licorice. Nectarine and vanilla with nice acidity. A light to medium bodied wine can be paired with light fish and chicken dishes, seafood, and soft cheese. ]] I swear hes not dead ]] Nap time. ]] 