 I received a great email from old friend and lifting legend, Mike Burgener, about the ways that Olympic Lifting resembles everyday life (originally written by Stephanie Vincent). I thought these were absolutely fabulous so I wanted to share them! Now go forth and learn, my lifters! 13 Ways Olympic Weightlifting Is Like Life The following is a guest post by Stephanie Vincent. Learn more from Stephanie at: RadicalHateLoss.com The 13 Ways Olympic Weightlifting Is Like Life... 1) There are a ton of experts, who will all tell you their specific methods to do it. However, there are actually few universal truths.  The rest is just about which expert and which method will work best for you. 2) Its complicated.  Youre going to have to triage what parts need to be fixed first before the whole gets better. 3) Improvement starts with the desire to be better, however it only happens through practice and dedication to the cause. 4) You will set personal records when you are completely in the moment, absent of fear, of thought, and of ego. 5) You need the kind of people around you that will teach you, challenge you, support you and generally help make you better at what you do. 6) There is ALWAYS something new to learn. 7) When it feels like we are getting worse, most of the time we are actually getting better. 8)  Fear happens.  The question is, do we let it stop us, or do we courageously move through it and meet our potential? 9) Strength is paramount, but without technique we wont get very far.  Technique is about efficiency, the ability to achieve a desired result without wasted energy or effort. 10) The amount of passion one has is directly correlated to both success and happiness. 11) You will fail a lot.  You will make mistakes.  You will drop the bar.  You will have days where you cant do what you did yesterday.  You will suck....and it will make you better....so, so much better. 12)  You will  be better than someone and there will always be someone better than you.  Accepting your own current level of ability will take you further in getting better than paying attention to anyone elses abilities ever will. 13)  You will have to change directions quickly.  Get good at this, and things will go much smoother ]] I had the pleasure of chatting with Ben Feliciano and Petter Ehrnvall from the hit workout DVD series, Les Mills Pump . We talked about the Body Pump workouts, sports, weight loss tips, and shared way too many laughs. Click below to watch the chat...and check out some abs! http://www.ustream.tv/recorded/30102576 ]] Spring has sprung and it is time to get that beach body back! Most of us have forgotten our New Years Resolutions (remember those way bay when?), but it's not too late to get back to the body you resolved to achieve. While we are about 2 months from bikini season, now is the perfect time to get your butt back in the gym. Whether it's CrossFit, yoga, walking, P90X, or whatever makes you happy -- just get back into it. Anyone who has listened to music knows that it is a saving grace in so many ways. When you're on that last mile, last rep, or last minute, music can give you that extra push to finish. Personally, I am competing in the CrossFit Open and I need some major jams to keep me pushing through those excruciating workouts. To keep your motivation thriving, I've compiled a list of my top 10 songs of the moment that make me want to set PR's and workout for hours on end. 1. Lykke Li -- I Follow Rivers (DJ Punish Dani L. Mebius Bootleg) 2. Knife Party Live at Ultra Music Festival 3. Dada Life - So Young So High (Tiesto Remix) 4. Moska Antoine Becks -- Insane 5. Kaskade at Ultra Music Festival 6. Dimitri Vegas Like Mike -- Wakanda 7. F**kin' Problems (ft. Drake, 2 Chainz Kendrick Lamar) 8. Porter Robinson at Ultra Music Festival 9. Rihanna -- Pour it Up 10. Apster -- Buckleknees ]] Let's be honest, when it comes to physical attraction, women often look for men with a little meat on their bones. Muscles represent resilience, toughness, andagain with the honestysexiness! During college, there was a reason why my roommate would always demand that we "go where the biceps are." Why? Because biceps are hot. And they're an easy muscle to show off. In fact, I'll bet that you've been "showing" your strength by flexing your bicepseven those string bean "biceps" that you so valiantly rocked back in sixth grade. But, biceps aren't just for the boys. Ladies, if you want lean, sculpted arms like Jennifer Aniston, Jessica Biel, or Cameron Diaz, working your biceps is absolutely essential. Slimming down your arms by lifting weights will make you look that much more amazing in your tank tops, little black dresses, and your bikinis on the beach this summer! Oh, and don't be concerned that you'll "bulk up." You will build muscle, but as muscle is denser than fat, you'll look lean and tonednot Hulk-like. For the full article featured in Team Beachbody, please click here to read. ]] Growing up as a track field athlete, there was one woman I looked up to and that was world champion and Olympic medalist Marion Jones. Her poise, her grace, and her pure athleticism in the sprints and jumps were awe-inspiring. In the year 2000, Marion Jones owned Track Field, winning 5 medals at the Sydney Olympics and bringing home glory for her country. Even before Sydney, she was an inspiration. Marion played basketball and ran track field at the University of North Carolina and also played in the WNBA. Marion was elite from the start. She was my idol. I even took my confirmation name after her because she represented strength and feminism, and always had a smile on her face. In 2007, things came tumbling down for Marion. Marion had used performance-enhancing drugs created by Victor Conte and the Bay Area Laboratory Co-operative (BALCO) and lied about it to a grand jury. While the middle-schooler in me was hurt by these allegations and by her subsequent guilt, I was more angry at the people pointing fingers than at Marion.  She was a member of our track field community and that all began to shatter. The BALCO FBI investigation cost us around $200 million and to what end? Do you ever consider how much money the government spends on trying to enhance our athletes chances of winning a medal? While Im not advocating drugs or cheating by any means, Im suggesting a balance in the use of our tax dollars and athletics. Just saying! I thought about all of the good things that Marion brought to the sport. She was a strong female role model that did great things for the United States and for track field in general. Track Field has never been a popular sport in the U.S., but with Marions lively attitude, lightning speed, and glowing smile, Track Field was back on the map. Having trained with some of the best coaches in the world, I understand the politics that have gone into drug testing and I find it despicable. While I am not in favor of performance enhancing drugs, I am also not in favor of the individuals that pick and choose the athletes they make an example of. Weve seen this with Ben Johnson vs. Carl Lewis and many other athletes in sports across the board. If the government is going to go after performance enhancing drugs, then they should test every single elite athlete and not just the medal winner. Just as Marion led her track field community over 10 years ago, she is back in action in the CrossFit community.  After years without competition, Marion decided to join CrossFit Texas, which has been a humbling experience. In an article in the CrossFit Journal, Marion explains, I was hooked for the first time. It was a challenge. I loved the challenge. While Jones-Thompsons (formerly Jones) track field and WNBA days are over, a new chapter in her athletic memoir opens and as a fellow CrossFitter, I couldnt be more excited. But isnt CrossFit a sport of integrity you ask? Yes. CrossFit does not condone performance-enhancing drugs and it has a strict policy against it. With Jones-Thompsons record, it is natural to be a little apprehensive, especially with the growing popularity of CrossFit and its competitions. However, while CrossFit is a sport in itself, its also first and foremost, a community. Maybe this is Marions second chance; not at a gold medal, and not as a CrossFit Games contender, but as a fresh start in sport. A fresh start filled with integrity and pure love of the game. The joy of CrossFit is that no matter what your background is  Mom, weekend warrior, or Olympic Athlete, when that clock beeps, 3,2,1, GO, were all in it together. Welcome Marion, its a pleasure to have you in our community. http://journal.crossfit.com/2013/04/marion-jones-thompson.tpl ]] I came across this great article by physical therapist extraordinaire, Gray Cook entitled "Play, Practice, or Train - Which Comes When?" As an athlete, I completely resonated with his points. Growing up, track field was always playtime for me. Even as a child, I challenged the boys to sprints and jumping contests way before I even started my track field practice. I was playing and I was conditioning my body to perform, subconsciously. I was creating my baseline. Partner carries...a workout for your abs since you won't be able to stop laughing! When I started officially playing sports, it was time for practice; Repeated motions to condition my body and muscle memory to perform once it came time to compete. I was practicing a skill (long jump/sprinting), so I needed to get my 10,000 hours in! In this time, I also found it to be playtime. We had fun with it. I was blessed with wonderful coaches who stressed quality over quantity and always made the practices fun. I came home feeling energized by my workouts. That's one happy Coco! Then something changed once I hit college. The coaching focused merely on training and did not bring any playtime or practice to the game. How is an athlete supposed to keep their love of the sport if it's not fun anymore? It was a quantity over quality game. I was coming home completely exhausted and my performances were declining. Once the playtime was taken away, I became a number on the board and no longer an individual. Because of that, my pure love of the sport died and so did my track field career. Relay races ... teamwork! However, years later I discovered a new sport where I can be a part of the ultimate athletic amalgam: playtime, practice, and training all in one. At CrossFit (South Bay), we work on skill (practice), training (WOD's/metcons), and ultimately we have fun doing these movements. When I go to CrossFit, I get to play with my friends. We get to lift, run, do ring work, and ultimately play with friends...every single day. I am grateful to have found such an amazing sport, box, and community that brings out the inner child in us us all. Because after all, sport is supposed to be fun and fulfilling. ]] Spring is finally here! The birds are chirping, the sun is shining, and clothing appears to be getting . . . smaller. While the warmer weather and the reemergence of the sun make for happier brains, they make it harder for you to hide that muffin top underneath sweaters and jackets. Unfortunately, your stomach is often one of the first places you gain weight and one of the last places you'll lose it. Belly fat is not only bad for the beach; it's downright dangerous. A study published in the American Journal of Hypertension revealed that "A larger waist measurement predicts the development of high blood pressure, regardless of total body fat." Other studies have found that visceral stomach fat (versus the subcutaneous fat that you can pinch) is linked to higher total cholesterol, insulin resistance, colorectal cancer, and diabetes. It's time to get serious about losing the spare tire around your waistnot only for aesthetic reasons, but also for your long-term health. And with just a few more weeks until beach season is here, there's no better time to start shredding that fat so that you can reveal a flat, defined, sexy stomach.... For the full article published in Team Beachbody, please CLICK HERE! ]] Most women are so scared of lifting heavy weights because they are afraid that it will in turn make them bulky. WAKE UP, ladies! Big weights do not make you big. Eating crap and living a sedentary life will make you "bulky." If you lift big weights and eat big meals (too big for your size), yes you will get big. But if you maintain a healthy diet and get in the gym...whether it is in the weight room, yoga room, pilates room, dance studio, on the track, or whatever makes you tick...it will benefit your body and your mind. I came across a spicy, snarky article on Lift Big Eat Big called " 10 reasons why lifting is terrible for women ." Check it out. But in all seriousness, get in the gym, pick up the weights, any weights, and get to work.  I promise that your body and mind will be sculpted into something more resilient, strong, and valuable that will last you forever. ]] Ahhh... vacation, the time for you to kick up your feet, pick up a drink, and take off your top (to tan in your bikini, pervs). But while we're relaxing and imbibing in drink after frozen drink, we tend to forget about our waistlines. The excuse I most often use is a simple, but clear "who cares? I'm on vacation!" which can be translated to, "Yes, I will have that third margarita and don't you judge me." But just past that incredible excuse lays my conscience and that old thing called, the truth. And the truth always knows that the extra 1,000 calories you're taking in a day won't magically disappear just because you're on vacation. For the full article, click below! http://www.huffingtonpost.com/collette-debenedetto/10-ways-to-stay-in-shape-_b_3460375.html ]] Summer is here and that means bikinis, babes, and brews. But while you're partaking in summer BBQ's and beach time, it's hard to find the motivation to stay in the gym. Find your bliss when working out. It could be a walk on the beach, a bike through the mountains, lifting heavy weights, or lifting light weights. Wherever you clear your mind, find your endorphin high, and feel good about you, go there and stay there. I know it's easier said than done so I've compiled my top 10 motivational beats of the moment to keep you focused and pumping in the gym: 1. Krewella: "Alive" (Hardwell Remix) 2. Monsta: "Messiah" (Dirty South Remix) 3. Nikki Williams: "Glowing" (Fedde Le Grand Remix) 4. Calvin Harris: "We'll be Coming Back" (R3hab EDC Vegas Mix) 5. Major Lazer ft. Flux Pavillion: "Jah No Partial" 6. Dimitri Vegas Like Mike ft. Moguai: "Mammoth" 7. Sander Van Doorn: "Into the Light" 8. Dirty South ft. Joe Gil: "Your Heart" (Michael Brun Remix) 9. Lana Del Rey: "Summertime Sadness" (Cedric Gervais Remix) 10. Knife Party: LRAD If you start fist pumping mid-workout, it's ok. You can blame me. ]] By now you have seen them on TV, you've shopped next to them at the grocery store, and you may even be living with one. These people love WOD's, eat Paleo, and workout in a box. These individuals range from soccer moms to students to professional athletes. Who are these people? Well, I'm talking about CrossFitter's. CrossFit is defined as "constantly varied, functional movements at high intensity." It is used by police academies, military special operations units, and elite athletes worldwide. It involves running, rowing, weightlifting, gymnastics, and specializes in not specializing. CrossFit wants to prepare you for anything and everything. That may mean lifting your child, picking up groceries, or running from a barking dog. While high-level officials and athletes use this workout to condition themselves, CrossFit is a sport that anyone can do because every workout has universal scalability to ones level and abilities. That means during one class, the new Mom can be working out next to the top-tier athlete. Load (how much weight) and intensity (reps) are changed, but the programs are not. For the full article, click here . ]] This past weekend I had the pleasure of flying to Denver, CO for one of my dear friends weddings. While there, I decided to take in some scenery before dancing the night away. My fiance and I headed up to the famous Red Rocks Amphitheatre in Morrison, CO. This Amphitheatre is the host to musical artists from around the world. What some outsiders don't know though is that the amphitheatre is also used to workout! So when we saw all of the fit people running up and down the amphitheatre steps, we decided to join them. Add in some running, some box jumps, push-ups, and 6,000+ feet of altitude, and it didn't take much for our lungs to start burning! Check out my fun workout at the Red Rocks Amphitheatre this past weekend: ]] The Santa Monica steps is the place to see and be seen when it comes to working out in Los Angeles. Located on cliffs overlooking the Santa Monica mountains and the Pacific Ocean, the Steps offer beautiful aesthetics in both the vista views and the people that workout there. The Santa Monica Steps have always been one of my favorite places to workout because they are as challenging as you make them, and you can also catch some rays and enjoy beautiful views! Not only that, but it's FREE! Located on 4th and adelaide close to downtown Santa Monica, the Santa Monica Steps are your one stop shop for a booty lifting, heart pumping, sweat inducing, fun workout. CHECK OUT THE VIDEO BELOW: The next time you visit the steps: try this workout: 1. Do a thorough warm-up to get your heart rate pumping with plenty of stretching. 2. There are 2 sets of stairs located about 400m apart from one another. Run down the metal ones, then  take two steps at a time back up. 3. Run over to the wooden steps located east of the metal steps. Run down these steps and then walk or jog up these steps. 4. Repeat! 5. If you want a more difficult workout, try increasing your intensity going up the stairs and decreasing the intensity of your run in between sets of stairs. This will give you more of an intense interval workout. 6. HAVE FUN! ]] A friend sent me an article on the link between successful women and sport. This article, by Gillian Tett, discusses how most high level female executives were also athletes, either in high school or college. Why you ask? Tett says that women involved with athletics are taught that competition and aggressiveness is good (out on the playing field), whereas most women are taught that possessing those trates are not in line with what is socially acceptable. Young girls are taught that demure and "ladylike" is good. Who came up with this bogus way of teaching America's youth? Demure and ladylike might slide with Donna Reed, but it won't fly in the C-Suite. Tett says that "being an athlete is one of the few socially accepted ways for teenage girls to compete, without peer criticism." That is why it is essential that we get our youth involved with sports at a young age. Why is it perfectly acceptable for a man of any age to be competitive, but if a woman is aggressive or competitive anywhere outside of an athletic event, she can be seen as harsh or worse even, as the ever hated b-word? If we condition our youth to see competition as a good thing (friendly, motivational competition), we are setting them up for reality and for success. Female athletes are not only taught to be aggressive, but they are taught how to work in teams with other women and people in general. It is far too often that women in the workplace are targeted by other women because of jealousy or because they just don't know how to communicate with a strong, determined woman. If women could just see that together as a team, you are stronger, the workplace would be a much better and more successful place. No one is going to hand feed you that new project, male or female. No one is going to feed you that promotion, male or female. You, male or female, have to go out and earn it for yourself, speak up and ask for it. According to Forbes , "when you hold your own, show others that you understand your worth, and are sure of your achievements, you'll prosper." That takes drive, aggression, and motivation. If the boys can do it, why can't you? It is pertinent that we get our youth involved with sports so that they can learn what it takes to succeed in sport and in life. You wouldn't stand still while someone dribbled a ball around you in soccer, so why do it in your everyday life? So ladies, I ask you to stand up and speak up for yourselves on and off the field as well as in and out of the boardroom. For the full article by Gillian Tett, click here . ]] CrossFit is quickly becoming one of the most popular sports in the world and next week, The Reebok CrossFit Games come to the newly named Stubhub Center in Southern California to test the world's fittest athletes over a week of rigorous athletic events and decide who will be the champion in 2013. CrossFit was founded by Greg Glassman in 2000 in Santa Cruz, Calif., and has quickly developed into one of the world's fastest growing sports. It is defined as "constantly varied, high-intensity, functional movement." This "sport of fitness" is a combination of weightlifting, running, gymnastics, and overall metabolic conditioning that tests the mind and body. For the full article published in The Huffington Post, please click here . ]] Bikini season is in full swing and it's time to maintain that hard earned body. But with the summer sun and succulent sangria calling your name, it's hard to find time and motivation to workout. Hmmm...sangria vs. cardio? A few musical snacks will save that six-pack of yours and keep you motivated whether you're working out in a gym or in the great outdoors. So plug in these innervating beats, put on that sunscreen, and get ready for some good old fashioned summer sweat! 1. Steve Aoki Chris Lake - "Boneless" 2. Lana Del Rey - "Young Beautiful" (Kaskade Remix) 3. Zedd - "Shotgun" 4. Martin Garrix - "Animals" 5. Avicii feat Aloe Blacc - "Wake Me Up" 6. The Bloody Beetroots - "Chronicles of a Fallen Love" 7. Armin Van Buuren - "D# Fat" 8. Dimitri Vegas Like Mike - "Chattahoochee" 9. Nicky Romero feat Krewella - "Legacy" 10. Sultan Ned Shepard Fedde Le Grand - "No Good" ]] While I specialize in health fitness, what most don't know is I'm also a hopeless romantic...but only with my new HUSBAND! Yup, that's right. I got married! Woohoo! Check out our first dance here: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=62pBBTi1QJs Now to my health fitness writer defense, there are some athletic moves in there so check it out! ]] The Primal Palate Once upon a time there was no French Fry Factory or Donut Dugout. Hard to believe, but our ancestors survived and thrived on food found only in nature. Now, present man is adopting those same eating habits. You may have heard of the hunter-gatherer diet, the caveman diet, the Stone Age diet  these diets are all better known as Paleo eating (short for Paleolithic era, and pronounced pail-e-o). While this way of eating has been around for thousands of years, the official name, The Paleo Diet, was created by Dr. Loren Cordain, the worlds leading expert on Paleolithic diets and Professor in the Department of Health and Exercise Science at Colorado State University. The main differences between the Paleo Diet and modern diet is the Paleo Diet has no grains, no refined sugar, and more good fats than the modern day diet. Paleo experts believe that additions to our contemporary diet such as grains, gluten, and sugar have contributed to modern day diseases such as diabetes, high cholesterol, and obesity to name a few. According to Paleo experts, Hunter et al, the abrupt change from a very physically demanding lifestyle in natural outdoor settings to an inactive indoor lifestyle is at the origin of many of the widespread chronic diseases that are endemic in our modern society. According to Cordain, DNA evidence shows that basic human physiology has changed little in 40,000 years...our dietary needs are the same as theirs. So how do you eat for the way your body was designed? Check out this How-to QA for eating Paleo! Q. What can you eat on the Paleo Diet? A. Paleo eating is based on the idea that you should eat what your body was designed to eat. Thus, vegetables, fruits, animal protein, nuts and seeds, healthy fats, herbs and spices are the primary sources of nutrients. That seems easy, right? Well...its time to take a closer look at your food to see where it comes from. First, when choosing a protein, the quality of the meat is very important, and thus, organic, free-range and grass-fed options would be the ideal protein sources. Your carbohydrates should only come from non-starchy fruit and vegetables. However, if you are expending a lot of calories in your daily workout or run, it is recommended that you eat some starchy vegetables such as sweet potatoes and squash (as seen in The Paleo Diet for Athletes). All fats are not created equal and they should be good fats that come from healthy sources like coconut oil, coconuts, olive oil, olives, nuts, nut butters, and avocado. Q. What are good fats vs. bad fats A. Miller et al describes, there is now strong evidence that the absolute amount of dietary fat is less important in reducing the risk for cardiovascular disease than the type of fat. Try to use monounsaturated fats (olive oil, nuts, avocados), which are known to lower blood cholesterol. Polyunsaturated fats are mixed. There are healthy polyunsaturated fats like Omega 3s (fish oils), but Omega 6 fats (vegetable oils), are not good for you according to Cordain, if you eat too much of them at the expense of Omega 3 fats. Q. But I thought diets with a lot of meat were unhealthy? A. Your average grocery store steak in the USA comes from corn and soy fed animals kept in tightly confined pens while being pumped full of antibiotics to keep them from getting sick. This environment leads to lower quality meat as mammals store toxins in their fat. Thus, increased red meat and processed meat consumption has been linked to a greater risk of cardiovascular disease. However, if an animal is raised in better conditions, the meat is healthier, as red meat derived from grazing animals is generally lean, low in saturated fat, and contains significant amounts of healthy long chain omega-3 fats. Therefore, if we stuck with the grazing nutritional pattern, Miller et al have said it would not have promoted atherosclerosis (hardening of the arteries) or chronic disease. So I know what youre thinking of all this food...BORING! But it doesnt have to be. The key is in retraining your primal palate. Between the proteins, healthy fats, fruits and veggies, its hard to be hungry! Plus, the extra fat in your food not only fills you up, but your taste buds love it too. Q. What should I avoid on The Paleo Diet? A. All grains, including bread, cereal, and pasta. While everyone handles grains differently, most people respond better without large servings of grain. In particular, Cordain notes that during the Paleolithic era, man did not have access to any of the grains that are currently in the modern diet. In addition, youll also want to nix any dairy. No other animal in the world drinks milk beyond infancy. Our bodies were not designed for massive dairy consumption. Most people think you need calcium from dairy, but thats not the case. There is great deal of calcium in many green leafy vegetables and also in nuts and seeds. Furthermore, fruits and vegetables have an ability to slow or prevent the loss of bone density, also known as osteoporosis. A study by Dr. Katherine Tucker at Tufts University found that the people who ate the most fruits and vegetables had the greatest bone mineral densities and the strongest bones. Furthermore, more than 100 studies have confirmed this finding. Something you also need to focus on with your nutrition is the acid-base balance. If you eat a highly acidic diet (cereals, legumes, meat, fish, salty processed foods, eggs, and especially hard cheeses), youll lose calcium in your urine. Dr. Lawrence Appel at Johns Hopkins University reported that diets rich in fruits and vegetables (alkaline foods) significantly reduced urinary calcium loss in 459 men and women (Cordain 19). The biggest no-no in the Paleo Diet is refined SUGAR. If you have to have sugar, the Paleo Diet recommends just a little bit of raw honey or pure maple syrup because this would be very rare to find in nature as Paleo man. Sugar has been shown to be as addictive as cocaine in mice studies. In addition, the sugar definition also covers high fructose corn syrup, as well as natural and artificial sweeteners, as each of these has been shown to cause your body to react poorly. Lastly, try to avoid canola oil, as it is derived from the rapeseed plant, where the oil is highly processed and is usually genetically modified. Canola Oil is not necessarily bad, but it usually goes into the making of processed foods and has a high omega-6 count. I encourage you to experiment with your diet  take certain things out of your diet like dairy or any other food you think you may have a reaction to and see how you respond. Then, slowly put them back in. Dont take out multiple things at a time or you wont know what was causing your bodies response (acne, bloating, etc.). Q. Can you really remove that many foods from your diet? What am I supposed to eat? A. I encourage you to experiment with your diet  take certain things out of your diet like dairy or any other food you think you may have a reaction to and see how you respond. If you slowly and methodically take out different foods over time, you will start to explore which ones in particular are causing your bodys issues (acne, bloating, etc.).Then, slowly put them back in one-by-one and see which ones you can handle. Everyone will respond differently to different foods. Q. What are the benefits of adopting the Paleo Diet? A. So you have to work for your food and you cant eat sugar  well, where is the fun in this diet? The fun is in the RESULTS  both cosmetically and for your health. I. No Counting Calories: One of the greatest parts about the Paleo Diet is that you dont need to count calories. Most people count calories because it is easy to overeat grains and sugars. With the Paleo Diet, youre eating breakfast, lunch, dinner, and snacks and theyre complete with high quality protein, fats, and carbohydrates. On the Paleo Diet, your blood sugar doesnt spike or plummet as it does with the Standard American Diet. Between the proteins, healthy fats, fruits and veggies, its hard to be hungry! Plus, when you are eating the food that youre supposed to eat, your body doesnt crave sugar and overeating. II. Fat loss: One of the greatest benefits of the Paleo Diet is fat loss due to the increase of quality foods in the diet which helps to minimize junk carbohydrate consumption. According to Cordain, wild, lean animal foods dominated Paleolithic diets, so their protein intake was quite high by modern standard, while their carbohydrate consumption was much lower. G.D. Foster, lead author for a New England Journal of Medicine study noted that low-carb diets outpace conventional low-calorie, low-fat, high-carbohydrate diets, at least during the first six months. If youre cutting out sugar, dairy, and grains, your body is bound to reap the benefits. According to Cordain, low-carbohydrate diets tend to normalize insulin metabolism in many people...this normalization prevents swings in blood sugar that, in turn, many cause some people to eat less and lose weight. III. Allergy Removal: The Paleo Diet helps remove harmful allergies from your diet. The Food Allergy and Anaphylaxis Network notes that gluten, casein (dairy), peanuts, and soy are among the eight foods that account for 90 percent of food allergic reactions. Not only are you removing allergies from your diet, but also when your body has an immunological response to food, it creates an inflammatory response. Inflammation plays a key role in a variety of illnesses such as cancer, heart attack, stroke, and leaky-gut syndrome among others. The Paleo Diet tackles many underlying pro-inflammatory modern-day dietary practices. IV. Quality of Food: Another advantage of the Paleo Diet is in the quality of food you are ingesting. By eating organic, free-range, unprocessed foods, you are not ingesting pesticides, preservatives, and artificial ingredients. Q. What is the 80/20 rule? A. Now you dont have to be a saint 100% of the time to see results, just 80% of the time. The 80/20 rule states you will get 99% of the benefits of the Paleo Diet if you adhere to it 80% of the time. Dont tell yourself you can never have your favorite food again because that is only setting yourself up for failure. Go ahead and treat yourself to your favorite item...pizza, ice cream, cookies....just make sure it is 20% or less of your diet. Not 70/30 or 50/50. Stick to 80/20. If you go overboard, you are sure to feel and see the difference. Q. Will I need to change anything else? A. The Paleo Diet stresses 8+ hours of quality sleep at night. Caveman slept much more than us...most likely because Angry Birds wasnt invented yet. Unplug yourself from electronics, turn out the lights, and enjoy the 8+ hours of sleep that will help regulate your workouts, mind, and body. In addition, this has been shown to help normalize hormone levels and decrease body fat. Q. Will there be any side effects in the transition? A. Youll most likely see some side effects take place as you transition to the Paleo Diet. Sugar acts in your body similar to that of a drug so if youre used to eating sugar on a daily basis, youll most likely have withdrawals, cravings, and headaches. Give yourself 2 full weeks on the diet. Keep a food journal and see how you feel on a daily basis. Those feelings will go away and youll find yourself more energized with less hunger pangs once your withdrawal subsides. Q. But buying organic and grass-fed is expensive! A. If youre looking for good cuts of protein, theyll most likely cost more money since corn-fed cattle are cheaper to raise than grass fed cattle. Find the closest farmers market to your home and buy local! Those foods will be healthier and fresher than what you find in the supermarket and you wont be stomping your carbon footprint on the environment from importing food. Also, remember that it is the toxic fats that we are avoiding, so if you need to get a cheaper alternative, buy the leanest cuts of meat you can find. Q. How will going Paleo affect your workouts? A. All for the best because part of the Paleo Diet is prescribed physical activity. O.Keefe et al said that the ancestral natural environment in which our current genome was forged via natural selection called for a large amount of daily energy expenditure on a variety of physical movement. If youre doing any type of exercise, you might notice fatigue in the first week or two, but that should subside. However, since youre not used to eating low carbohydrate, there will be a transition period for your body. If youre doing a high cardio program like Insanity or The Asylum, make sure to add more fruits and vegetables into your Paleo Diet, as seen in Cordains book, The Paleo Diet For Athletes  especially squash and sweet potatoes, which are best metabolized right after your workout. Im not asking you to go out, hunt, gather, or forage, but you can lead the healthy, vibrant life of a hunter-gatherer and reap the waistline shrinking benefits. ]] I came across an article in Business Insider today regarding the "13 Nutrition Lies that Made the World Sick and Fat." Finally, a big news source, confronts reality and speaks the truth about what is REALLY "good food." Business Insider cracks myths about the complete nonsense that has been created in the world of nutrition. The article dives into hot MYTHS such as meat giving you cardiovascular disease, whole wheat is healthy, eggs raise your cholesterol, and saturated fat makes you fat. Let's hope Business Insider doesn't lose any advertising money from the big food companies. Ha! Well played, Business Insider. Well played. Now back to my eggs and bacon breakfast. Click here to read the full article . ]] My good friend, Brett Hoebel , recently wrote an article entitled, "Where There's Pain, There's Gain." As an athlete recently sidelined by a serious knee injury, I really connected with the physical and emotional pain that Brett struggled with through his own recent injuries. Many think that injuries give you a time to rest and relax, and while that may be true, they're also a time to reflect. As an athlete, your body is your fine tuned instrument for expression. I find that while I love working out for the physical benefits, both inner and outer, I truly work out for my emotional fitness. When the clock countdowns from 3, 2, 1, to GO, it is time for me to phase out all of the outside distractions and focus on that time for myself. However, when something out of my control forces my instrument to stop playing, it can be a real struggle. Brett speaks about focusing on the positive things we can control and learning from these injuries to create a brighter and stronger tomorrow for both our mind and body. So even if an injury, an illness, or a rough patch of life gets you down, remember that there is always a lesson to be learned in all of this; It just takes time, perseverance, and faith to see what that may be. For Brett's full article featured on Eleven by Venus , click here . ]] Confucius once said, "Success depends upon previous preparation, and without such preparation there is sure to be failure." Even though that was said thousands of years ago, that rule still applies today. When it comes to eating healthy on the go, it's all about preparation. Sure, you can stick to your healthy eating when you have the time to prepare your own meals, but what happens when you have to leave your Paleo cocoon and enter the real world? All of a sudden, you're picking food based on convenience rather than on nutrients and after a while (read: a few days), it can and will catch up to you. So whether you're traveling for fun or for work, it is important to prepare yourself for success. For the full article featured in The Huffington Post, click here . ]] As the fall chill rolls in, the one place I want to be is in the kitchen making comfort food. But how do we indulge in comfort food while we still watch our waistlines? We get creative in the kitchen! This week, I made some delicious paleo protein dark chocolate chip cookies! You can play around with the recipe depending on how strict paleo you want to go! And the best part? You can have these babies for breakfast, for dessert, or on the go at anytime! Cookies for breakfast? SIGN ME UP! Ingredients: 2 1/4 cups almond flour (can also use coconut flour) 1 tsp baking soda 1 heaping scoop of vanilla protein powder 1/2 tsp salt 1/2 cup of coconut oil OR 3/4 cup of grass-fed butter Optional: 2 tbsp flaxseed 1/4 cup xylitol or stevia 2 eggs 2 tsp vanilla extract 1/4 cup raw honey 1/2-3/4 cup dark chocolate chips Optional: 2 tbsp apple sauce for a moist consistency Instructions: 1. Preheat oven to 350 degrees 2. Mix dry ingredients together in a bowl 3. Mix wet ingredients together in a bowl 4. Mix all ingredients together and add in the chocolate chips 5. Spray 2 cookie sheets 6. Spread the cookies out on the baking sheet. Press them down so they are in a cookie shape. They will not rise like normal cookies. 7. Bake for 8-10 minutes depending on how large you've made the cookies ENJOY!! ]] I am all about female empowerment through any means possible, but especially through strength training. I had a good chuckle over an article I came across by Sarah Hipps entitled "10 Things Not to Say to a Female Lifter." Via Sarah, " If you are a woman with even a half serious level of lifting under your belt, you know that some of the remarks you get because of it can be ridiculous. Half the time you have to laugh, other times you go full defense mode. Whether youre a bit bigger because youre a powerlifter, a bit veiny because youre a Bodybuilder, or a bit masculine because youre a hardcore Crossfitter...youve definitely heard at least one of the following statements." For the full article, click here . ]] As a young girl, it was known that you either like Barbies or you like sports. You're a "girlie girl" or a "tomboy." As we grew up, beauty usually meant falling within the cultural norms of femininity established by magazines, movie stars, and the girls on television. Beauty usually meant thin. Beauty usually meant safe. Well, times are a changing, and so is the way we see beauty. Throughout adolescence and college, I struggled with the vision of beauty. I knew that through sports I felt vibrant, strong and beautiful. That said, magazines, movie stars and television always portrayed a different view of beauty, and that was difficult to understand. As a collegiate track athlete, I wasn't tall and thin. I was short and muscular. How could that be beautiful? FOR THE FULL ARTICLE, CLICK HERE: http://www.livestrong.com/blog/in-crossfit-women-can-be-the-beauty-and-the-beast#ixzz2jjGGuI8U ]] Ladies and gents, I have officially lost my mind...in the best way possible. My friend, Lea, and I have created TwerkOut WerkOut TM, a proprietary strength training system, here to create glutes that salute with the moves that can drop it to the floor. Whens the last time you saw twerking in the gym? You can thank us later, but for now, please let us know if youd like more information or an interview. Our release is copied below for immediate distribution with our campaign video linked again here. We hope to hear from you soon. In the meantime... Click here to enjoy! ]] 