 The 354 MW SEGS CSP installation is the largest solar power plant in the world, located in the Mojave Desert of California. Other large CSP plants include the Solnova Solar Power Station (150 MW) and the Andasol solar power station (150 MW), both in Spain. The over 250 MW Agua Caliente Solar Project in the United States, and the 221 MW Charanka Solar Park in India, are the worlds largest photovoltaic power stations. The life cycle greenhouse gases emission of solar technology is just a fraction of fossils, but still somewhat higher than hydro, wind and nuclear. Solar can't efficiently provide base load power as it only generates electricity when the sun is out, but it's a great complementary to nuclear especially in areas with high electricity use from air conditioning. In this post I would like to focus on the aesthetics of solar power plants which is important as they cover large masses or land. In my opinion solar installations have an inherrent beauty as they transform ocassionally arid desert landscapes into views that remind us blue lakes made up of geometric patterns. The futuristic structures for me express the hope that 21 century, technology driven, modern life can coexist with nature in harmony. Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] Do you want to be free of cancer and heart disease? Do you want to see your great-grandkids graduate, mankind establish colonies on other planets or dinosaurs brought back to life again? Do you want to be able to feel the Earth's magnetic field, dive down into the ocean without scuba gear or run at 50km/h for hours without being too tired? Do you essentially want to become superman? Transhumanists do. Technology is racing ahead with an ever increasing speed and soon our biological evolution will be turbo charged by technological evolution. Watch these videos discussing transhumanism (often abbreviated as h+ ) from various different perspectives to get an introduction to this intellectual and cultural movement. Learn about what h+ promises, what questions it raises and how to prepare for a new age in human history. Link: Transhumanism News on SingularityHub Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] The title of the video below suggests the interview with Richard Dawkins and Lawrence Krauss is about the movie Unbelievers and atheism, but in fact the discussion is mostly about science and what it means to them. Starting at 24:38 the interviewer asks whether they really meant to suggest that science can be spiritual? In their answers they confirm that they do in a non supernatural way and talk about their personal spiritual experiences in the sense Carl Sagan used the word. I too have had such experiences when I first saw Saturn's rings through a telescope and when I visited CERN and realized the engineers managed to create literally the coldest place in the known universe to make superconducting possible. For me the experience doesn't have to be special 'doing something for the first time' event. I frequently have such spiritual experiences in mundane situations too. For example, recently I watched the snow falling and I imagined how each snow crystal takes up a unique shape despite the simple rules of crystallization. Another time I was looking at a crowd of people and I thought about how we're all related as one human family descending from a single tribe. I love science because it indeed makes living life a deeper experience. Knowledge doesn't take away from the wonder at all, quite the opposite. The same applies to culture in general. For instance, when I visit a place and I know about its history the sightseeing becomes a much richer and more enjoyable. If you have had any such experiences, do share. Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] Post has been updated in November, 2013 to reflect corrections suggested in comments and latest developments. Google+ recently took the second place in the race between social networks from Twitter with over half billion registered users (about half of them are active at least once a month). What could be the reason for such fast growth? And will there be a day in the near future when it overtakes Facebook ? In the chart below I compared the number of supported features in each social network and Google+ came up on top with 58 features versus 34 supported by Facebook and only 23 by Twitter. And all this was achieved in just 3 years. Perhaps being the most feature full social network of all is one of the reasons why Google+ is enjoying such fast adoption rate. Other reasons are the aggressive integration of Google+ into Android and all Google services. Probably the novelty factor plays an important role too. Group Feature Google+ Facebook Twitter Profile Customizable Profile ? ? ? Animated Profiles ? X X Mass Friending Groups ? X X One Way Following ? ? ? Text Long Posts ? ? X Rich Formatting in Posts ? X X Commenting Comments ? ? X Images in Comments X ? X Post Rating ? ? ? Comment locking ? X X Rich Formatting in Comments ? X X Notification System ? ? ? Reply in Notification System ? X X Media Embedded Images ? ? ? Embedded Videos ? ? ? High quality images in posts ? X ? Upload full size photos ? X X Auto Awesome Eraser ? X X Auto Awesome Action ? X X Auto Awesome Pano ? X X Auto Awesome HDR ? X X Auto Awesome Motion ? X X Auto Awesome Smile ? X X Auto Awesome Mix ? X X Animated GIFS in Posts ? X X Auto Awesome Movies ? X X Auto Backup from phones ? X X Album Uploading ? ? X Image Filters ? ? ? Text on Images ? X X Large Images/Videos Layout ? X X Tall Images Support ? X X 3D Images Support ? X X Tagging People ? ? X Posts features Easy Re-sharing ? ? ? Reshare Graph ? X X Link Snippets ? ? ? Location Sharing ? ? ? Mood Icons ? ? X Truly Public Posts ? X ? Post Editing ? ? X Special features Integrated PM ? ? ? Chat ? ? X Video Chat ? ? X Group Video Chat ? X X Video Broadcasting ? X X Groups / Communities ? ? X Events ? ? X Games X ? X Polls X ? X Poking X ? X Mobile Support ? ? ? Tablet Support ? ? ? Finding content Own Feed Search ? X ? Tags ? ? ? Popular Tags ? X ? Popular Posts ? X X Advertising Paid Post Promotion X ? ? Advertising Free ? X X Spam Spam Reporting ? ? ? API API for posting X ? ? Login for 3rd Party Sites ? ? ? Comments for 3rd Parties ? ? X Rich Widgets for Websites ? ? ? Total 58 34 23 Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] Check out my suggestion for a new transhumanism movement logo. It is based on the currently used h+ abbreviation and meant to update the currently used logo shown on Wikipedia . The letter H represents humans , and the + sign the post human era and the augmentation of the human body. The letter and the sign are fused together creating a new whole just like the transhumanism movement promises. The plus sign (cross) demonstrates a positive outlook on the future and healing of the human body. The primary cyan (light blue) color represents the future, technology and freedom. The H+ logo is free to download and use: symbol in svg format and all variations and colors in pdf format . If you're interested to learn about H+ watch some interesting videos on the subject. Update: Readers suggested that the logo can also be read as "I+" as "Me Extended" or "It" as "Information technology". Both meanings apply to transhumanism. Renat Yakubov on G+: Good one, as for me. It's nice, that this logo looks like I+ and H+ simultaneously, reflecting our personal and global goals. Allen Hildebrandt on G+: I actually like it.... "I plus, H+" and a combination of the H and Plus...? . Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] There are certain parallels between the promise of old religions and transhumanism (h+) particularly in respect of the concept of heaven. Transhumanism much like religions promises: eternal life through brain uploading, virtual reality or avatars; nearly infinite wisdom with huge processing power and immediate access to all knowledge through brain upgrades; freedom from human suffering like aging and sickness through advances in medical technology that will allows us not only fix broken tissue but actively prevent any damage too; and being able to continue interact with a loved one after physical death by transferring the person's last brain state into a virtual body. One major difference between religions and transhumanism is that religions are designed to regulate the behaviour of individuals through a moral code for the benefit of the group, thus there are various tests one must pass in this life in order to qualify for the next. In h+ there are no such requirements. The other more important difference is that while we don't have any reasonable physical evidence for the existence of heaven the way most religions understand it (buddhism is an exception because nirvana is not a supernatural phenomena, but a state of awareness one can achieve here on earth), we do have a pretty good understanding of how transhumanism will achieve the state of technological advancement where various heaven becomes possible and feasible for most people. According to Ray Kurzweil, one of the main proponents of transhumanism and the related singularity theory, we will have the ability to upload our brains realistically latest by 2030. The change of humans to transhumans will not be a sudden event in the future. It is already happening to an extent and will continue to be a gradual and almost unnoticeable transformation. I'm not suggesting h+ is a religion as it doesn't have any of the major characteristics of a religion, but I do feel it's fair to say that there are important common motivators between them. Perhaps this explains why the h+ movement is catching on so fast in the world. If you want to learn more on the subject read my earlier blog post titled introduction to transhumanism which contains several videos on the subject. Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] Contemporary culture has an idealized picture of the American Dream where a company can be started from nothing by anyone in a garage. According to the the stories Amazon, Apple, Disney, Google, Harley Davidson, HP, Mattel, Microsoft, Dell and Nike among many other giants all started by previously unknown genius founders from incredibly humble beginnings of simple garage operations and became multi-national, billion dollar corporations. I would like to argue that the idea of starting these businesses from zero is largely misrepresented. The garage by itself is significantly more than meets the eye. Space The obvious function of a garage is to protect whatever is inside from the environment. But the existence of the garage suggests that there is enough wealth available to support a fairly large non-essential space to experiment with ideas and even do small scale production. A garage also comes with a house that includes amenities that support the business. A typical garage we're talking about in itself is larger than what most families on Earth live in as their primary space. Having a garage is a huge luxury if we look at it from a global perspective. Safety We should not forget that the value of the garage also comes from the safe neighbourhood which allows business founders to work on their project without the danger of their inventions and small profits taken away by criminals or competitors. A neighbourhood where private property and inventions are respected is a huge invisible value and unfortuantely is not present in many parts of the World. Laws In an ever wider scope the garage business can only survive if the laws of the country support such initiatives in general. If you're not allowed to tinker and sell your stuff without going through complicated bureaucratic systems to set-up expensive companies and pay all kinds of hidden taxes you can say good-bye to any start-up. Strart-up experimentation requires freedom of business. Time A garage business requires the founders to have enough free time to develop their idea. Most adults especially in families with small children work at least 12 hours a day, sometimes in several jobs, to earn a living. They have no or very little spare time to learn or create anything new. Knowledge We must also note that most garage start-up founders have access to high quality education and/or acquiring important skills at a premier company of some kind. They typically also have access to people in key positions or with specialized skills to work with. Money When you are building a garage venture you must have enough savings to support not only your business expenses no matter how small they are, but also your own living expenses between the time you start working full time at your business and the time the operation starts making enough revenue to provide you with profits you can live off. This typically takes at least 1-3 years, but can last up to a decade. Motivation Most importantly the right motivation is key. The founders must belong to the middle-class to begin with so they can have an incentive to become successful, celebrated and wealthy from their business. If you take all this into account, the idea of staring a business in a garage becomes less readily available than one would first think. It's basically open for people who can afford a house in a fairly rich neighbourhood, have good education and work experience, have freely available funds and have much free time on their hands. Such conditions exist for a significant number of people in the developed world, but it's almost non-existent in poor nations. No wonder that most garage operations are from North America and to a smaller extent from Europe. Startups are the most important economic engine in any country. They re-invent business and create new efficiencies in the economic system that everyone benefits from directly in form of jobs and contracts or indirectly by using cheaper and more valuable products and services. Start-ups are in many ways more important than the multi-nationals they eventually become. If there is one thing governments should focus on is creating the conditions described above to allow garage businesses disrupt stale economies and create more wellbeing for everyone. If you're one of those motivated founders who strive to create the next Apple or Mattel you should focus on creating the above mentioned conditions in your life as much as possible. Move to the right location, take up the right job, find a nanny, etc. Half of success is creating the right environment where your talents can bloom. Good luck! Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] I find the 'Buy American!' (or replace American with any other country) campaigns irrational and counter productive for several reasons. Buying stuff from local people made sense a hundred of more years ago when helping out the neighbour with some business made him richer and this resulted in higher chances of him making a purchase of your products later on. This may still make some sense in developing regions of the world that are cut off from our global civilization. But Today in our deeply interconnected and internationalized World buying stuff that was made in the country you hold a passport from makes little sense. Here are my three reasons why. We live in a knowledge society A person living far away from you may affect your life much more than your next door neighbour. For example, let's say you're an American. The kid in China whose father works in a factory that produces your purchased goods may one day work on a cancer drug that could literally save your life. Another kid few streets down from your house one day may bust your car even though you helped him by buying stuff from his dad's grocery store. Information respects no borders and new information is helpful to us no matter where it was generated. Everything is connected Company ownerships are extremely complicated and interconnected. It's entirely possible that a company that sells products that read MADE IN CANADA are owned by middle eastern investors. And the oil you supposedly buy from Saudi is actually produced by American companies. Most companies and brands in the world are owned by a multitude of nationalities directly or indirectly. Even companies that are owned by a single individual get raw materials, various services and knowledge from other companies that are probably not owned fully by people of the same nationality. Every single corporation is incredibly international in the modern world. The 'MADE IN ...' is a meaningless marketing tool. The correct sticker that would apply to all products would be 'MADE ON EARTH'. Just for the sake of the argument let's assume you will manage to make a purchase that only benefits a local merchant who only used local materials, services and knowledge. He may still go on vacation to another country or his son may buy a foreign vehicle. The money would still flow to other nations. Even if the above argument do not apply to your purchase because it is a unique case, I still have one more argument against buying your country's products exclusively that will surely be relevant every time. Trade is a tool for peace and wellbeing There is no better tool to create peace between different cultures than trade. When people become more interdependent on each other because of trade there is a much higher chance they will not attack each other as it is in their best interest to keep the trade going making both parties better off. If for nothing else buy products from other countries to strengthen this interdependence. Even if a given country is not a threat, consider the benefits of stabilizing and enriching a developing country by giving their people business. Less poverty means less overpopulation and less pollution. Making poorer places richer has strong positive feedback to everybody in the developed world. Also, the richer the people abroad the less likely your job will be exported as I argued in a previous post on the subject. Any time in history a country tried to become self sufficient it lost the efficiencies of trade and division of labor. In result it became less wealthy than other trading nations. Whenever free trading was re-introduced it always produced greater well-being for all involved. The richest city states in the world all traded as freely as possible with all other nations without trying to buy their own stuff. The only exception I can think of where buying local makes sense is fruits and vegetables for environmental and health reasons. Less shipping and shorter travel time generally results in a smaller carbon footprint and higher levels of micronutrients. But even in this field consider that eating a variety of foods is important for optimal health. Also, consider that local inefficient small scale farming may have higher environmental impact than more efficient farming farther away even with transportation included. We also know from a recent research that freshly picked and quickly frozen foods are often nutritionally better than supposedly fresh foods that we find in supermarkets. Locality is not the only variable in the formula that determines what's the most ethical, healthy or economically beneficial for us to buy. All humans came from a single tribe in Africa and spread out all around the world in the last few hundred thousand years. We're all one family of brothers and sisters. I think we should embrace the idea that we're all citizens of the World rather than citizens of a single country. Let's start to slowly kick the tribal thinking that benefited us for a long time because it became obsolete and counter productive in the modern World. Let's leave nationalism out of our buying decisions. Image: Liberty Foundation. See the full campaign Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Google+ ]] Currently Facebook is undeniably the leader in traffic generation, but this may not last forever. On older sites with well established Facebook and Twitter following, Google+ has little chance of taking over simply because the blue social networks have been around longer. However, on new sites Google+ does have a chance. On two fairly new sites I'm running, I was surprised to learn that Google+ referral traffic took over Twitter ( Thorium Forum and 3D prints of the World ) and on one of them G+ is already on the heels of Facebook. I don't have a comprehensive study on Google+'s effectiveness for new sites compared to the other two giants, but I heard similar good experiences with Google+ from other webmasters. The reason why Google+ is catching up with Twitter can be easily explained. According to stats from September Google+ has approximately the same 500M+ active users as Twitter. But Facebook is still at least over 2-3 times bigger than Google+ by any measure. On big sites Facebook generates over 20-50x more traffic than Google+. So how come Google+ can still be competitive with Facebook on new sites? I think I know the answer. Let me explain a simple strategy you can follow to make the most of Google+. There is an effective and honest way to grow your Google+ readership and referral traffic: join and use Google+ Communities . Communities on Google+ are designed to work a bit like old-school forums where people with specific interests come together to discuss world news and their personal experiences. Do not simply post your content on your feed for people who circled you. Search for Communities that match the topic of your posts and post into them. The posts will be visible to people who circled you and to the members of the community. Some of these Communities have tens or even hundreds of thousands of members. When you post in these Communities you directly reach people who signed up for the kind of content you're offering. Your posts will bring real value to the followers of these communities. It is also a great way to generate traffic to your website and gain new followers. For new sites this can be invaluable. You can't achieve the same effectiveness on Facebook or Twitter because they are primarily designed for communication with your friends, not interest groups. There are groups on Facebook but they are somewhat hard to find and generally smaller than on Google+. You can also use hashtags and they work on Twitter, but virtually nobody browses content through tags on Facebook. You can buy yourself followers on both Facebook and Twitter for a new website, which is not possible on Google+ at the moment. Maybe this is the reason why Facebook and Twitter is not interested to create communities similar to what Google+ has. They want you to buy the first few hundred followers instead of growing them organically through communities. Google on the other hand is not interested in making money this way. Google makes money on gathering information on users so they can target ads better. Does it make sense to invest time in growing your Google+ followers? The answer is clearly yes . Besides the already mentioned traffic generation there are two more reasons why using Google+ is a good way to spend your valuable time. Search traffic is usually the biggest single source of traffic on sites. Google+ activity around your website without a doubt helps with Google Search rankings. Finally, the G+ network is growing more aggressively in both number of users and features than any other social network Today. You can see Google+ being the most capable in this comparison of supported features post , which will eventually lead to bigger number of users too. It is likely that Google+ will be the second biggest social network within two years for most sites and will challenge Facebook within five. Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] China enjoyed unprecedented success attracting manufacturing business from all around the world in the last 20 years. Most products in any supermarket feature the iconic and sometimes ridiculed Made in China signature. Some associate it with bad quality, others with the tragedy of offshore manufacturing that is killing jobs in North America and everywhere else in the world. To be fair this is what happens in free markets. Cheap labour and the efficiencies of mass scale production generated an environment where products can be made at a lower cost. People all around the world enjoyed and directly benefited from this process by being able to buy the same or similar products at a lower cost. But this trend will not last forever. The only constant is change. China will have to prepare for a massive shift of manufacturing away from them. I argue that within 5 years the growth in manufacturing in China will top out. There are at least 4 main reasons for this. 1. Growing wages The average wage in China has been growing at an amazing average of 14% per year for the last 10 years. It's expected to grow further for the next 5 years. The standard of life have risen fast from abject poverty to close to international standard wages of over $1,000 per month. Soon the average worker in China will be paid roughly as much as an equally well trained person anywhere else in the Western world. If adjusted for living expenses in some areas this already happened. China is also slowly implementing laws that protect workers in various ways, reducing the risk of human tragedies but increasing the cost of human labor for manufacturers. As wages rise Chinese workers become less attractive to business. 2. Robotization There is a growing trend of using more and more reprogrammable robots in manufacturing that can do many different tasks with high precision. See the video about the Tesla factory in California below. Currently the price of such robots is still prohibitively expensive compared to humans, but it's dropping fast. Within a few years it will be cheaper to buy a robot to do a fairly complex task than employing a person for the same job. As robots replace people in factories there will be less reason to have manufacturing done in China. 3. 3D Printing Additive manufacturing is reaching a stage where it can start to take over traditional manufacturing methods. Today every auto manufacturer uses 3D printing and the technology is now moving into aerospace. Watch CNN's presentation on how 3D printing is changing the world and 3D Prints of the World for the amazing number of uses the technology already has. With 3D printing you can create complexities and efficiencies in material use that were impossible with traditional production methods so far. Printing objects on location cuts out the cost of transportation, packaging and retail operations. Most importantly, a custom 3D printed product made for your specific needs will bring you more value. These three factors of 3D printing together will further diminish the traditional efficiencies of giant Chinese factories. 4. Nationalism There is a growing trend among Westerners demanding locally produced goods. The reasons behind such movements are disputable. If you take everything into consideration many times off-shore production is better for the environment and people in general. But nationalism doesn't have to be rational. Tribalism is an ancient and strong instinct inside us that benefited us for hundreds of thousands of years. For marketing purposes it's enough if we feel better about using and buying our own products and services. Companies are catching up with the demand. Food and car manufacturers were the first to use nationalism to sell their products. Lately even technology companies like Apple and Google are marketing their products as Made in USA to generate more goodwill and sales. See the Apple brand video titled 'Our Signature' below. This trend is going to continue for some time and puts and extra pressure on Chinese manufacturing. Conclusion The recent quick growth of China and other Asian nations is a good thing in every way. It levelled the playing field globally. It brought well-being to Asia and it created new previously non-existent markets for Western brands. Some of the manufacturing will come back to the West and it will be dominated by 3D printing and robotics. Technological change will force China to face slowing growth in manufacturing. But Chinese people work hard and smart. They will figure out how to generate value outside of mass scale production. They will start competing in knowledge industries. The Chinese economy will grow no matter what happens in manufacturing. China will become the most dominant player in the world economy within just years. Watch the TED by Eric X. Li talk below. China will exert more cultural influence than ever on the West because it will not be about cheap products anymore. It's a good time to learn the Chinese language and Chinese philosophies (especially Confucianism and Daoism) as the understanding of China will give you an edge no matter what you do. Comment this post on: Facebook Twitter Pinterest Google+ ]] 