 Heres a listing of todays best Amazon FREE Kindle downloads.   Prices change often on Amazon so check to make sure this is still FREE before downloading.  The Beth Moore books are still available for download! To Live Is Christ [...]]] Hey everyone  Swag Code Alert! Heres the new Swag Code available on Swagbucks.com: Code: Search Amount: 5 SB Time: Tues, Jan 7th, 1pm - 2:30pm Pacific Time (4pm  5:30pm Eastern / 9pm  10:30pm GMT) Available in: ALL SB COUNTRIES=) Make sure to go to Swagbucks.com to get [...]]] Hey everyone  Swag Code Alert! Heres the new Swag Code available on Swagbucks.com: Code 1: 8Differences Amount: 8 SB! Time: Wed, Jan 8th, 1pm - 1:58pm Pacific Time (4pm  4:58pm Eastern / 9pm  9:58pm GMT) Available in: ALL SB COUNTRIES Make sure to go to Swagbucks.com to [...]]] Dollar Tree Weekly Deals Dollar Tree Coupon Policy Dollar Tree Ad Check your ad for sale dates.  Ive included the highlights, see the Dollar Tree Weekly Ad page for the complete list of weekly deals! Click here to see the [...]]] Kmart Weekly Deals Coupon Match-ups 1/5  1/11/2014 Have you signed up for Kmarts loyalty program? Earn rewards on all your purchases at Kmart, Sears, and Lands End. Below Ive listed the best deals for the week. Visit the [...]]] Heres several new printable coupons worth printing. Print these while you can! $1.00 off 1 LOreal Paris Adv. Hairstyling Product  $2.00 off Tickety Toc Bubble Dvd  $1.00 off one (1) meat-free Gardein frozen entree  $1.00 off ONE Luvs Diapers  $3.00 [...]]] Heres several new printable coupons worth printing. Print these while you can! $1.00 off any one APPLEGATE Item $0.75 off any ONE (1) GoGo squeeZ product $1.00 off Energizer Brand Batteries or Flashlight $1.00 off any GARNIER FRUCTIS hair product [...]]] Publix Weekly Ad Coupon Match-ups 1/8  1/14/2014 Ive listed the highlights of the Publix Weekly Ad, view the entire Publix Coupon Matchup and Ad here. Click here to see the complete list B1G1 Sale Priced Based On Purchasing [...]]] Safeway Weekly Ad Coupon Matchups 1/8  1/14/2014 Ive listed the best deals of this weeks Safeway deals! Find a complete Safeway Coupon Matchup and ad list here. Produce . Apples, Organic, per lb  $1.99 Includes: Gala Canned [...]]] Heres a listing of todays best Amazon FREE Kindle downloads.   Prices change often on Amazon so check to make sure this is still FREE before downloading.  Quest for the Pirates Treasure by Gary Gaston  Childrens Ice Cream Airlines [...]]] 