 I often tell people I had Cancer Lite. Gun to your head and forced to contract any form of cancer out there, youd probably go with something similar to what I had. Its not that I make light of my experience, as certain aspects of it were hell, but all things considered it was a [...] The post My Life was Worth $75,121.33 appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . Related Stories Chemotherapy And You! We need a federal agent at every... ]] Aaaaaand thats a burn. Updated 3 minutes ago The NRA says we need armed guards at every school in America in order to prevent mass shootings. Well, if thats the case, then... We need a federal agent in every rural church. foxnews.com/us/2012/12/21/4... davidfrum@davidfrum Fri, Dec 21 2012 17:27:35 ReplyRetweetFavorite We need a federal agent in [...] The post We need a federal agent at every... appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . Related Stories My Life was Worth $75,121.33 ]] This is what I do while Im supposed to be working. It syncs so well too! The post Yakety Astros appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . ]] Trying to remember the last time I was this excited for a non-sequel movie. No pressure. The post Cloud Atlas appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . Related Stories The Love Competition ]] Heres a surprisingly compelling mini-documentary. Seven strangers each have five minutes in an fMRI machine to alove someone as hard as they can.a The winner is the one who can generate the greatest level of activity in the regions of the brain associated with love. [via Radiolab] The post The Love Competition appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . Related Stories Cloud Atlas ]] Despite my affection for quotes, there are some that annoy the hell out of me. Only boring people get bored. Really? Is that so? Then Im one hell of a boring guy. Whenever I find myself bored and allow that quote to sneak into my head, I almost get angry. Partly at whoever first said [...] The post Let Me Sing You The Song Of My People appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . Related Stories Ive Been Inked For Years ]] Originally drafted on July 16, 2011. This is part of a new series where I clean out my Drafts folder. Smile. Big and often. Its your best defense around the swirl of death and depression. Remind yourself that youre young, relatively fit, and survived dozens of idiotic activities as a kid that should have killed [...] The post Chemotherapy And You! appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . Related Stories My Life was Worth $75,121.33 ]] Originally drafted on April 16, 2011. This is part of a new series where I clean out my Drafts folder. Theres an old proverb that says the faintest ink is more powerful than the strongest memory. At least I think thats how it goes. I should probably write it down. I was constantly terrified of [...] The post Ive Been Inked For Years appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . Related Stories Let Me Sing You The Song Of My People ]] I have a giant world map hanging above my bed. You remember it, right? Its littered with primarily red stickers, all signifying places Id like to visit one day. Lisbon, Dar es Salaam, Mongolia. Every so often theres a red sticker with a black sharpie mark in the middle to represent somewhere Id once wanted [...] The post The Happiest Place On Earth appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . ]] While back in my hometown last month, I encountered what might have been the coolest car Id ever seen. It was similar to the one pictured above except it was dedicated to the far superior Skittles. I scrambled for my phone, but the light quickly changed and it drove away as I stared wide eyed, [...] The post So This Is A Thing appeared first on Goob Is Goofy . ]] 