 Photo Credit: Luca Rossato via Compfight The world doesnt need more conformists. If you dont fit in, celebrate that, and then get ready to stand your ground. -  Laird Hamilton   For decades weve standardized, commoditized, and sanitized everything.  Schools measure people the exact same way: grades and test scores.   Despite having proven [...]]] Photo Credit: Tc Morgan via Compfight  I call my latest book a career suicide. In some ways it was the complete death of the person I was before this and the full embodiment of my inner misfit.  You have to eventually let go of who you once were in order to become the person [...]]] A few days ago I picked up a book about teaching yourself how to draw.  My dad looked at my initial drawings and said this looks like a kindergartner drew it. And as you can see from my sketches they mostly did: My curiosity about learning actual skills was piqued. How often in adult life [...]]] Photo Credit: CIA DE FOTO via Compfight Living is getting out there where things arent that comfortable  Erik Wahl Is your day dictated by to-do lists, checkboxes and driving yourself the to a point of such exhaustion and anxiety that youre just counting the hours so you can go to sleep, and repeat this [...]]] Photo Credit: Thomas Leuthard via Compfight   Youve scoured the job boards, spoke with friends and family, yet still you arent any closer to finding the meaningful work you desire. You dream of rolling out of bed and feeling pulled towards the work youre doing. Starting the day with passion instead of having to hook [...]]] At this point Ive been drawing for roughly 18 days.  Im no Picasso, I probably wont sell my art, but I will definitely continue to draw. Playing with different forms of self expression helps to build your creative muscle. Teaching myself how to draw has caused lots of sparks and ideas for new [...]]] Photo Credit: laffy4k via Compfight   Lifes blows cannot break a person whose spirit is warmed by the fire of enthusiasm.  Norman Vincent Peale When I was very young, I spent hours curled up with a book, either reading one or writing one. I also spent many afternoons playing outside with my brothers, enjoying [...]]] 1. Its easier to criticize than it is to create 2. Dont judge your work while youre creating it 3. Unnecessary creation is a good thing  4. Be willing to suck 5. Learn really see, not just look 6. Gradual improvement is all that matters 7. Embrace your imperfections 8. Practice every single day [...]]] Photo Credit: Elisabeth DOrcy via Compfight  Our natural tendency when  were creating is to judge.   We edit, backspace, doubt, and continually question whether what were making is any good. We take ourselves out of  FLOW, which is where our best work surfaces. As Ive spent a little more than 22 days learning how to [...]]] About a week ago I decided to reinvent my mission at the Skool of Life.  I wanted to see if I could learn a new skill every 30 days.  So I decided that I would teach myself how to draw.  Needless to say my first few sketches were nothing to write home about. But [...]]] 