 What's there to feel If its last time everything is real My hands are all numb and limbs are still Aching heading shouting the same words I wanna breathe some air of relief am suffocating inside chased by the midst. I wanna cry I howl in silence, I wanna feel something, anything and everything that's real for this is the last time, before I die. I got to sob a little bit feel the tears running through my cheeks the warmth of being alive its the last day I have got to live. Laying like this, Am hallucinating the past lived moments those fragments didn't last I can't go back and say "Am sorry, for everything and for the last time!" Every bit of me was lost in denial But now am calling for little peace and salvation I'll never found But soul is searching a song to remember but I keep ending up saying this the same repeated lines, I wanna breathe some air of relief am suffocating inside chased by the midst. I wanna cry I howl in silence, I wanna feel something, anything and everything that's real for this is the last time, before I die. I got to sob a little bit feel the tears running through my cheeks the warmth of being alive its the last day I have got to live. Looking ahead is no option turning back is no solution stuck in this mourning moment Actuality haunts my conscience. Am having a fight sense of judging wrong or rights, while leaving this world bound by sins I have lost the my conscience. Having no faith I lived but today I hope and still believe in given a chance a want to live again saying same lines over and over again I wanna breathe some air of relief am suffocating inside chased by the midst. I wanna cry I howl in silence, I wanna feel something, anything and everything that's real for this is the last time, before I die. I got to sob a little bit feel the tears running through my cheeks the warmth of being alive its the last day I have got to live. I wanna Live the Last moment until tomorrow  comes to say goodbye.]] Thou shall not fear Thou will burn in fire Hold faith in yourself And in none other. Give up? no! no! Given up no faith, no hope. Will survive Will fight Will Strike back 'Coz the souls can't die. Thou shall strive Its faith Its in mind thee made for war To conquer the world. Stepping in his boot Alexander will enlighten the path He will show the way Making the ages count. You are made for some thing more, Don't sob over lost souls. Thou shall not fear Thou will burn in fire Hold faith in yourself And in none other. Thou shall face what comes Thou shall not rest Until war is won This sermon we live by singing this war field song. ]] I remember from the scars How I Passed through The wounds of past I go through the same old path Lost somewhere never to come back. My scars of haunting reality My scars of despise and tragedy The scars to remind me Another forgotten story. All I want is to forget The haunting memories Of dreadful truth A reality I aint accept But they show me My mirror image. Walking souls Buried with dead conscience My conscience is shouting The wrong and right decisions I fight with em Losing my consciousness. My scars of haunting reality My scars of despise and tragedy The scars to remind me Another forgotten story. My open heart Burnt with tragic bruises With fraudulent turns I have lost hope. Scars wont let me be forgetting my past. My scars of haunting reality My scars of despise and tragedy The scars to remind me Another forgotten story. Whats happening to me, Where I am Stuck in this moment Caged in denial. I cant move To move ahead to move on Where is that only thing Which can be my freedom. Then I see those four little scars Out of no reason it made me laugh When I realized I have that smile I couldnt stop wondering How wrong been right. The moment of that playful fight The joy and happiness And many hardships I survived Every scar tells a story Happiness or sadness It has its melody. Story continues and so many scars But every story ends With the same tag line I have lived I have survived. My Scars are worth it Coz they define My being and Who I am. ]] Let the sky fall down the rain pour from broken cloud let the air suffocate my breathing for human soul has died. Look around and witness the misery crying pain my fellows' tragedy I can only mourn I don't have a word for human killing humanity Paused at one place break the ancient bond the connection is lost and so the compassion of hurt. Lost under the unknown cruelity lost in haunting greed find all that he needs the humane in human is lost So let the sky fall down let some innocent life be gone cleaning the slate with bloody hands let angels fly over this land. Let the peace mantle this earth preserve the green with its blue let flowers bloom again and new species rule again. The gone be gone the souls been lost let we be dug up, by another generation. let we be cursed for the guilt of some other let we be rest in peace for something better. Let the sky fall down the rain pour from broken cloud let the air suffocate my breathing for human soul has died.]] Darkness of a craving soul haunted by a sealed demon seen no light no long can fight free way is distant sight Angel oh! Angel Angel from the God Angel with no wings to fly Angel shine like gold Angel bring that brightness of light Broken heart trapped in the long chain caged in demolished passion break through breaking dawn broken heart screaming wild Angel flying away Angel with no wings float up there Angel I call for you shine that light only once, once, once for God sake. Possessed in this demonic clutch suffocated in the haunted castle finding ways looking for salvation lost in deception deceived by distortion. Angel oh! Angel don't fly away come for my freedom there should be a way am God's child ain't He is dismay. Angel oh! Angel come find my way Angel oh! Angel I should have a way a chance to survive a chance for my story to reach heighten glory Angel oh! Angel find my way. Angel oh! Angel one day I will find a way.]] My words are scattered and so are my thoughts. Drawing meaning outta something unknown. Looking ahead with rotten soul, Gotten faceless Directionless, hunting remorse. Only a voice So evil, so dark Capturing my mind, Capturing my heart, Fiend, Fiend Together they cry. No escape From the caged beast, Fighting to hunt, Resting to breathe. Crying, weeping My sobbing soul Dried eyes, staring strong. Anguish bursting On right and wrong Running to hide, Running to survive, Running to save own self. Running from merciless broken heart bleeding crimson sorrow dropping tears of lost cause. Love, lover, loss Last no long, Wandering in Lonely lanes I have only this song. With dried eyes Am staring strong, No way ahead To move on. No way ahead Nowhere to move on. Why I sing, Why I weep, Why my pain So aching too much. Trustless life, betrayed my heart Lost a soul, lost a part Lost my innocence, lost my trust. Walking along But not moving on Stuck in the cage Denial I own. Cant say no more I have everything in control Once been pride and glory Is shattered with cripple aplomb. How I speak of hope When hope is lost. Everything I believed in a blink it's gone. Murdered by my own hand My existence and where I belonged. Struggling for ways of survival Lost my image, Lost my reflection. My action be reasonized, My expression be justified, Can I go back? Can I play the same part? Wrong be right And everything is alright Preserve my soul Before diminished in foul. Mirror, Mirror My judge, my beholder, Show me who I am? Show me my deeper soul! Dried eyes Am staring strong, Evil or innocence What I bear. Mirror, Mirror Real Me-er Alas, My ugly face My demons which devour. Mirror, Mirror Show me my slur Can I look at you? Can I face my true bearer? Mirror, Mirror Broken down in faithless tears. Tattered pieces of shouting facts Mirror, Mirror Oh my judge! ]] My heart cries I can't let you hear my tears rolling down down my memories with pain, with sorrow walking through open sea stepping on shore marking on sand leaving our mark behind. But today I have to leave My life with you has to end here have to leave you to leave for beyond and far away. I go beyond will call out your name several times even if you ain't hear even if you ain't see me I will be there and our hearts will beat at the same time. So long, so long way you have to go without me I disappear in a blink but don't scar remembering me. With emptiness, with void inside The incomplete story has to complete. I hope you find your way which drift you away from me. We will still walk on the beach but my mark won't be left behind. We belong together like ocean and shore here all this distance won't even be there when our hearts beat together So long, so long way I leave you with this gift to move along on your way in happiness and dismay.]] Eyes of sun look through the darkness, Eyes so green drowning oceans' depth. Serene flying bird blooming in blossom cared in tender love taking a leap of life. Spinning through the ride of life settle to be glorified. Spark undead glowing in darkest dread Turn to nothing even if fate betrayed. Ride on collide and fall to ashes burnt out body and soul to live the life. Undead as it is until the soul ends until accepted lost drown the end to bury Taking that last leap taking that last breathe taking that chance The soul is glorified.]] I have to pass through the darkness I have to seek the light Get away from haunting dread My emotions bound in lies. Let go of broken past Broken heart, my soar memories Ones again there will be day The Class* will be written of me. But I need to take A leap of faith to future unseen Enough with the baby steps Its my time of victory Or I die only trying. Its all I feel insida me You aint have to follow my lead But if you take my hand today We help each other, Thats all I can say. So let go to that Class of victory Rejoice our choice To defy treated pathetically Why blend in When we meant to stand out Let jump today Let fight today Let join The Class of 2016. * Reference to The Class  By Erich Segal (one of my favorite authors) written on The Harvard Class58. ]] How I feel for you How I sing for you How I love you But then you take me over Take me over the threshold Take me over the edge Take me over with silence Just don't make me conscious Just don't make me conscious The brightness of the light The floor so sparkling The cross underneath All our love lost behind My life, my aim My destiny calling in But a sip of wine And you take me over the threshold You take me over the edge You make me cold to my soul But don't make me conscious. Let there be little silence Let mourn for lost soul Lets pay a small tribute To the one forever gone Let me join you Let me believe with you Take me over the threshold Take me over the edge Take me over the silence Just don't make me conscious Just don't make me conscious.]] - A vivid story from my Past Life... The spirits standing in front of me The spirits got me talking It tells me to choose Either wrong or let it be right But its a poison to swallow A call of duty for tomorrow. And then a sudden realization I knew, you will look after Listen to my every word I can speak now, But I choked up, I suffocate through my throat And there was blood. Let there be a little wine A tear drop for all divine I call for you I can touch you its my life And I have to survive. All these long years I struggled And my mother cried But there is no rules, No borders From where I stand behind Oh! my soul You been so pure But now I can't mend All that's lost With blood and sole I have lost my soul. Now I sip a little wine Sobbing over My demised essence, Let my tears roll down And my cold heart to mourn. I never knew the other side, That night I crossed The border line. I walked a world apart I could see my edge And a line Separating our soul Taking humanity's toll. Why? Why I ask, I never knew him But he has died I shot him in my cold blood. I knew none But they're gone. The families lost And everyone is cursed. Why? For what? I don't understand. I mourn on myself I serve my country Or am saving myself? Freedom, Rights and dreads Whats a soul, without love Whats the world, without living beings Whats left of a country, with no human touch. But bounded by my laws I have to kill again But I can't, I can't, I can't But I have to kill Until my life ends. I cry for them Its strange but its true But on the border line I kill again I kill until my life ends. I look behind A son and my wife My life left behind Lost too easy, With a shot no hurt Now blood on my hand I could touch my heart Crimson color of my own And I have seen enough. The last glance my dears The snap wet and red. My heart's last beat I closed my eyes With only wish "Before this war eats everything, No Gun held against, No more human sacrificing Before this war stops every heart Our sons grow in that perfect world Grave's love sent And where the war has an end."]] "Denial is the first hurdle for a problem, Acceptance is the first step towards a solution." An inspiration touching that naive face a tragedy that pushes to success breakthrough for inspiring the change denial to chain everything. Let me breathe, Let me go to inspire those certain souls, lost in darkness, lost in unknown, lost in wild anguish, Let me be their peace and hope. Destroyed faith of human nature diminished faith in God decoyed, deceived, disrespected fight ends when everyone is gone. Fight for survival each day struggle to live one more second whales, animals and human beings anguish destroying everything. Hidden in denial Hidden from truth darkness mantled way to move Calm we be breathe air of relief eyes settling in to see a way through finding a way to new future finding a way to live together. Innocent blood shredded be dry move with grave souls, we cry we mourn, but we try a future, a way ahead a fantasy if ever be real. Truth to accept over denial. Appealing all anguish to turn into ashes and peace behold in whole world, where everyone lives together, no one be the master, no one be trained to surrender, no one is killed on the name of God... Is that really not pssible, to dream of such a world? ]] Life turn tide run slash and break over the soar We run fall wretched break our heart our faith Darkness of clouds every where so cold, I am blind hands stretched for you aback I stay, no say rolling into the fears of night Hauted souls dread I feel left alone frighten with ownself reflection mirrored shadows have surrounded captivated in my apprehension saturated with clutter stress I don't have a connection break through, or wrectch my soul. Life turn open eyes I stand to walk anyway choose ways found some suffocation still aint lemme breathe I walk, I walk I keep taking failed steps I see, I can see Lights on day glow bright sun, rise through tunnel ends distant light new morning rising through. Cloudness shreds away fallen darkness has been raised Life will be in place again ripple can turn its way. Destiny held bright unfullfilled purpose to find falling again to fly high keep running, Run again fall again my soul have to rise again life paused, but turn back run ahead to begin again.]] All I feel is hopeless Drive me crazy Am anxious I dont know Whats eating me I am yelling silently In my self. God help me From this feeling I get Save me oh! Save me Save me from myself. I feel nothing expect Am feeling this I feel hatred I feel dread I feel nothing Except I feel this way. I feel nothing Except am dismayed. A haunting feeling everywhere I cant escape No matter am any where My affliction my anguish How can I figure out some way? How can I figure out some way, Until I dont understand my mirrored self. I feel nothing Except for feeling this way Dying crux, my faith giving up On my way Am running away But I cant escape I cant figure choices I make To escape myself To escape this grave Mourning with woes I keep running away. I feel nothing Except for feeling this way I destroyed the good While coming this way. I can run away But cant escape my fate To stand and face Maybe a hope I have, someday. -- Theme Picture borrowed from "Dark Girls" documentary. ]] So on, these words try to make a song but can it utter the pain I have gone? Lights passing out and how I been left alone empty room in silence I mourn. Defied by fate of love in coldness I have abandoned myself. So on, these words are trying to make a song but they can't utter what it takes to be gone. What its like to be gone Lost somewhere all alone never to be found am gone What's to be forever gone. No shoulder to cry on No shoulder to rely on No one I can seek for No one around to be called my own. With invisible existence invisible like am gone in my grave am all alone six feet down in a hole. How's it to be gone Lost somewhere all alone never to be found am gone Gone forever with no mourns.]] For story until now Go To the END : Chapter Seven -  The Dread Room I twisted the golden latch cold it was, as my heart elfin creaking sound echoed through the hall Oh holy mother Oh dear God I galloped my fear and wide open my eyes the door slipped from my hand inviting me with wide open arm. Is my dread too judgmental am I a prey of my own paranoia I took a shaky step put my right foot on the carpet suddenly the window went wide open flapping and beating inside and out heavy wind blowing too harsh too cold and howling with groan It wasn't very soon I took another step, rushed to the window to close its panes But not before I could suceed A bat flew in restlessly flapping hitting the walls sound of its wing frozen my feet my heart beat synced with its flapping wings it rushed across the room so fast to be followed it flew outside through my open door I could hear it in the hall I kept frozen for few seconds then rush to close the door breathing heavy I locked myself in the room like that weird door will protect me from what's there in the hall. I realized my eyes was so wide open I sweated wet in my layers I was breathing so hastily I could drink a gallon of water I calmed myself, it took several minutes what a nightmare my trip till am here ghastly drowned in my past thought I panicked and haunted by own self. I write this now, to let go of my feeling. to calm myself in such dire moment and to note every when and how until this ends. Now I must take a shower cleanup from the trip before am ready to sleep. I ain't know in this creepy room If I can find peace or wait alert to pass this deceive. -- To Be Continued... Until Now in Be My Guest : Chapter One - Boarding The 3:15 Train Chapter Two - Solitude As I Had Asked For Chapter Three - A Dream So Real Chapter Four - Breaking Dawn to Break Free Chapter Five - We Arrive!! Chapter Six - 666 Further on : Chapter Eight - The Dread Room Continues ]] For story until now Go To the END : Chapter Eight -  The Dread Room Continues What say of my juvenile thoughts Ghost and Demon all I can think of. In impeccably ordinary, I see thousand flaws A peace room, not a strange inn though the sound of everything why so petrifying to relax. Everything seems mysterious everything undeniably queer why everyone so aberrant why every moment raising questions in me. What say of my juvenile thoughts should I be really aghast or am being too suspicious. What if, my twisted thoughts show me direction, keep me innocuous. Would I be too naive not considering the odds not seeing whats in front? Do I have a say Can I escape from this? My heart started pounding again with Mysteries surrounding my brain. Let me write down, what happened After writing to my journal, before I write again. I went to take a shower Calm myself, clean from travel. Not long before, I turned the tap. The dripping water wash my thoughts. I heard some sound coming from the room My bathroom door was open and through shower curtains I saw A translucent figure in white gown moving around my bed walking towards the study table at the corner wall I remembered by journal left there unclosed with my last log. I took a moment "what is it? in the room?" "Is it some ghost, some devilish soul been haunting the night?" I cared no more I needed answers I jumped off my shower and busted out of the bathroom to startled the spirit walking around. To my embarrassment I stand naked in front of her The inn lady laying some Milk on the study table with care and love She turned and closed her eyes she chuckled and smiled without a word between us I rushed to cover myself. I came back into the room after a while of spent embarrassment the nice old lady was standing by with her head down and a wrinkly smile. I apologized to her "I thought you were something else" She kept smiling and told in her weird accent "No Ghost, no haunted, this room safe." "How you got in? I locked the door from inside." "No, No... Young Lad. I have a master key work on any door in here. I hear you wanted Milk you sleep, for sleep come well. Pardon me, if I scare you. I mean no harm, so be true." I smile at her innocent tone "I thought of asking for Milk, but you already read my mind. Am sorry to startled you like this. Now can I wish you goodnight." She turned to leave, but suddenly crossed herself and looked at me. "You want to say something?" I asked In some trans she replied "Thou be devil's slave, slaughter and burn in hell, thy unseal the door of grave murder thy soul thyself" she spoke with somber tone in perfect English accent she ever spoke. Without waiting another moment she left the room door slammed behind her with wind from the window. I rushed again, to close the pane I locked the door and with questioning thoughts "What did she mean? why she made that remark? How she spoke such good English when she couldn't even say correct words?" I retired to the chair took the covered glass while drinking my Milk I saw a letter. A letter addressed to me "But who wrote this?" I turned the envelop its signed - Count Dracula at your service. Now am writing my journal thinking should now I read it? Thinking about the good lady and suddenly what gotten in. All this strange situation only one I feel connection Count Dracula my host and his kind letter maybe our first communication. Let me say goodnight to my journal I'll read this letter am holding then I will retired for tonight hope sleep will fix this weird night. -- To Be Continued... Until Now in Be My Guest : Chapter One - Boarding The 3:15 Train Chapter Two - Solitude As I Had Asked For Chapter Three - A Dream So Real Chapter Four - Breaking Dawn to Break Free Chapter Five - We Arrive!! Chapter Six - 666 Chapter Seven - The Dread Room ]] Am a drop of blood am the heart break that bleeds am broken soul misunderstood and diminished am the dead past forgotten even from dreams. Am a drop of blood when you murder your soul I cried but you didn't reconcile It died screaming and crawling but you didn't even realized the miseries killed you and you were lost to fate defied you changed your path you changed yourself for adapting mud and dirt lies and dishonesty Am your drop of blood that you had lost ain't even noticing what's gone. Am your screaming soul Am your drop of blood Am your broken heart but nothing change since you changed your path I keep screaming come back come back am a drop of blood am the heart break that bleeds am broken soul misunderstood and diminished am the dead past forgotten even from dreams. Am the heart break when you have broken a heart innocent souls been cheated with your lies. Left in misery you search a new path you found light in darkness Camouflaging your nastiness you pretend to be innocent You infect other souls around lost in distrust made someone else like you What have you done? How you could erase yourself? Remember how your heart been broken how could you break it too I have to understand there is no end to misery there is no sign of salvation in selling your soul. I will keeping screaming for you to come back for your soul to be pure Come back Come back for am a drop of blood am the heart break that bleeds am broken soul misunderstood and diminished am the dead past forgotten even from dreams. No resolute can bring me in memories faded from where you believed in Am not gonna fight to stay not gonna stick to you but breaking dawn will prove to you darkness will be gone and morning shine will make you whole. Am your drop of blood Am your heart break Am your broken soul Am your dead past lost in your dreams Am a part of you that you have lost.]] How you will like to loose your loving wife? A person you love beyond any imagination possible, may be others do understand or don't, none matter until you love each other - But if you're forced then, how you will choose to loose your wife, your soul-mate? Options : 1. Spending each day, and living each day to the fullest knowing that finally you will loose her to death. She will pass away in the hands to some darkness never to come back. You want to love her so much, pour your heart your love in each day so badly that maybe she won't be there again tomorrow to know that how much you love her. But then again when sun shines and you see her smile, sunlight reflecting through her shaved head, you laugh with tears in your eyes, feeling sad and glad all at the same time. Again with a hope. Today its your last day to show her your heart, tear open all the emotion you have for her. Then that last day comes, the last day you have to say all that you wanna say. You gonna know this is it, when she holds your hand and says "I had a wonderful life with you. I loved it all." and closes her eyes. Your night and day paused at that moment. And you jus can't move with the numbness and stillness. Your heart chocked out in your throat but you can hear it beating so hard and crying silently to make it stop, so that you can leave with her. But dear this is how you choose to loose your wife not how you leave with your wife. 2. Spending each day fighting with your parent, for the honor and respect they defy to serve you and your wife with. Crying, yelling, trying to explain them every action and intention. Waking up each morning with despair that you and your wife paying as the price of jus' being in love and choosing each other. Living in hell, in stress overwhelmed with disgrace and dishonor. Scared that your loved ones will be hurt if you try to loose those not so well wishing parents. Who want you to be miserable each day jus because they want to fulfill their uncompromised ego and unwilling to understand you and your emotions. Further they punish you by snatching away your life and your love because you have to stick around them or they black mail you by hurting the ones you care for. You have to keep witnessing them, blaming and criticizing the one you love with baseless untrue argument without uttering a word. Certainly progressively growing distance between you and your wife sooner or later, even though you may feel deep love inside for her. No way you get to share either your anger for your parents or your deep love for your wife. Your parent will never accept their defied ego for the name of your happiness, those parents are rare breed. But how long will you expect, your wife to be the only one to support and understand you. Although you continue to carry you parents problems on your shoulders. You can't sail on two boats simultaneously. Its not about choosing your love. It is the matter between wrong and right, justice and unfairness. In this case you definitely have to loose your wife because your parents are blood sucking leeches and selfish parasites who doesn't let go easy. Hence spending each day with your wife bearing stress and burden. Sometimes avoiding each other 'coz some talk may trigger the bubbling but covered anguish, or yelling out at each other 'coz a small coke-can has spilled over and its too much stress for you both. Ending up separated with pain, even though you love each other unimaginably on the name of heaven and earth. You feel equal pain as the guy you might be in the first option. Difference is you know she is out there but no where around you. You can't see her face anymore. Not smiling, not talking, not even fighting. She exists but she is defunct for you. It worst than loosing her to death. But You have lost your wife. Accept it, Swallow it, you have to live with it. Whose fault? your parents who forced you to go through this? or your wife who didn't pull this up to the end? Or its you? making the right choice? Now tell me How you choose to loose your wife? - Being a wife I can say, no wife in this world who loves her husband wants to be in the second option. If I can and have a choice, I tell my husband - We live our life to the fullest, till death does us apart. I better go away with the first option living a wonderful life and loving him till the end than dying everyday in the later burying my emotion in my shut doors, being extinct to the one I love everyday with all my heart but can't say that I love you. I wish, if I have a choice. But you have. So decide - How you choose to Loose your Wife? Think about it, if you're in a situation caught up with the option 2 and you are suddenly struck with a news like option 1, will you still agree to keep getting bullied, and keep nodding over the white-collared blackmails. Or will you want to spend each and every moment with your wife cherishing the past emotions creating new memories and pouring your love, your heart into the present keeping aside all the pending fights, all the unanswered complaints, keeping whole world apart from your life which might hurt her on her those last counting days. If you agree to the latter, why wait for such a news as option 1, and why not cherish every moment as it might be your last together, so that you never have to be that one guy in option 2 ever again... ]] Oh! the howling wind did angels come down with black wings Olympus' doors were broken with distress and disgust Oh! the mother nature anger burst with fiery thunders "You humans shred blood on my soil crushed me, ruptured my heart wretched everything I have wrecked my soul to the very core. Now stand to face me when I come ridding those howling winds I sing to diminish you vanish forever from this earth." Oh! the angels wore their black wings with tremor and hurricane they came riding the howling wind ready to bleed shatter the unholy souls angels with black wings ready to fight for mother earth. "God has given up hope and trust disgrace you humans of earth. Now we wear these black wings wings of destruction. To erase you, to finish you. Your end will be a lesson survive or surrender face our thunder if you have a holy heart come face our anger." Mother earth's howls her sadness and angry cries The God needs a hope pure human with holy souls. There is a chance all she wishes her children to understand. Those insane winds passed away carried mass of destruction howling "I diminish you all, crushing you to dust" With a warning they return Now its time to think what's next and what was wrong Shall there be a change an inspiration? Shall we stand beside each other with sole passion? Would there be any trust behold? Would there be another hope? Is it possible to restore, the lost and the gone, the Utopian land in our hope?]] Its scary heart beating too fast echoing sound haunting through the walls my breathless soul my heart chocked in my throat living in dread too afraid to escape Now I know there'll be distractions but ain't it possible at least to take that chance too afraid to fail too scared to try take a leap of faith with your closed eyes. Close those eyes focus at the light let all the sound vanish and listen only to own breathing breath, taken in or relieved breathe slowly and deeply let all your fears go away vanish into the grey let go of your dread with the air you exhale. Pause a while tell yourself you're ready to survive. You're excited to face your fears and your dread. Mercy takes you away and your life is about to change take that one step whatever is ahead can't fail if not tried but failed to confront what's inside.]] The spirit departed from this world come, take me in your arms haunt my core soul and lift me higher above this world. Above the clouds, above everything, that ever mattered above everything, that will be encountered. Spirit gone, departed from earth give me power to see this universe with clear eyes, I see past and future no lies to hide, no truth be defied. Oh! Spirit between heaven and earth I can't take this pain to be mortal survivor haunt me or devour my sole but take me away from this unholy world. With agony I suffer get me a miracle, when I falter. Oh! the holy spirit the angel of good and evil fly me to the destiny I envision, and I dream. Oh!! The spirit departed from this world come take me in your arms haunt my core soul and lift me higher above this world. Help me when I chase my dream a dot of light in my dark tunnel show me way to proceed my only way to salvation, is to succeed. Oh! the departed spirit show me if you exist help me find a miracle restore my belief. I jump with closed eyes to leap beyond the edges where no one ever reached fly me there where dreams are real to believe.]] Thine soul, emerged from grave, covered in dirt, with sins dismay, oh! the unholiness, so unexpressed, Ye left the earth, murdering thyself. Buried under disgrace and disgust, conscience mantled with lies and regret, thine foul sole, breezy night crying howls, despicable cavalier brought thy shame oh! mercy thy humane soul, oh! mercy thee God of the world. Forbid thy darkness in heart the black stone thou stab in back thou be the slave of evil a drop of blood thy sold on the name devil. Now buried under pile of dust no sole, no word serve for thine loss, forgotten from the world, erase from memoirs, no one recalls not a lone tear ye shalt have. A word for thine loss but thou deserve nothing at all. Dead to the world, to heaven, dead to all, and to hope! Thine soul, emerged from grave, covered in dirt, since a decade. Oh! the unholiness of thine soul, several mistakes ajar, undone, several chances passed away when thou missed thy adept stint. Abreast buried under grey stone buried in loneself and loneliness, moving with no propensities no direction. Lost road, captivated alone, eyes open but nothing ahead Nailed in a coffin under dark grave abhor thine ugliness, thine to see, thine to own, how utter thou hast thy ghost haunts only thyself. -- Tribute to Edgar Allan Poe with lines from William Wilson, " Dead to the world, to heaven, and to hope! " ]] Sometime you have to jus jump Not thinking where would you land the choices between the wrong and the right blur the edges, blur the outcome whatever it might be Jus' jump, Jus' jump take a leap of faith it may not be but it may. Risk all you have thy soul you trust Leave your conscience aside and take a decision on guts Sometime you don't have the time to plan out your life around for a while you are already in the battle with no weapon you have to fight you may die but you dead already? if no so you fight use all you have fight harder and harder to survive ask yourself what is your destination what is that you want strive hard and jus take that jump with blind eyes no logic will last no plan with make the path you have no choice all along nothing matter when you jus jump alone Jus' jump, Jus' jump take the leap of faith if you dare you may die taking chances bloody floor where you landed but it might be that you fly nothing matter if you reach your destination. so forget everything and jus jump.]] Life is such a beauty played with games of betrayal Love is cursed unfaithful and crushed being untrusted No diamond can shine forever dull with dismay let go and run to horizon never look back until your death My soul tied between heaven and earth is confused state who I am? who I have been? what i lived for what I lived with with lies and deceptions which I trusted Now  earth left my soul Not I choose this end but shattering my faith my life taken away. swallow the pain the burn flavor gallop in with numb limbs my aching heart says only this Life is such a beauty played with games of betrayal Love is cursed unfaithful and crushed being untrusted Love unreal, untrue make me pathetically suffer you whore of betrayal.]] 