 "Requiem (For the Damaged)" 22" x 30" Acrylic on wood. Above is my new piece for Roq la Rue Gallery 's 'Lush Life 3' group show, opening this Friday. Below are some detail shots: There was a lot on my mind while I painted this, so if you're curious, read on: &lt;!-- /* Font Definitions */ @font-face {font-family:Cambria; panose-1:2 4 5 3 5 4 6 3 2 4; mso-font-charset:0; mso-generic-font-family:auto; mso-font-pitch:variable; mso-font-signature:3 0 0 0 1 0;} /* Style Definitions */ p.MsoNormal, li.MsoNormal, div.MsoNormal {mso-style-parent:""; margin:0in; margin-bottom:.0001pt; mso-pagination:widow-orphan; font-size:12.0pt; font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-ascii-font-family:Cambria; mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family:Cambria; mso-fareast-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family:Cambria; mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-bidi-theme-font:minor-bidi;} @page Section1 {size:8.5in 11.0in; margin:1.0in 1.25in 1.0in 1.25in; mso-header-margin:.5in; mso-footer-margin:.5in; mso-paper-source:0;} div.Section1 {page:Section1;} --&gt; This piece is dedicated to all people who create during times of social upheaval, war, natural disasters, or any other kind of turmoil. Even though I dont live in a war-torn country or in the wilderness, fighting each day for survival, I ingest hundreds of stories and perspectives during the course of one painting, in the form of news commentary, political interviews, military documentaries, and podcasts on history, psychology, and anything pertaining to the human condition. It can often become harrowing to listen to all of this while trying to create something that has beauty, magic, and hope. This is what I imagine it must be like for a creatrix like Demeter or any other embodiment of mother nature, who is destined to create for eternity, while the world responds with death, darkness, and destruction. I wanted to capture the melancholy of a goddess that has come to this realization and ponders her fate and that of the world, the ghosts and demons, the dying and the living. The red stream of fabric in her hands represents life blood- she holds it to her chest with her right hand, as it slips through the fingers of her left. There is a powerful paradox between life and death, between creation and destruction, and though she understands the importance of her role in the balance of the universe, there is a sobering acceptance of the grim reality in her gaze. Death is everywhere, but so is rebirth and magic, which springs from the darkness of the unknown, from the heart of the cosmos, and makes life worth living, or at least a bit more bearable. If you made it this far, you get a bit of news : I will be releasing prints of  'Sleeping Sickness' (below) sometime next week, with the option to purchase as a large-sized print or as a mini print. There will be free mini-sketches included with select orders. Check back here, follow me on facebook , or on twitter (@mllemiaaraujo) for updates on that score! ]] My copy of the latest Spectrum annual came in the post this week, so here are some snaps of my entries- excuse the glares! It is a rather glossy book. Fantastic cover art by the great Jean-Sebastien Rossbach! "Snow In Summer," my first accepted entry in the 'Book' category! "The Priestess" in the 'Unpublished' category. "Two Spirits," in the final spread of the 'Unpublished' section! And super-honored to be printed opposite Michael Whelan. Also this week, I finished my painting for Roq la Rue Gallery 's "Lush Life" group show, which opens next Friday in Seattle. It's a bit different from what I've done before, and a good 'preview' of what my solo show pieces will be like. I will share images sometime next week, so stay tuned... ]] Porcelain, Ivory, Steel. 16 x 20. Acrylic on wood. Forgive the delay, but I've had a flurry of different things going on the past few months, some of which I'm still unable to share right now. But today I can finally unveil my contribution to HBO and Mondo Gallery 's  Game of Thrones  group exhibit, opening March 8 th at SXSW in Austin, TX. It was a dream come true and an absolute thrill to paint so many of my favorite characters from my favorite show on television..all with HBO's approval! Below are some of my sketches and studies done in preparation for the piece, back in January. I finished the piece in February, so you can imagine how long I've been dying to share it with you ;) For those of you near Austin, the opening reception will be from 7pm-10pm on the 8th, and the show runs til March 12 th . Do take photos and share them, if you go! More about the show here: For inquiries/sales please contact gallery@mondotees.com Or view their website after the show opens, for the preview page. More from me soon!! xxx ]] "Secrets of the Deep" 8.5" x 14" Acrylic on wood. It's been a long time since I've posted here- my apologies! I've been juggling a lot of things these past few months, and honestly facebook , instagram , and twitter are a bit easier for me to update than this here blog. But I will do my best to get back on the ball here :) Above is my most recent piece, which was part of Copro Gallery 's 'Anomalies' group show curated by Jon Beinart. My 'Feral' study (below) will also be in Tokyo at Shinjuku Ganka Gallery starting tomorrow, Friday the 15th, as a part of the 'Hivezilla' group exhibition, curated by Nathan Cartwright! "Feral" study 6" x 9" Graphite on paper. Other than that, I am currently focusing on commissions (which I will be sharing as I finish) and small originals that I will be posting for sale on my bigcartel store . So be sure to check back there often for new things! In other news, I have revamped my website ! It is no longer flash-based, and can be viewed on all mobile devices and ipads. Sheesh- it's about time! I also recently joined deviantart and behance - so be sure to follow, if you are on either of those sites. I'm overdue for a sketch dump- so that will be in a future post! Until next time... be swell! xxx ]] Tom Bagshaw's first show at Corey Helford Gallery , alongside David Stoupakis. Some may be turned off by the fact that he works digitally, but I am on the other side of the aisle- I have just as much respect for digital painters as I do for an oil, acrylic, gouache, or watercolor painter. Each of these mediums can be regarded as being 'easier' to work with, depending on the artist, but each requires just as much skill to handle successfully. In fact, I think digital painters have to work harder to achieve the warmth and life that Tom puts into his paintings..much like computer animators trying to capture the essence of hand-drawings. To me, the imagery and the feeling I get from it, is what captivates me- regardless of the medium. I have been entranced by Tom's works for more than a year now, and he delivers every time! I was equally impressed by the presentation of his work- the framing and varnishing really pulls you into the piece. I took some detail shots to try to capture the effect, but see for yourself if you are in the area! The show closes this Saturday. Tom is also starting up an exciting new project called 3Cs - in which he will paint 100 digital portrait studies in 100 hours, over 100 days. The first 100 people to show at the Fine Art Print Company in Bath, UK at noon on the 1st of September will have the honor of being painted by him over the next three and half months! Makes me wish I lived in the South West of England! For more info on how you can get involved, follow the link for the project blog here . ]] Corey Helford Gallery) for nearly 2 months now. In addition to being halfway through a few paintings and sketching for a few more, I've been drawing madly in my sketchbook...here are 10 sample pages for you to see. Busy, busy... ]] See the previous post for details on the sketch-giveaway! ]] I've been crazy-busy with painting, but I have a few things to share with you. The good folks at Spectrum posted a video preview of the upcoming 18th annual! My three pieces can be seen during minutes 1:33, 6:02, and 6:54, respectively...so excited to see them in print! It's an amazing-looking book, and apparently already available for pre-order on Amazon . Go get it! Next up...some simple costume sketches that I've been doing from Downton Abbey , which I'm currently obsessed with. I'm not a tv person, but this show is right up my alley, particularly since I've adored the Edwardian period for more than a decade, and get sucked right into that world. Love it! And here's the full image of the modified master copy in oils that I posted last time...just an exploration with paint strokes. (Pardon the wonky camera angle.) Lastly, huge thanks to Ricardo Ferreira for spreading the love and showcasing my work on his blog ! Very kind of you, sir. More soon, I promise! Until next time... ]] My solo show opens tomorrow, May 12th at Corey Helford Gallery! Above is the gallery's ad in the May issue of Art News . Huge thanks to Hi-Fructose , Juxtapoz , Daily duJour , Arrested Motion , and Platinum Cheese for spreading the word:) There are 7 paintings and 10 drawings total, my largest output ever! I will be posting all the images from the show by Monday, but in the meantime, here is the info on prints: The above piece will be available as a print here, through the gallery . "Predators" Giclee Print Image size: 22"? x 15"? Printed on a  24"? x 17" sheet? of Moab Entrada Rag Natural 300 fine art paper. Limited edition of 50, signed numbered. $150. In the meantime, you may phone or email CHG to order: sarah@coreyhelfordgallery.com | 310.287.2340 For those of you in LA, the first 300 guests at the door Saturday night will receive a free mini print of "Forest Healer"- see above for scale :) So please stop by if you can- I'd love to meet you and share what I've been working on for the past 10 months! xxx ]] I have some new small originals for sale, including the Arya study for my Game of Thrones piece! I've been working on a top secret project for the past couple months, which is where most of these pieces came from...in the meantime you can snag them while they last at www.miafineart.bigcartel.com 'Nightshade' 12" x 12" Acrylic on wood. This past weekend, I was happy to be a part of Corey Helford Gallery 's 'Art Collector Startup Kit' Group Show. Each artist created a 12" x 12" piece to be offered at lower price points in order to encourage new collectors to pick up an original from their favorite artists. If you are interested in my piece (above), please contact jch@coreyhelfordgallery.com or sherri@coreyhelforgallery.com More soon! xxx ]] Next, I tried a more simplistic approach with a random image: Here is an oil study for one of my solo show pieces that I am currently working on in acrylic. It got a bit choppy and thick, but it was valuable practice. (The final piece will not have candles with dodgy halos in it, mind). And here are a few 2 1/2 hour model paintings from Ignat Ignatov 's class, which I took a few months ago. All are 12" x 16": There's so much to improve on with these, but the important part is that I had a lot of fun with a foreign medium. I also think that my acrylic work is definitely benefiting from everything I learned here. If you ever get the chance, take Ignat's class- he is a terrific and encouraging instructor! And just to keep them all together in the same post, I'll repost my last oil study (an attempt to go thicker with the paint on a smaller canvas), after Howard Chandler Christy: Working on a piece for Roq la Rue 's 'Lush Life' group show right now, which opens next month...stay tuned! ]] I recently joined instagram, and have been sharing some progress and process shots as a way to document the final 2 months of work on my solo show. Feel free to add me! (mllemia) Here is an instagrid link for those of you not on instagram, if you want to take a peek at last week's action. I also cross post some of the photos on facebook and twitter , but the instagrid link will continually update as well. Above is a drawing study of one of my models, several of which I plan on including in the exhibition. More soon! xxx ]] Hope everyone had a lovely end of the last year! I'm working like mad, but thought I'd take a breather to let you know that postcard sets are now available to order here at my online store . They are only $4 each + free shipping. Details below: You will receive all of the above postcards. One will be signed at random. Two of the cards have images on both sides (above). The other two have text on the back. Phone numbers and old email addresses on those are defunct, by the way ;) Free shipping on all orders via USPS first class mail. (International buyers have the option of adding tracking for an additional cost). Here is the fancy blue envelope you will receive, snugly enclosing your order! Sketchbook stuff (and maybe some sneak peeks and process stuff) soon...but now, the easel beckons! ]] I've been working like a madwoman on my show (what's new?), and still going...but here's something I can share at the moment! Tomorrow at Last Rites Gallery , a very interesting artist collaboration and live painting event will be taking place, and I am honored to be a part of it. The participating artists who are not on the east coast (I am one of those) were asked to make a 24"x30"ish sketch on a provided canvas, which will then be painted by the local artists who are attending the live-painting event tomorrow afternoon. The finished collaboration pieces will be auctioned off that evening to raise money for the International Child Art Foundation . Here is the press release if you'd like more info. Follow this link to view all of the canvas sketches. Mine is below: For those of you in New York, here is the info to attend, as well as the list of participating artists. Should be fun to watch the painters at work, so if you are able to make it and take photos, feel free to post a link in the comments :) I have some very busy months ahead, but I will try to post more often! Hope you've all been well :) P.S.: Thanks SO much to everyone who's been buying postcards and prints the past couple months- every little bit helps me to keep doing what I'm doing, and I'm extremely grateful! xxx UPDATE: Follow this link for the ebay listings for all of the collab paintings, and to see how they all turned out! This is your chance to get some great deals on artwork by all of the artists involved, and to help a good cause at the same time. ]] The contest is officially closed, and I've been announcing the winners on each site. Here, I skipped over the double-comments and counted from the total of 18, so the winner is Karen! I will be emailing you later this afternoon, or you can go ahead and email me your mailing address if you get there before I do :) Congrats!! Thanks so much to each of you for entering! There were 286 entries across the board- I wish I had that many prints and could afford to mail them to all of you ? Really, your support means the world! More soon... xxx ]] Proofing the upcoming print release...pricing and release date info soon! The lame phone pic will have to do for now ;) Busy, busy! ]] Please forgive my lack of updates- I've been up to quite a bit since my last post. But most importantly, I'd like to share that tomorrow 1xRun and I are releasing two print editions of 'Forest Healer', at noon EST/9am PST. You can choose between a limited hand-embellished edition, or a standard edition, both are the same size, and only available for 10 days here: Standard Edition Hand-Embellished Edition 1xRun prints sell out rather quickly, so be sure to follow those links if you want to get in on the action! There will also be a couple of originals available for purchase- just scroll down when you get to this link if you're interested. I'm going to share some new works in my next post, so keep your eyes peeled ;) Mia xxx ]] I want to take a moment to share a very special painting that I had the chance to create last year, for one of my most ardent fans, Hasan Niyazi. Sadly, he passed away last month, far too young, at 38. I am so humbled to have known him, albeit briefly and across oceans, and will always regret never having had the chance to meet him in person. Hasan described himself as an amateur art historian, but he was as passionate and knowledgeable about Renaissance painters (especially Raphael), as the professionals. He reached out to me for an interview in 2011 , and I had the pleasure of answering some of the most interesting and thoughtful questions of any interview I'd accepted. He'd never bought an original painting before, but wanted to start his collection with a piece from me- a true honor. His commission request was unique, as it was the first time a client asked me for a painting of himself done in the renaissance style. I was a bit nervous as it was way out of my comfort zone, but in the end he loved what I did with it, and I was happy with the results as well. So in celebration of his life and love of Renaissance portraiture, I will share his inspiration for this piece and a bit of the process. Every element in this piece had personal significance to him, and was specifically requested, so I had to compose them in the most practical way to fit the basis of his inspiration, this painting which is rumored to be Raphael's self portrait: -Hasan wanted his likeness in Renaissance garb, and offered styling suggestions by providing example paintings of the period. -The hills near his house, the view from those hills of the city skyline, bushy trees, and what he called the 'magical looking dead tree' near his house, all were very important to the picture. -His two cats, Astro and Kimba make an appearance. -The ring on his finger and the Rose of Sharon, are both for his beloved partner of 12 years (which I placed near his heart). -He even wanted a subtle Star Wars reference, and provided a piece of concept art of Jabba's Palace. -The brooch on his hat bears the image of Aphrodite, as a reference to Cyprus, the birthplace of his parents and the Greek deity. -He also sent me a photo of sunset clouds near his home, that I adapted into the piece. -It was certainly a challenge, and I had to scrap the painting at one point and start over completely, as I had lost the freshness in the first attempt. But it was all worth it, to hear his overjoyed response upon seeing it finished and in receiving it early this year. Here is my second attempt at the painting, still in the rough stage. The final piece. 7" x 7" Acrylic on wood. I still can't believe I finished this painting a year ago today, and it makes me very sad to know that he left us all so soon. One of the last messages I received from Hasan was a tweet telling me how lucky he felt to own an original piece of mine, and that he counted it among his most prized possessions. A photo of the portrait, framed, and hanging on his bedroom wall. Here's to you, Hasan, wherever you may be. You will be missed. And to his loved ones and family, I wish you strength and much love. A very special thanks to Sharon for granting me permission to make this post. xxx ]] Quick post so you can mark your calendars...and here is the first super-washed out progress pic that I can share from my new body of work, to be unveiled in just over two months at Corey Helford Gallery ! This is a detail from one of the larger pieces in the show. And now, back to work! ]] Here is a sketchdump of a bunch of stuff I've been doing on the side over the last couple months. Drawing comes more naturally to me, so whenever I need to take a break from painting, I like to do studies like this. The first several are large-sized drawings done on newsprint, the last 5 are from my sketchbook. And yes, the lighting in these photos is a tad too warm- apologies! ]] Thank you so very much to everyone who participated in my first giveaway- yes that's right, the implication that there will be more in the future is intentional ;) I am still floored by how many of you entered- your kind and encouraging words were definitely taken to heart, and will help tremendously when I start running out of steam in the coming months ^___^ Really, I wish I had an original for each of you to walk away with, but at least know that there will be future opportunities. I leave you with a detail of a quick oil study I did of a Howard Chandler Christy painting last week...still need to fix some bits, but 'twas fun! ]] "Oryu-yanagi" 36" x 24" Acrylic on wood. Hi-Fructose was kind enough to post about my upcoming show , and reveal the above piece. Less than a month away...exciting! It seems like as long as I'm busy, posts here will come once a month, eh? As I said last time around, I've been posting a lot of little progress shots on instagram. Here is a sampling for those of you not on there (it's finally on android though, so follow @mllemia if you join :) More soon! xxx ]] UPDATE: Comments are now closed, and the winner will be announced later on Wednesday...stay tuned! Ive decided to do something special this week in honor of everyone who has supported me, encouraged me, bought originals or prints, sent me emails, tattooed my work onto themselves, etc. etc! Being a self-employed artist is not easy, but every single one of you has made it possible for me. And for that I will be eternally grateful! So! Here is your chance to win one of my painting studies (below). Even though it's unfinished, it's one of my favorites. As you can see, her desk-mates will be sad to see her go :) 'Gasp!' study 5" x 7" Acrylic on clayboard To Enter: Leave a comment on this post with your name and email address , so I can contact you if you win (I wont send you spam, promise!). It's entirely optional to leave a personal message, but I would greatly appreciate it :) The cut-off time for comments will be Tuesday, October 11th when the clock strikes midnight (PST) . I will then select a winner at random, and congratulate him/her in a new post the following day. May randomness favor you, and thank you all so very much! ]] It's time for another fan appreciation giveaway! I have some extra mini prints from my solo show (above) that the printer made as backups, so those of you who couldn't make the opening- here's your chance! The image size is 5" x 7", and it's signed (unlike the opening night ones). -To enter, simply leave a comment on this post with your email address , so I can contact you if you win (You will not be added to any mailing list, nor will you be assaulted with spam). -You may leave a personal comment if you wish, always appreciated, but not mandatory :) -As usual, I shall select the winner via random number generator. -Contest ends Tuesday June 5th at midnight PST. In addition, I will be giving away 5 more of these, each on a different social network platform - tumblr , facebook , my facebook fanpage , instagram (@mllemia), and twitter . Follow the links to find my giveaway post for each, and enter in as many as you wish- one entry per site/platform, for a maximum of 6 entries...make sense? May randomness favor you, and thank you very much for your support!! p.s.: It's taking me a while to do a proper post about all of my new work, so in the meantime, check the new gallery section on my website for images, detail shots, and framed shots! More soon :) ]] Finally- print release details! "Sleeping Sickness" will be available in 2 editions on Thursday, December 15th at 1PM PST at my webshop: www.miafineart.bigcartel.com Since this is the first time that I am releasing my own prints, I've decided to do two editions- a larger-sized, more 'collectible' piece with a small edition size...and a mini print with a larger edition size, for those of you who just want this image on your wall. Read on for pricing, exact sizes, etc: Pretty sure most of you can imagine how big the large print will be, so this is the image size of the mini-print. It will have a wider border on each side though: And here is the fan appreciation par t! I've decided to give more people the opportunity to win a mini-original from me, and just as before, randomness shall be the judge. &lt;!-- /* Font Definitions */ @font-face {font-family:Cambria; panose-1:2 4 5 3 5 4 6 3 2 4; mso-font-charset:0; mso-generic-font-family:auto; mso-font-pitch:variable; mso-font-signature:3 0 0 0 1 0;} /* Style Definitions */ p.MsoNormal, li.MsoNormal, div.MsoNormal {mso-style-parent:""; margin:0in; margin-bottom:.0001pt; mso-pagination:widow-orphan; font-size:12.0pt; font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-ascii-font-family:Cambria; mso-ascii-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-fareast-font-family:Cambria; mso-fareast-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-hansi-font-family:Cambria; mso-hansi-theme-font:minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family:"Times New Roman"; mso-bidi-theme-font:minor-bidi;} @page Section1 {size:8.5in 11.0in; margin:1.0in 1.25in 1.0in 1.25in; mso-header-margin:.5in; mso-footer-margin:.5in; mso-paper-source:0;} div.Section1 {page:Section1;} --&gt; Every 5 five orders, I will choose a number at random, and include a free mini-sketch with the winner's order. 1-5, 6-10, 11-15...all the way up to 75, a number will be selected within each batch. So there will be 15 chances to win on mini-print orders (75 divided by 5 is 15...), and 5 chances to win on large-print orders (25 divided by 5...well, you get it!). In total, 20 mini-sketches will be awarded . I will leave it a surprise, so if you win, you will know when you open your package. Limit 2 orders per customer (in case you are getting a gift for a friend and one for yourself...but please stick to this guys, or I shall be cross). Below are some of the mini-sketches that I will be giving away...they measure roughly 3 1/2" x 4 1/2", graphite and white pencil on toned paper: Check back here on Thursday morning for a reminder, or follow me on facebook and twitter ! ]] 