 1. Define objectives first from a consumer's, not an advertiser's, point of view. 2. Target the campaign to create value for consumers. 3. Test, listen, and adjust ads to improve the customer experience. 4. Evaluate an expansion strategy. 5. Constantly look for ways to refresh the message. There are four spheres: Public Sphere, Social Sphere, Tribal Sphere and Psychological Sphere ]] Click the link given below to see the guidelines: http://goo.gl/dGwT4 ]] Just finished it watching for the 2nd time. Wonderful Cinematography and awesome breathtaking shots of Iceland....!! Worth watching it twice or thrice . On September 15, 2008 at 1.50 A.M, Lehman Brothers filed for bankruptcy. I still remember that, It was my first day to the college for attending the B.E (ECE) orientation session with Vinod and Mythin Khan but that time I didn't know the impact of the 2008 crisis on the world economy. Now I do know it..! [WARNING : Lengthy Review Ahead] Inside Job is a documentary written, produced directed by Charles Ferguson. Sony Pictures was the market distributor. The story unfolds in Iceland with the Internationalization of 3 large banks of Iceland. The interesting thing about Iceland is that with a population of 3,20,000 and a GDP of US $13 billion, they had a banking losses running into US $100 billion dollars. This was the starting point of recession. The Global economic crisis of 2008 costs tens of millions their savings, their jobs their homes. THEME: The story of economic crisis of 2008. SHOOTING PLACES: Iceland, New York, London France. MUSIC: The opening theme music is wonderful to listen and was composed by Alex Heffes. AWARD: It won the Academic Awards for the best documentary feature RUNNING TIME: 1hr and 45 minutes KEY CAUSE: Sub Prime Lending for buying houses. The term "sub prime lending" means, lending to borrowers who don't have the capacity to repay it. (i.e.) Poor credit worthiness of the borrower. They do it to get higher interest rates which in turn will bring in more profits. Budget: US$ 2million Box Office: US$ 7million IMDB Rating: 8.2/10 DRAWBACKS: Little bit of patience is needed to watch this film, Its better to have your headset plugged in so that you can hear better. If companies around the globe are unable to borrow, they'll begin to cut jobs, cease investment, and default on their debt in larger numbers. - Peter Coy BW, 3rd October, 2008 REASONS FOR THE CRISIS: 1) The housing bubble 2) Poor creditworthiness of borrowers 3)Home loan borrowers unable to pay the EMI's due to rising interest rates. 4) High leverage ratios of investment banks. 5)Speculation in the derivatives market 6) Collapse of major global banks in US Iceland 7) Greediness unethical practices of Investment Banks, Credit rating Agencies, Auditing Firms, Financial services firms, CEOs, CFOs, stock market traders, bokers , sub prime lenders Insurance Companies. 8)SEC (securities Exchange Commission failed in discharging its duty 9) Heavy speculation and betting in the derivatives market. 10) Complex financial products which where difficult to comprehend. MAJOR AFFECTED COMPANIES: 5 investment banks: Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley, Lehman Brothers, Merrill Lynch Bears Stearn's 2 financial conglomerates: Citigroup JP Morgan 3 Credit Rating Agencies: Moody's, Standard Poor's and Fitch. 3 Securities Insurance: AIG, MBIA and AMBAC AFTER CRISIS: The government bailed out the troubled firms by doling out a package of around US $700 billion dollars. This was done through TRAP (Troubled Assets Relief Program). KEY SPEAKERS: Dominque Strauss Khan, George Soros, Eliot Spitzer, Lagarde, Paul Volcker, Charles Morris, Nouriel Roubni, Ben Bernake, Satyajit Das Robert Gnaizda The film is divide into five parts: PART I: HOW WE GOT HERE? After the 1929 Great depression, banking industry was tightly regulated. The US Finacial sector was stabe for the next 50 years. By late 1990's financial sector consolidated into a few gigantic global firms, each of them so large that their failure could threaten the whole economic system. During the late 90's deregulation and advancement of technology led to the explosive growth of complex financial products called derivatives. In 1998, Citicorp and travelers merged to form the world's largest financial services firm. In 1999 Gramm- Leach - Billey Act overturned the Glass Stegal Act which protected the invetors money from risky investments. SEC and CFTC were incharge of soverseeing the investment banks and the regulation of derivative markets. Trillions of dollars of mortagages were sold by lenders to the investment banks which in turn created CDO's (Collateralized Debt Obligation) and sold it to the investors. These mortgages mostly composed of sub prime loans, but CDO's were given the highest rating (AAA) by the rating agencies such as SP, Fitch Moody's. It was rated on par with Govt. Securities. Pension Funds were also invested in the CDO's. Investors bought CDS (Credit Default Swaps) to insure themselves against the failure of CDO's. Even speculators could buy CDS to insure CDO's which they didn't own. This system was tricking time bomb in the financial system. Rating agencies had no liabilities , if their highly rated invetments went burst. PART II: THE BUBBLE (2001 - 2007) US $100 billion dollars were lended as sub prime loans. So anybody could easily get credit for buying a new house. 99.3% of the house price were given as loans to the borrowers. So when the borrowers could not pay their EMI's, they walked away resulting in foreclosures. Country Wide Financial Corp was the largest sub prime lender in the US and lended close to US $100 billion dollars. During 2003 - 2008, traders and CEO's became enormously wealthy. Investment banks preferred sub prime loans because they carried higher interest rates. This led to massive increase in predatory lending. During bubble, investment banks borrowed heavily to buy more loans create more CDOs. on April 28, 2004 SEC lifted leverage limits on the investment banks. In Raghuram . G . Rajan, former Chief Economist (IMF) published the paper titled " Has financial improvements made the world riskier. Goldman Sachs sold more than US $3 billion dollars of toxic assets to the investors. They also bet on these toxic assets by buysing CDS from AIG, by this way they were actually piling risks onto the AIG's books. Predicting the collapse of AIG itself, they spent US $150 million dollars in protecting their CDS against the potential collapse of AIG. The logic was that if their investors lost more money, Goldman Sachs would gain more profits. Morgan Stanley was betting that their entire investments would fail. PART III: THE CRISIS The securitization of food chain happened. The link was connected as follows: Borrowers --Lenders--Investment Banks --Investors (Retail, Corporates, Institutions, Pension Funds, etc.) As the links passed on from one stage to another, the magnitude of risk in the chain grew exponentially. In September 2008, Lehman Brothers was taken over by Bank of America. On September 16,2008 5000 people belonging to the London office of Lehman Brothers lost their jobs. Also the Commercial Paper Markets collapsed. They are used by companies for operating expenses such as payroll. Foreclosures rose to 6 million by the year 2010. People in US started living in tents. PART IV: ACCOUNTABILITY Most of the people and institutions involved in the crisis went Scot free. SEC, CFTC Federal Reserve Board which were in charge of regulating the investment banks and other associated institutions failed in their duties. Top executives of the insolvent companies walked away with their private properties intact. For most of the period from 1990 - 2010, Academicians played a key role in shaping the financial regulatory policies and banking practices. Some people had conflict of interest due to their presence as consultant in investment banks. PART V: WHERE ARE WE NOW? (note: year 2010) Tens of thousands of US workers lost their jobs. European Union imposed stricter banking regulations. Most of the investment banks had to pay penalties running into millions of dollars. Merrill Lynch and Countrywide Financial Corp gets eventually taken over by Bank of America. Financial Institutions  Write-Downs Citigroup (USA) - $24.1 bln Merrill Lynch (USA) - $22.5 bln UBS AG (Switzerland) - $16.7 bln Morgan Stanley (USA) - $10.3 Credit Agricole (France) - $4.8 bln HSBC (United Kingdom) - $3.4 bln Bank of America (USA) - $5.28 bln CIBC (Canada)  $3.2 bln Deutsche Bank (Germany) - $3.1 bln Total Write downs and losses were around $300 - $350 billion US dollars. Global Impacts of the Crisis: 1)Investors lost confidence in the stock market. 2)Consumer spending slowed down due to lack of cash/ unwillingness. 3)U.S.As economic condition affected the global economy. 4)World economy slipped into recession. 5)Exports from China, Korea, Taiwan and India decreased. Impact on India: 1)FIIs pulled out of money from the Indian stock market 2)Public Sector Banks, viz State Bank Of India, Bank Of Baroda, Canara Bank, Punjab National Bank etc did not have major exposure to credit derivatives market due to their limited overseas operations. 3)Stock market Crashed and BSE sensex crashed from 24000 level to 8000 level. 4)ICICI Bank incurred a loss of close to Rs.1000 Crores because of exposure to international securities market CLIMAX: There is a sufficiency in the world for man's need but not for man's greed. BOTTOM LINE: The story of economic crisis of 2008 has been explained in an elegant manner with no glitches. Charles Ferguson has once again proved his mettle with the representational skills. A movie worth watching and I would personally rate it as 9/10. ]] Click the link given below to view the PDF on Slideshare http://www.slideshare.net/valliappan1991/inside-job-movie-review-the-story-of-global-recession-2008 This document clearly narrates the events that led to the economic crisis of 2008 resulting in a global recession. In 2008, many global banks collapsed and had to be bailed out by the US government. ]] Source: Forbes It doesnt matter what you do or where you work  everyone is looking for ways to be more productive on the job. But excessive amounts of caffeine and list-making wont get you any closer to reaching peak productivity levels today. So, why are we all so obsessed with productivity? Its probably because in this digital age, staying on task and avoiding distraction is harder to accomplish than your actual work. Not to mention the feeling of a productive workday is somewhat euphoric. This search for a more productive workday has led to a certain misconception about what productivity really is  and its a lot more than checking tasks off your to-do list. Truly productive people arent focused on doing more things; this is actually the opposite of productivity. If you really want to be productive, youve got to make a point to do fewer things. To find out the secret to a more productive workday, I spoke with project management and productivity expert Tony Wong . He provided me with some excellent insight into what he and other like-minded individuals do during their work week. Make room for increased productivity by putting these habits into play: 1. Cut your to-do list in half. Getting things done during your workday shouldnt mean fitting in doing as much as possible in the sanctioned eight hours. Do you really need those 30 tasks on your to-do list? Take a less-is-more approach to your to-do list by only focusing on accomplishing things that matter. 2. Take more breaks. The ache in your brain after several long hours of work should be your signal to take a break. Since your brain has used up its glucose, give yourself a moment to refresh by going for a walk, grabbing lunch or a snack, or just meditating. Youll come back recharged and ready to achieve greater efficiency. 3. Follow the 80/20 rule. Only 20 percent of what you do each day produces 80 percent of your results. Eliminate the things that dont matter during your workday  they have a minimal effect on your overall productivity. For example, break your next project down into steps and systematically remove tasks until you end up with the 20 percent that gets the 80 percent of results. 4. Use your morning to focus on yourself. Its a big productivity killer to start your mornings by checking your email and your calendar. This allows others to dictate what you accomplish. Start your day out right by ignoring your emails in the morning and getting in a good breakfast, reading the news, meditating, or working out. This will ensure youve got the necessary fuel for a productive day. 5. Tackle your challenging tasks before lunch. Knock out your most challenging work when your brain is fresh. If you have any busy work or meetings, save them for the afternoon. By scheduling your day this way, youll be able to create a new and more productive way to manage your time. 6. Improve your email etiquette. Email is a productivity killer and usually a distraction from tasks that actually matterdont fall into this productivity trap. For example, people often copy multiple people on emails to get it off their plate, but this is a sign of laziness and actually distracts everyone else by creating noise against the tasks theyre trying to accomplish. As a rule, if you receive an email where many people are CCd, do everyone a favor by BCCing them on your reply. If your email chain goes beyond two replies, its time to pick up the phone. 7. Create a system. Youve probably developed a few productivity-ruining habits over the years. Manage your distracting ways by creating a system. For those of you who check your emails compulsively, plan a morning, afternoon, and evening time slot to manage your inbox. Otherwise, youll get distracted from accomplishing more important goals throughout the day. 8. Stop confusing productivity with laziness. While no one likes admitting it, sheer laziness is the No. 1 contributor to lost productivity. In fact, a number of so-called time-saving methods  take meetings and emails for example  are actually just ways to get out of doing real work. Place your focus on doing the things that matter most as efficiently and effectively as possible. 9. Stop multi-tasking. Stop trying to do 10 things at once! Changing tasks more than 10 times a day drops your IQ an average of 10 points. Get things done more effectively and efficiently by focusing on one task at a time. Less is more when it comes to being productive during the workday. Stick to the basics for reaching productivity. ]] (function(d, s, id) { var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0]; if (d.getElementById(id)) return; js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id; js.src = "//connect.facebook.net/en_GB/all.js#xfbml=1"; fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, fjs); }(document, 'script', 'facebook-jssdk')); Post by School of Management - NIT Warangal . ]] 1) 70% of employers have rejected a job candidate because of information they found about that person online. 2) 85% of employers say that a positive online reputation influences their hiring decisions. Source: Linked In Click the link given below to download the two presentations created by the Linked In company. http://goo.gl/op8SCj File Size: 38 MB (approx) Example of best profile: http://www.linkedin.com/in/kruller ---------------------------------------------------------------- Valliappan P MBA, Class of (2012-2014), School of Management, NIT- Warangal 09603722578 | 09092984219 ]] 1) https://www.myuniverse.co.in (Aditya Birla Group) Key Use: Helps in tracking your personal finance, managing investment portfolios and keep track of your personal budgets This site helps you keep track of your income, expenses, investments, fixed deposits, insurance, mutual funds, credit card bills,etc. Ex: If you enter your HDFC Bank Internet Banking User ID and Password in this site, that bank account will get linked to your MyUniverse ID.Actually the above mentioned site is too good that you can't ignore it, provided you become a premium member, by paying Rs.500 / per year (*Unlimited no. of accounts can be added and tracked). Basic version is free (*only two accounts can be added) Only transactions will be displayed for analysis purpose and no one can transfer money. Its highly secure and uses RC4 128 bit encryption. The security protocol used here are SSL and TLS 1.1 Its also accessible in Android phones. 2) www.perfios.com 3) www.arthayantra.com " Take control of your money even on the go " Valliappan P MBA, Class of (2012-2014), School of Management, NIT- Warangal 09603722578 | 09092984219 ]] Corporate Banking role Treasury Banking role Front End Investment Banking Debt Equity Market Front End Investment Banking (Middle office, operations, IT and support) Private Equity (PE) Venture Capital Firms Debt Equity Markets (Research, Middle Office, Operations, IT Support) Hedge Funds and Investment Management Private Banking wealth Management Bank  PO / Asst. Manager (Public sector and private sector banks in India) Financial Analyst Equity Analyst Business Analyst Brand Manager Sales Manager Business Consultant E  Commerce Advertising Media Corporate Finance Business development Financial Manager in FMCG also in other manufacturing industries Market Research General Management / Strategy Consumer Products CFA / ICWA / CA POSTS AUDITING ---------------------------------------------------------------- Regards, Valliappan P MBA, Class of (2012-2014), School of Management, NIT- Warangal 09603722578 | 09092984219 ]] It took me 6 long hours to launch my website. Had to change the CNAME records, host server, DNS mapping, search engine indexing, etc. ]] Starting from a simple loan, credit markets have featured many innovations as well as costly crises. 1. Loans: Credit appears to go back to the early days of the written record. Often, loans have been made only if the borrower could provide some collateral, like a house. Over thousands of years, basic loans have proliferated and developed into new forms, like credit cards and peer-to-peer lending. 2. Bonds: Until bonds, most loans were made by a single lender. As bonds evolved, they allowed multiple lenders to pool their money to provide a single loan, making it easier to attract more lenders. The greater distance between borrowers and lenders made it easier for bad loans to slip through and has distributed risk more broadly through society. 3. Securitisation: Banks bundle, or securitise, a large number of similar loans  often mortgages  which serve as collateral for a bond issued to investors. Securitisation exploded as banks saw a way to get rid of risk and attract new sources of funding. Most securitisations are sliced up so that some investors can take more risk than others for a higher payout. This goes wrong when investors underestimate the risks of underlying loans. 4. Derivatives: Until recently, the world of debt consisted largely of loans and bonds. Today, credit markets are also dominated by derivatives, which are tradeable instruments that derive their value from some other asset, like a bond, allowing investors to bet on the movement of that asset. ]] "Imagine a world in which every single person on the planet is given free access to the sum of all human knowledge. That's what we're doing." - Jimmy Wales (wikipedia founder) ]] Azim Premji may buy #Myntra stake for Rs 300 crore. In the last 3 years, Indian e-commerce has witnessed a 150% growth rate. #Fashion is one of the largest categories in Indian e-commerce and a leader there, will find backers. ]] It's the age of "click and find", but there is no replacement for the human brain as a learning tool. ]] Tweets by @nitw_cura !function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+"://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js";fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document,"script","twitter-wjs"); ]] 