 As you can see from the screen capture above, here is a detention basin with a high water elevation of 176.  Now we need to create a feature line that represent the location of our spillway.  It is important that this feature line is in a different site from the detention basin, that way it will not react with the pond grading. In the capture above, you can see that an elevated feature line representing the spillway has been created.  We will then create a grading group for the spillway, and use the grade to surface method and target the proposed detention basin. In the two screen captures above, you can feature line has created the spillway,  The bottom capture shows the spillway in a 3d perspective.  It is important to note, that the infill option needs to be used to close the bottom of the spillway.  Also, if for some reason the spillway needs to change location, we simply move it to its new area, and the spillway will be updated. Finally, now that the spillway and detention basin are created, we simply need to make a new surface and paste both surfaces together. ]] The command give the user the ability to change the level of detail on a surface based on the zoom distance. What this means is that the more zoomed out, the more simplified the surface will be, and conversely the closer you are, the more detailed. When you start the command the first time, the capture above will let you know that you have entered detail mode.  The image below show the icon that will appear in the top left corner of model space once the command has been invoked. This command, which was added into the 2012 product, will make dealing with large surfaces much improved. ]] The first thing that we need to do is convert the Civil 3D points to standard blocks with attributes.  To accomplish this, I will use the AeccConvertPointsToSdskPoints command.  As you can see below, we now have point blocks.  Before I convert the data into shp format, I will get rid of the Civil 3D points in the drawing now that we have blocks. To convert the block data into a usable shp format, we can use the mapexport command. After selecting the file name and shp file format, we will select point for object type. We will next flip to the data tab, and choose the select attributes option. Here is where we can select what attributes we want to be stored in the shp file.  In our case, we will select elev, point, and desc. Now that the file has been created, we can send this to our client our local municipality for their use.  To give an idea of what you will be sending, I will bring the file into Civil 3D using the data connect to bring in the shp file. As you see in the capture below, I have chosen to add the shp connection and selected the shp file previously created. After connecting and adding to map the shp file, you can see the following. I will then choose the table option to display the data that was generated in the shp file. Here is the table with the corresponding data we chose to export with the shp file.  This is what others who plan on using this shp file in other programs should see. ]] As you can see from the screen capture above, the line is elevated as we would expect.  Now the user has two options.  The first option we will look at is in the point style. As you can see in the capture above, we can simply set the point display mode to flatten points to elevation, and set the elevation to zero.  It is important to note that this setting will have no impact on the creation of a surface using these points.  The second option is to set the osnapz variable to 1.  By setting the variable to 1, osnap substitutes the z value of the specified point to the value of the current UCS.  It is worth mentioning that Civil 3D does not save this variable, and thus why it defaults back to 0 each time you open the software.  The only way that I can see to permanently change this would be to add the following line of code to the acaddoc.lsp file. ]] Autodesk Labs has released an update for Project Chronicle .  For those of you not familiar with this tool, Project Chronicle is a technology preview that makes it easy for users to share and capture software workflows.  The utility consists of two main components.  The first component is the recording utility.  It allows the user capture worflow from either Revit or AutoCAD based software.  The utility records a continuous video with optional narration.  Some cool features of chronicle are that it is also is recording the timeline and details of the workflow, such as the commands used to create the objects or data.  The second component is the web site.  After capturing the data, it is uploaded to the Project Chronicle website where other users can view the videos, along with the timeline and other recorded components.  It is important to note that viewing can be made public, or can be restricted to a specif user or users.  Your chronicles can also be shared to such public media sites as Facebook or Twitter. ]] Civil 3D 2013 Service Pack 1..  Autodesk has released this service pack to address a variety of issues discovered by users and Autodesk personnel. As always, please take a look at the readme file prior to installation.  It is also important to note that you cannot run an automatic uninstall to remove this update.  You will need to do an uninstall and re install to restore your version of the software. ]] When laying out Assemblies sometimes the overall look can wrong, some subassemblies will even include a label Layout Mode to let you know that when processed in a corridor will look right. Assemblies are building blocks to build a corridor, and are NOT intended to be plotted, we have Standard Details Sheets for that. . Ive notice this behavior in the Generic Link to Marked Point and some Medians. Looking at a MEDIAN assembly, this one is closing the gap from Left to Right hooking to the MarkedPoint (triangle), with positive grades crowning upward. When built in the corridor and placed in the cross section, the positive grades. Now using the same subassembly on the other side of the median, closing the gap from Right to Left. This time we will hooked to the MarkedPoint (triangle) will cause the subassembly to flip. Because the median subassembly had to flip to connect, the original positive grades are now inverted too. ]] Lets talk about 3 options to get create a Depth Profile in Civil 3D: First Option: Creating a copy of the EG surface profile it will be and exact match. We will then drop the copy the needed amount. However if the Alignment path were to change or Surface was to be edited the copy would NOT be up-to-date 1. Use the AutoCAD command to copy the EG Profile. 2. Go into Profile Properties dialog box: Rename it, set a different Style and change the Update Mode to Static. 3. Lower it using the Edit Geometry tools Raise/Lower PVI Elevations command. Second Option: Creating a Feature Line from the Alignment and EG Profile that can be Projected and Lowered. 1. From the Ribbons Home Tab Feature Line Create from Alignment. 2. Choose of what profile to follow, Uncheck the Dynamic Link box and option set options to weed out vertices. 3. Next add Feature Line to grid, Select the Profile View from Ribbon Project Objects to Profile View button. 4. Make sure the Use Object is set for elevations in the Dialog Box Options. 5. Lower the Feature Line the Ribbon or Right Click command to Raise/Lower. Third Option: Create a surface with EG pasted into it, NOT just a copy for we want the copied surface to be dynamically tied to the original. The down side here is duplicating a TIN surface will increasing the drawing size. 1. Use the AutoCAD copy command to make a copy of the TIN Surface. 2. From the Properties Rename it and set appropriate Style. 3. Then use the Surface Edit command Raise/Lower to drop the elevation. 4. Sample the new Surface to have it display in Profile View Grid. ]] Ive been thinking about the many different ways to profile a single file or in line survey. Surveys like this are common for a proposed utility run or cross section survey. The need is simple, to profile these field points, but the issue is creating a TIN is just too cumbersome for the lack of supplementing point data. We could add supplementing points manually or copy in parallel, but in this case we will do it without creating a TIN Surface: 1. Draw 2D Polyline that connects the needed sequence of points 2. Create Alignment from Polyline. 3. Create empty Profile View from the Alignment 4. Draw 3D Polyline connecting the needed sequence of points 5. Project 3D Polyline to Profile View. First , start by using the AutoCAD POLYLINE command to connect the needed points. Second , using the CIVIL 3D command, from the Home Tab, to Create Alignment from Objects . Once done with selection you will be prompted for alignment direction and choice to reverse. Then on to the Alignment Creation dialog box, note that the option for Add curves between tangents is left unchecked. Once command is complete, the Alignment and its Labels will appear. Third, Select the created Alignment and from the Ribbon pick on the Profile View button to create an EMPTY grid. From the Create Profile View dialog box, accept the defaults by selecting the Create Profile View button. When prompted select a point on screen to create the empty Grid (this will be the grids lower left corner). Forth, similar to before, using the AutoCAD 3D POLYLINE command to connect the needed points. I found that if I freeze or turn off the display to the previously created Alignment, this will be easier. Fifth , select any point on the Profile View grid, then from the ribbon select the Project Objects to Profile View button. Once in the Project Objects to Profile View dialog box, make sure the option to Use Object elevation is set. This will automatically populate the previously selected Profile View gird with the line. This projected line work is dynamically tied to the original 3D POLYLINE, if it is edited, stretched, trimmed, etc.., its view in the grid will update. ]] 1. Create a TIN Volume Surface 2. Ran am Analysis to User Contour Elevation 0 3. Then Extract the Created User Contour as a Line Start by Creating a New TIN Volume Surface (in this example a POND will be compared against a CROSSING plane) The Volume Surface is calculated from elevation 0, it will appears below the TIN Surfaces. To simplify view set TIN surfaces to No Display, and leave VOLUME Surface on The Volume Surface is shown here using a Tin Points Style. Notice how the Pond hole is filled up. A Surface Analysis to a User Specified Contour needs to be done to find the intersecting boundary. Before running the Analysis, make sure the User Contour component is visible in the used surface style. The color has been changed to RED for it to stand out in Plan View Then the VOLUME Surface Properties dialog box to the Analyses Tab, Select User-defined Contours as the Type. Presses on the Range to 1 and In the Range Detail area set the Elevation value in the row to 0.00 The result should be a POLYLINE marking the location of where the 2 Surfaces intersect. The resulting Boundary Outline can be extracted. By selecting the surface and going to the Contextual Ribbon. From the Tools Panel use the Extract Objects and Uncheck everything except User Contours. The final product is a 2D AutoCAD Polyline, that can be selected and edited. ]] Here is the expression:  IF({Surface Elevation}/2=TRUNC({Surface Elevation})/2), {Surface Elevation}, -1) The expression starts of with the IF command, which tells the expression to check for given output.  The surface elevation/2 is telling the interval at which we want our contours to be displayed.  In this example, we want to label every other contour, but this could  be set to /3, which would check for every third contour, etc.  By using the TRUNC command, we are checking to see if the contour is divide by 2 evenly.  For example, a surface elevation of 102 would generate a value of 51 and a truncated value of 51, where as a surface elevation of 101 would generate a value of 50.5 and a truncated value of 50.  In the example, the surface elevation 102 would be labeled, while 101 would not.  This portion is taken care of by the last part of the expression which is {Surface Elevation}, -1.  If the statement is true, then it uses the surface elevation, if not it generates a -1 value for a false statement. The reason we are having the statement generate a negative value is that the label style composer, as seen above, the Sign option allows us to hide negative values.  Note, in my expression, I'm having a false statement generate a value of -1, but in theory, it could be any number as long as it is negative.  This is ultimately how we can have Civil 3D label contours at a given interval. Here is what your new label should look like.  Why spend anymore time then needed to quickly label your contours. ]] Now with the blank template as the current drawing, I only need to edit the drawing settings of the other template/drawing that has the object layers assigned.  I then select the object layers tab and simply hit OK. As you can see from the screen capture below, the object layers have been transferred to the blank template. The second trick I like to use is to have three predefined pipe networks all ready created within the template, which you can see in the following screen capture. It is important to note that these networks are networks in name only, and they don't currently contain pipes or structures.  Now what they do contain are object layers, like you can see in the capture below. By having the networks predefined, the user doesn't have to set these layers when they start the pipe network creation process.  All the user needs to do is edit the appropriate network, and start laying out pipe. ]] As you can see from the screen capture above, once you select reference text from the label style composer, you will be given an option to choose what type of object you would like to make reference text for.  In my example, I will be choosing alignment. In the capture above, you can see that I have added a reference text component called reference text.1.  I will rename this to something logical like second alignment station.  From this point on, we create the component like we normally would, and anchor the label.  In my label, you can see that I have anchored the label to the outgoing pipes, with it being displayed as ???. Now that I have chosen the label that I created and selected the manhole, you notice that I have a pick box and some instructions on the command line asking me to select the second alignment.  I can now pick the appropriate alignment, or right click and I will be given the option to choose the alignment from the list. Once I have chosen the appropriate alignment, you should see the question marks change to a station and offset value like the one seen below. It is important to note that reference text component allows the user to change from one alignment to another.  If you look at the label in the AutoCAD properties box, you will note the reference text option at the top. From within here, the user can select different alignments or components depending on the object created in the label.  If you hit the green box, you will be given the option to again select another alignment  .A great example where this can be utilized is when labeling a proposed surface. How often do we build multiple proposed surfaces to give the client various options of how the site can be graded.  A typical surface label is tied to the surface that we select when labeling, whereas a reference text label allows the user to use the same label, but change the surface it is getting the values from. As you can see from the example label I created, the value of the reference text allows us to do multiple  labels within one label, or change randomly from object to object. ]] As you can see from the screen capture, it looks more like a hex nut  rather than a pipe.  The cause of this is a system variable called FACETDEV.  The default value for the variable is set to .5 feet.  This variable works very similar to how the mid ordinate distance does for contours.  Civil 3D is drawing small line segments to represent the circular pipe.  If you change the variable to say .01, you end up with what you see below. This is probably what most of you would expect to see.  I would like to point out that this variable will hold if changed in your corporate template, meaning you should only need to change this once.  Lastly, you may notice some drawing performance depending on how low you set the value, so you may need to play with it to get the right balance between performance and display. ]] In order to get around this, we can go into our code set style and add some additional link codes that we will assign to just the links we wish to label. Once we are editing the code set style, we can right click on links, and hit add.  Here we can add a link code for such things as foreslope, ditch, etc.  These additional codes will allow us to specifically assign them to certain links.  After selecting add, it will ask for the link style witch isn't important. After selecting the link style, you will notice that it makes a new link code named new code.  We can rename this to Ditch, or whatever additional feature we wish to label.  Here we can also assign an appropriate label style to label elevation, slope, or whatever data we wish to convey. The following screen capture depicts what the new code set style should look like after creating the additional codes with an appropriate label style. Now that we have created the two additional link codes, we can go into the subassembly properties of the two individual links. From the parameters tab, we simply go to the link codes, put in a coma, and add the appropriate code we just created, in this instance we would add ditch.  It is important that we spell the code to match exactly with the code created, upper or lower case does matter. We can do the same for the foreslope as well.  Here is what the subassemblies look like. This process will save time on labeling, and these styles can ultimately be added to the corporate template for  others to use. ]] Autodesk products, the user's guide pops up with content, index, and search options for the specific software. After spending some time searching for a solution, I simply went back to an older version, in this case Civil 3D 2012, copied the following file, and overwrote the same one in Civil 3D 2013. C:ProgramFilesAutodeskAutoCAD Civil 3D 2012HHAppsHydrographs.chm The hep content now works as expected.  The file in 2013 must be corrupt.  If you do not have access to a previous version of the software, please let me know and I would be happy to send the file. ]] While teaching recently a Civil 3D 2013 class we came upon an interesting dilemma with Corridor Surfaces.  When trying to constrain a Corridor surface using the corridor itself is now always presented as an option by default.  It may not always be to our advantage. The issue is evident when the a subbase extends further out than the proposed TOP surface.  When trying to constrain the proposed TOP surface with the Corridor Extents, the surface will go further out than the Daylight. The fix here is to constrain the surface using Add Automatically using Daylight or Add From a Polygon. ]] Autodesk released the Geotechnical module for subscription customers.  It can be found under the Productivity Tools for AutoCAD Civil 3D 2013. It is important to note that installation of SQL server as well.  After installing the module, you will see the following addition to the ribbon. To begin the process of importing soil boring data, we will select import.  Before we can import any boring data, a drawing will need to exist, which means it must be saved. The import data box allows us to select the appropriate files to be imported.  I'm bringing in data via csv.  There are also options to import data via AGS 4 and AGS 3.1.  Here is a link to AGS that discuses in further detail the formatting and group headings.  Since I have chosen a csv file type, I will be importing to files HOLE.csv and GEOL.csv.  It is important to note that in this version of the module, the csv files must be named exactly as I stated, including case sensitivity.  Samples of these files can be found at Keynetix , along with sample tutorials for using this module. After selecting import, your boring data will be brought into your drawing.  As you can see from the screen capture, the borings are brought in with an x,y, and z location.  Note in the view on the right, the borings are broken down into various stratum. From the Borehole Manager tab, when can select which borings we will like to include, along with assigning an appropriate style for the type of boring as seen below. From the Strata Manager, we can select which surfaces we would like the module to create within Civil 3D. The Hatch Manager allows the user to assign various colors and hatch patterns to an array of soil boring materials. Finally, the Create options allows the user to add the soil borings to profile view for a given alignment. The borehole selection screen allows the user to choose which borings will be added to the profile view. Now simply select create, and the soil boring data is added to the profile view. ]] AutoCAD Civil 3D 2014 has been released to the masses.  I will try to summarize the list of new features that have been added or enhanced in this years version.  A good place to start as always is the help files. Pressure Pipe Enhancements Create Network from Objects Can be added to cross section views Can have assigned pay items in the Parts List Can be used via the data shortcut Sort parts lists by size New annotation options Can be added to plan production sheets Extract Corridor Solids Data references are saved in the drawing Improved interoperability with InfraWorks (Otherwise known as AIM) Survey Queries Import and Export One of the more interesting features in Civil 3D 2014 is its backward compatibility with Civil 3D 2013.  This means that 2014 files can be opened and edited in 2013.  However, there are some limitations due to enhancements in 2014.  The screen capture below talks about the limitations.  This can also be found in the following link Round-Tripping Data between versions . Lastly, here is the new logo for Autodesk going forward. ]] Civil 3D 2014, Autodesk has introduced a live map service to acquire satellite images.  In order to to use this service, the user first needs to log into Autodesk 360 , and have a coordinate system assigned to the drawing.  After logging in, the user simply needs to type GEOMAP on the command line. The user is presented with several choices.  The first choice is Aerial. The second choice is Road. The third choice is Hybrid.  This is a combination of Aerial and Road. Lastly, the user can simply select off to hide the imagery. ]] Autodesk has announced a new certification program that is based on a workflow.  The certification is called Roads and Highways Workflows using the 2014 Infrastructure Design suite. Autodesk has been certifying users on individual products for quite some time, but this is something new.  The exam itself is broken down into the following topics: Project Planning Preliminary Design Detailed Design Visual Communication The following are a sample of some of the objectives that may be tested during the certification exam: Create a storyboard Select a road style Create a proposal Import the .imx file into Civil 3D Create the initial corridor Preform clash detection Calculate cut/fill Render Images Here is where you can find a complete list of objectives for the exam.  The exam will focus on such programs  as Civil 3D, Navisworks, 3Ds Max and various other products. A book has been created by Ascent which matches the name of the certification and can be used for preparing for the exam. Information for taking an exam at one of our facilities can be found at the following Advanced Solutions link. ]] Autodesk Subscription Site, under the productivity tools for AutoCAD Civil 3D 2014, you will find the Shared Reference Point Tool.  There is an installer for Civil 3D, which runs from the Toolbox, and then a second installer to run on Revit . The extension exports an XML from Civil 3D with X,Y, and Z coordinates, along with the corresponding rotation and units.  This reference point defines the relationship between the site and building. ]] Autodesk has released Hotfix 1 for Autodesk AutoCAD Civil 3D 2014 which addresses a number of various issues found by customers and Autodesk.  As always, you should take a look at the read me file prior to installation.  It is important to note, that this Hotfix can be uninstalled from the control panel. ]] The only thing constant in life is change! - Francois de La Rochefoucauld This statement being true, we are moving the ITS NOT JUST DIRT blog to a new site. Were joining forces with other industry leaders to create a one stop shop for all things technological in nature. The new site will include posts by other authors within the building, infrastructure and manufacturing industries, as well as a New technical support blog. We would like to encourage you to follow us at http://blog.advancedsolutions.com/ for all of the up-to-the-minute posts, latest trends in technology and fun facts. You only have until September 3 rd before ITS NOT JUST DIRT will become obsolete.  Follow us today at http://blog.advancedsolutions.com/ Cheers, Rob, Leo Kevin ]] 