 A few months ago...Luz came to me to design a unique invitation for her wedding. I was very honored! She wanted a unique and classic invite with a happy cinnamon color. The result was very elegant and unique. She was very happy with the collection. I love the look of excitement in the brides' eye when they see their invites for the first time.]] A client of mine approached me with a great concept for their logo for their delicious roasted corn business. He had the idea which I took and ran with to create this fun logo. Hot Cob now uses this for all their merchandising opportunities. ]] Just wanted to share a promotional video of things we have done in case anyone is in need of a good design company to assist them in their business ventures.]] I just wanted to thank a client of mine for trusting me in designing their line of wine. Carpenter Hill Vineyard asked us to design a couple of their wine labels. They wanted to upgrade their existing label to a more sophisticated, yet approachable label. Hopefully we get a chance to design their website :) http://www.carpenterhillvineyard.com/Wines.htm ]] Smile Design Inc. is now Twittering! Watch out world! http://twitter.com/ SmileDesignInk ]] We wanted to share a company that has unique baby, pet, and people products. We have been designing and branding ORE Originals for almost 9 years now. They have great products for everyone....check their website at: www.oreoreginals.com You won't be disappointed! ]] Coming soon to a store near you...Just finished another wine label for Red Blanket a sister product of Red Lily. Thanks Les for trusting us to do your wine labels.]] Capella Technologies gave us a fun project to work on this week. They needed to create bike jersey for the CapellaTechTeam riders for the Century 100K and Half Century 50K Ride. Here is one of the comp that we presented and was selected. The team is going to look good and will proudly present their company.]] Fascinating video about the Social Media Revolution. Can this thing called Social Media be a fad? What do you think?]] Need a customized invitations for your special event? Whether it is a corporate event, a special birthday, or even your wedding, Alluration is the best at captivating your audience. Starting out as a hobby, Alluration has created numerous memorable materials for friends, family, and corporate events who needed that customized touch specifically for your special event. Check out Alluration at www.alluration.com]] Just wanted to share. Ever look for a company through your mobile phone and you see a blue box with an empty image. I was that company a few months ago...my website was not compatible with any mobile devices and really didn't know what to do about it. Thanks to Thirdoor (http://www.thirdoor.com), a company that offered to bring my site up to date with today's most useful device...our mobile smart phones.I think they did a great job, considering the space limitations of a mobile phone. Check it out and let me know what you think! Thanks :)]] Alluration is proud to introduce the final wedding invitation for Raina Carlos.They came to Alluration for a memorable and unique invitation...Damask was the theme with a hint of red. Getting the right feel of the invite is usually the main concern of the bride groom. People have an impression that quality means more expensive. Alluration worked with RC to get a customized invitation without going over budget. They wanted to create an elegant sophisticated piece that would spark the whole feel of the night. Congratulations RC!!!]] Alluration wanted to feature another successful invitation package we created for Lisa Fedinand. Plumb Gold were the colors chosen. Liza wanted something lavish, rich, yet simple. Simple elegance is a hard thing to pull off, but I think Alluration gave the couple exactly what they wished for. The invitation and wedding materials were applied to many other pieces in their wedding and provided a cohesive look feel for the whole night.]] Just for fun, if Alluration had a chance to redesign the Royal Wedding materials...This is probably what I would come up with. Don't mean to downgrade the royal designer, but the cover of that programme was so boring. Here's our take on it if we were to design the programme cover.]] Wanted to share Smile Design, Inc.'s contribution to a new movement by Manny Pacquiao and his "Fight the Fight Against Poverty"Campaign. We were asked to create a logo mark that represented the foundations movement to end poverty. The "M" in the center is created with a yellow ribbon (the official color of Manny's movement) and has two P Letters on both side of the ribbon creating the letter M. The two P's symbolizing the two sides of the fighthis fight in the ring and his fight to end poverty. Eight stars are represented in the logo for his eight titles and the circular shape symbolizes his global connection. The rays of the Philippine flag and sun is represented to signify his roots. The logo is now featured in the official website of Manny Pacquiao www.mp8.ph Products featuring the logo will be sold worldwide in the near future to help Manny Pacquiao's Foundation to help poverty in the Philippines. Please check out and support the movement! ]] A preview of a mobile site we are doing for Capella Technologies which compliments the newly re-designed website. ]] 