 http://hbr.org/2013/09/understand-the-perils-of-co-creation/ar/1 The rise of social media has generated tremendous opportunities for companies to engage with customers. Many allow customers to participate in value-creating activities, such as brainstorming advertising taglines or product ideasa process often referred to as co-creation. These activities not only help companies innovate at low cost but also engage customersevery marketers dream. In practice, however, these programs are hard to run. Some customers hijack theminstead of offering real ideas, they seize the chance to ridicule the company. Such hijacking is one of the biggest challenges companies face. Prior research suggests that about half of co-creation campaigns fail. Consider Henkel, a large German manufacturer of detergent and other products. It ran a contest in which customers could submit innovative packaging suggestionsand was deluged with negative ideas. (One was a label describing the detergent as Yummi Chicken Flavor.) General Motors invited customers to tweak its advertisements, resulting in a rash of ads criticizing its SUVs as gas-guzzlers that contribute to global warming. McDonalds set up a Twitter campaign to promote positive word of mouth, but the effort became a platform for consumers looking to bash the chain (see examples below). When Tweets Attack When Tweets Attack McDonalds introduced the hashtag #McDStories, hoping to attract heartwarming, upbeat posts. Oops... Managers considering co-creation initiatives should think carefully about the risks. Our research identifies three areas of particular concern: Strong brand reputation. Firms with strong brands need to protect themthey have a lot to lose. They must be aware that these initiatives give customers opportunities to tarnish the brand. Strong brand reputations are generally built through consistent, effective marketing, and companies should weigh the potential for misbehaving customers to undo their careful efforts. High demand uncertainty. Companies are more likely to ask for customer input when market conditions are shifting. But this frequently backfires when demand is highly uncertain, because customers in fast-changing markets often dont know what they want or what theyll like. Porsche got lots of negative feedback when it announced plans to release an SUV, but it proceeded anyway, and the Porsche Cayenne was a great success. Too many initiatives. Companies ordinarily benefit from working repeatedly with the same suppliers, but that doesnt hold when the suppliers are customers. Experience shows that the quality, quantity, and variety of input decrease as the frequency of engagement increases. A study of the Dell IdeaStorm program (in which customers were invited to submit product or service ideas) found that people submitted ideas repeatedlyincluding many for things the company was already offering. And customers whose ideas were implemented tended to return with additional ones that were quite similar to their first suggestions. This isnt to say that firms should never try to crowdsource value creation in an attempt to engage customers. It can be a viable strategybut managers must understand the high probability of misbehavior. They need to monitor engagement activities continuously and intervene if customers begin offering too much comedy and too few genuine ideas. Peter C. Verhoef is a professor, Jenny van Doorn is an associate professor, and Sander F.M. Beckers is a PhD student, at the University of Groningen, in the Netherlands. ]] http://lnkd.in/bdDGMnp via LinkedIn]] http://lnkd.in/bAUgPQK via LinkedIn]] http://lnkd.in/bpy24tM via LinkedIn]] http://lnkd.in/bHEtJJU via LinkedIn]] http://lnkd.in/b9Tuheq via LinkedIn]] http://lnkd.in/bqXDpJr via LinkedIn]] A tale of two drugs. Why drugs are so expensive...!!! http://t.co/H57LUZbCQj  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) November 16, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth November 16, 2013 at 11:17AM via IFTTT ]] Analytics 3.0 Tom davenport article in hbr. http://t.co/jpmcOhZSph  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) November 21, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth November 20, 2013 at 05:36PM via IFTTT ]] Data scientist still the sexiest profession alive !!! http://t.co/WHT8xMcfXb  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) November 22, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth November 22, 2013 at 06:21AM via IFTTT ]] Deep learning @google http://t.co/fh1vqheJQl  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) November 17, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth November 17, 2013 at 11:02AM via IFTTT ]] Open data: Unlocking innovation and performance with liquid information @McKinsey_MGI http://t.co/RXFGuAqIJh  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) November 15, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth November 15, 2013 at 07:58AM via IFTTT ]] Elon Musk's Secret Weapon: A Beginner's Guide to First Principles - Microlancer Blog http://t.co/DDPLpFzNjB  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) November 15, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth November 15, 2013 at 08:14AM via IFTTT ]] A quick synthesis of Mu sigma decision sciences summit (oct 24-25 2013@ Chicago ) http://t.co/C1emRnuxA8  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) November 15, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth November 15, 2013 at 07:54AM via IFTTT ]] Jawbone up... Now ...connects you to the internet of things, http://t.co/T5xC4nnnhG  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) November 16, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth November 16, 2013 at 11:31AM via IFTTT ]] Design thinking ( musk/ jobs) http://t.co/U9APTdqyma  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) December 4, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth December 04, 2013 at 09:04AM via IFTTT ]] Tablets usage for e commerce. http://t.co/SMXFEvIZqa  Gopi Vikranth (@GopiVikranth) December 6, 2013 &lt;br /&gt; from Twitter https://twitter.com/GopiVikranth December 05, 2013 at 08:30PM via IFTTT ]] Currently Reading: How to create a mind Bauchelin and Korbal broach (Steven Erikson, vol 1) Matter Non Fic The Black Swan Anti Fragile Team of Rivals David and Goliath Fiction: Books of south: Tales of black company Game of thrones: Dance with dragons Lost Symbol Inferno Words of radiance Elantris ]] 