 The new scentsation in search Coming to your senses: go beyond type, talk, and touch for a new notation of sensation. Your internet sommelier: expertly curated Knowledge Panels pair images, descriptions, and aromas. Take a wiff: the Google Aromabase - 15M+ scentibytes. Don't ask, don't smell: For when you're wary of your query - SafeSearch included. On the same shelf : April Fools: YouTube shut down, Google adds smells Complete list of smells in Google Nose ? - Stack Overflow Observation Deck: Why I Want a Google Nose By Adam Rogers Round Up: All of Google's Jokes for April Fools' 2013 -- from Google Maps treasure hunting to YouTube closing Google Nose Hacks Google launches new search: Nose -- adverblog.com/ ]] Brian Mathews Extract: wanted to share an interesting observation. I hosted an exercise reviewing a wide variety of service spacesbanks, hotels, trade shows, retail, etc and we considered the visual cues of those different environments. Whats the visual cue here? One of the slides featured a jewelry store. Whats the visual cue here? Browsing ! Maybe you know what you want and can point right to it. Or maybe youre not sure and prefer to try several options. The point is that the items are in full view. This is a perfect solution for a growing development at our circulation desk.  Weve recently started lending a handful of adaptors to accommodate SCALE-UP , media:scape , and other technology needs. Instead of keeping them locked away in a backroom it seems we could emulate the jewelry store experience by showcasing them. The expert user can point right to the item she needs, while the novice can try on different adaptors to find the right fit. Its good for users, but also helpful for library staff may not understand the complexity of all the hardware and related accessories. Continue reading ]] Diff Displays computer system knows when you are distracted (although you are in the office, anyways), in other words: Big Brother computer system knows when you're zoning out @ now.msn.com -- or here (via: www.dailymail.co.uk ) Would that tweet get you fired? Just ask FireMe! Workplace Infographics Boss Infographics Creating Workplace Relationship Harmony | visualizationworks.com The Workplace Insider: The Bad Boss Diaries | Visual.ly Visualization of the Week : Identify your insiders, outsiders and gateways, WolframAlpha's updated Facebook tool visualizes your network (and makes outliers obvious). Behind the Boss: A Peek at Company Leaders' Personal Style ]] Walls dont lie @ Livemint K.G. Subramanyans new mural is remarkable in scale and visionand for what it says about the mural as an art form. By Sanjukta Sharma Extract: "In K.G. Subramanyans spectacular new mural, War of the Relics , the invader faces the invaded and the victorious face the defeated in a deadpan dialectic. The 9ft-high, 36ft-wide work spread across the gallerys walls, consisting of 16 panels divided into eight diptychs, is the masters meditation on the futility of violence. Despite its panoptic arcat one end is a scene of rhapsodic horsemen from the Crusades, and at the extreme other end are battle tanks that could well be from 2002s AfghanistanSubramanyans figures, painted in black acrylic and oil on a white background, are undramatic. They represent war in a quiet, non-fussy way..." "Among world cities, the mural thrives as public art in Los Angeles and Philadelphia in the US. In 1987, the Mural Conservancy of Los Angeles (MCLA) was set up to preserve the citys numerous mural wallsall commissioned and painted between the 1950s and 1970s. Many were lost to real estate development. The MCLAs role now is just to preserve what exists. In Philadelphia, in 1984, then mayor Jane Golden initiated what came to be known as the anti-graffiti initiative. She invited the citys graffiti artists, who were working without any patronage, for commissioned works in the citys public sphere. It led to around 2,000 murals. The difference between graffiti and a mural is in its sanction and ownership. Graffiti, the more democratic art, is not commissioned and its purpose is not spelled out. Murals, in that sense, belong to the owner of the space in which it is created, and to the commissioning authority or person..." continue reading On the same shelf : ]] Giving children non-verbal clues about words boosts vocabularies, By William Harms June 24, 2013, UChicago News The clues that parents give toddlers about words can make a big difference in how deep their vocabularies are when they enter school, new research at the University of Chicago shows. By using words to reference objects in the visual environment, parents can help young children learn new words, according to the research. It also explores the difficult-to-measure quality of non-verbal clues to word meaning during interactions between parents and children learning to speak. For example, saying, There goes the zebra while visiting the zoo helps a child learn the word zebra faster than saying, Lets go to see the zebra. - Read more at: UChicago News ]] Extract: Outline Circulating Facebook message warns that, due to the new "Graphic App", material posted on Facebook is no longer private and can be seen by anyone. The message includes instructions for overcoming this supposed problem. Brief Analysis The claims in the message are total nonsense. There is no such thing as a "graphic app". This is apparently a misguided reference to Facebook's new Graph Search functionality. Graph Search does not change existing privacy settings. continue reading: Facebook 'Graphic App' Privacy Warning Hoax ]] Data exploration through visualisation Posted by Ben O'Steen Extract: The impact that a thoughtful visualisation has cannot be underestimated. However, it's easy to forget how tremendously useful they are for understanding your own data, before you even know what you have.... "Textual cross references found in the Bible"  Chris Harrison http://www.chrisharrison.net/index.php/Visualizations/BibleViz The questions "Is there...?" and "What if...?" drive the exploration of data. Often, these questions are best answered by creating something in reply: "This is what it looks like in that context." This can be as simple as creating a chart from a spreadsheet , or pulling out all the key words and phrases and putting them all together on a single page. There are also a number of tools that will take structured data and provide different ways to examine them. Info courtesy:  The British Library`s Digital scholarship blog On the same shelf: Visualizing the holy books ]] Search Engine Journal). In the context of semantic search, a question is worth asking: Is Google as a search engine running out of innovation, visualized through a very slow development of the search techniques (two news stories from the years 2009 and 2013 are below) and what is also seen below as the discussions on the subject? Is this then leading to other competitors, such as TechScour For Internet Publishers , to help search and find what you need when you need???? The answer is awaited. 2013: Google overhauls dictionary as part of project to revolutionise search, Wired UK 2009: " You may have heard that Google is joining the race for the semantic search engine . Semantic search is the capability for a computer to understand what you're searching for based on the meaning behind your words instead of just pulling out keyword-based results. Google is up against a wide range of competitors for the semantic crown including newcomers Kumo , Microsoft's upcoming redesign of Live Search, and Wolfram Alpha -a search engine making some outlandish and unverifiable claims. ... Google is still the same old Google and an excellent first stop for finding information. However, Google is flying the semantic search flag without really delivering a noticeably different experience. If semantic is the future of search, then Google has a long way to go. " Google's New Semantic Search: A Test, PCWorld What is the term for neglectful spelling of words such as "you" as "u"? English Language Usage Stack Exchange "is a question and answer site for linguists, etymologists, and serious English language enthusiasts. It's 100% free, no registration required." Google: how can u vs. how can an individual is not really about grammar @ Jerz's Literacy Weblog -- "A Googler who chooses to search for an individual rather than u or you or even a person is probably thinking of a word that contrasts with society, and that will affect the nature if the results being returned." Google boosting search to the speed of sound - Worldnews.com Ai Research - Creating a new form of life - Alan logs (Google Standard?!) English ? - OUseful.Info, the blog... Can "toast" (as in browned bread) ever be countable ... ACRL 2013: Visual Literacy In Action by Greg Hatch on Prezi An Introduction to Inertial and Visual Sensing U You turns student life into visual memoirs | The Daily Utah The U and You - Salt Lake City, UT - Education | Facebook The  U and You  Project: Longitudinal Storytelling Capturing ... MySpace comments - Statistical Cybermetrics Research Group This Time It's Different: Treasures and Traps in the Next Gen Transition Download meSaying yes to the Webs most dangerous search terms by Conor Myhrvold Social Media Netiquette Texting complaints come from stereotypes printed ... - linguistic pulse Spelling Thee, U and I: English Globish - Optimized Linguistic ... Useful Tips on Improving Your English Using Google ]] Mapping the Important Things The Before  Original St. Francis College Library Map New St. Francis College Library Map  Front New St. Francis College Library Map  Back Map Key (Subject by call number and color) On the same shelf : UNH School of Law library: Floor plan Queens University Floor Plan Tour University of Toronto Virtual Tour Library Tour @ Seneca Better by Design: An Introduction to Planning and Designing a New Library Building Ayub Khan Designing a School Library Media Center for the Future Rolf Erikson Checklist of Library Building Design Considerations William W. Sannwald The Library of Congress: The Art and Architecture of the Thomas Jefferson Building John Y. Cole Transforming Libraries, Building Communities: The Community-Centered Library Julie Biando Edwards The Academic Library Building in the Digital Age: A Study of Construction, Planning, and Design of New Library Space Christopher Stewart Creating the Customer-Driven Library: Building on the Bookstore Model Jeannette A. Woodward ]] "...originally told by Joy Garrison Wasson. She taught English in Muncie, Indiana for over thirty years.  She died on October 15, 2009, after a long illness. She was only 62." Source: [ http://philipchircop.wordpress.com ], and Harvey Mackay @ Early To Rise , read his excellent narrative, pleaseImage courtesy: Mrs Tattoodle See also : The Seven Wonders of the World @ Revering the Universe. Caring for Nature. Celebrating Life. World Pantheist Movement!, www.pantheism.net An Intense Life | The Seven Wonders and other inspirational things Seven Wonders of the World  A Different View - The Rat Race Trap 7_Wonders_of_the_World Not What You Think by The original ... Streams 'N Stirrings: Feast of the Assumption of Mary - Reflection ]] The Globe and Mail Oct 1, 2013 Facebook is making it even easier to search the posts and status updates of your friends (and other people who leave their posts unprotected) months after first introducing its Graph Search feature. On the same shelf: Social Graph or Graph Search -- What's in a name? Mark Zuckerberg Introduces Facebook 'Graphic App' Privacy Warning Hoax @ Hoax-Slayer Infographic: Google Search VS Facebook Graph Search ]] Googles Misinformation Graph Strikes Again, By Chris Crum WebProNews October 29, 2013 Extract: Users have encountered another blunder from the Google Knowledge Graph with Google showing some quite questionable content, and presenting it as "knowledge" on a very high-traffic search term. This is only the latest in a series of misfires from the Knowledge Graph, but probably the highest profile example yet, given the search term. ... Search for "st. louis cardinals" on Google right now, and you'll probably see a Knowledge Graph result that looks something like this: Its currently number five for baseball teams on Google Trends : continue reading: WebProNews ]] Physiognomy-- see books on the subject in the Library of Congress. Some may call it 'the language and assumptions of phrenology .' The Well Quiz October 3, 2013, Can You Read Peoples Emotions? By THE NEW YORK TIMES Are you tuned in to the emotions of others? Or have you been accused of being insensitive? If you are among those people who are mystified by moods, new research offers hope. A new study shows that certain types of reading can actually help us improve our sensitivity IQ. To find out how well you read the emotions of others, take the Well quiz, which is based on an assessment tool developed by University of Cambridge professor Simon Baron-Cohen. For each photo, choose the word that best describes what you think the person depicted is thinking or feeling...   Continue with The Well Quiz Understanding Your Score: The average score for this test is in the range of 22 to 30 correct responses. If you scored above 30, you may be quite good at understanding someones mental state based on facial cues. If you scored below 22, you may find it difficult to understand a persons mental state based on their appearance. (If no final score appeared, please double check to be sure you didnt skip a question. More more is in 'Can You Read Peoples Emotions?' By THE NEW YORK TIMES On the same shelf : Reading the mind in the eyes - Glenn Rowe's home page Is your personality written all over your face? Revealed in a new ... The Ancient Art of Chinese Face Reading - China Gaze Spiritual Seeker (Face Reading (Physiognomy): Eyes Since eyes ... How to Read Others' Emotions | eHow Face Reading in Chinese Medicine, 2e Lillian Bridges Amazing Face Reading: An Illustrated Encyclopedia for Reading Faces Mac Fulfer The Face Reader: Discover Anyone's Personality, Compatibility, Talents, and Challenges Through Chinese Face Reading Patrician McCarthy Face Reading: How to Know Anyone at a Glance Barbara Roberts Faces Around the World: A Cultural Encyclopedia of the Human Face ]] PS. Before we go to visualize the complexities, here are illustations of using the elephant in real time visual literacy training: I . Lesson 7 , Description: Have students work in pairs. Ask them to choose an object to study the parts of, the way the blind men studied the elephant. For example, if they choose a car, they may study the tires, windows, headlights, and bumpers. Have them write: A ____ is like a ______. SAY: Work with a partner. Choose an object and describe a few of its parts. For each one, write: A ____ is like a ______. [ source : Unit 6 - Pearson Longman] II. Developing Visual Literacy in Science : "Suppose you were to ask your students (before showing them the photograph) this thought-provoking question: What do you think a jungle looks like to a person riding on the back of an elephant ? What might they say?" [source: Developing Visual Literacy in Science K-8 - PB279X by  Jo Anne Vasquez] The term Visual Literacy is not so simple, given the shades of meanings it brings in the eyes of the beholder.... What people say: VISUAL LITERACY is an elephant . We are ljke the blind men . [ source : Visual Literacy White Paper Website @ A Supplement - visdesignoced] Just like media literacy, visual literacy is about analyzing and creating messages [ source : Visual literacy - ISTE] Visual literacy is about teaching people to understand the power of visual imagery to persuade, and to understand that the purveyors of media are using that power to persuade viewers with every image that they publish.[ source : The Myth of Visual Literacy Why Mass Consumption is King] Visual literacy is about interpreting images of the present and the past and producing images that effectively communicate the message to the audience [ source : LARSONart - Visual Literacy] If pictures can express what words alone cannot, and if that 'something' is what visual literacy is about then it may be difficult to define visual ... [ source : Visual Literacy And The Arts - SlideShare]  Visual Literacy is about getting that image in front and having people make meaning from it. [ source : Visual Literacy | Musing - CoETaIL] Visual literacy is about interpreting images of the past and producing images that effectively communicate the messages to an audience. [ source : visual literacy by Maureen Keegan on Prezi] "I attended this Webinar and found the title misleading. The subject is not visual literacy, how to interpret images, but rather about using visual elements in instruction. If you are interested in the second topic, the Webinar is quite good." [as illustrated by Prof. Robert P. Holley @ [collib-l] Visual Literacy, in relation to a webinar : Leveraging Visual Literacy for Communication By Nicole Brown ] "What does it mean to be visually literate? Does it mean different things in the arts and the sciences? In the West, in Asia, or in developing nations? If we all need to become "visually literate," what does that mean in practical terms? The essays gathered here examine a host of issues surrounding "the visual," exploring national and regional ideas of visuality and charting out new territories of visual literacy that lie far beyond art history, such as law and chemistry. With an afterword by Christopher Crouch, this groundbreaking collection brings together the work of major art and visual studies scholars and critics to explore what impact the new concept of "visual literacy" will have on the traditional field of art history." [source: Visual Literacy by James Elkins / Visual Studies: A Skeptical Introduction by James Elkins] See also: Media Literacy: Thinking Critically About Visual Culture (Media Literacy Series Ser) Peyton Paxson Dr. Bamford states, Any form of literacy, but especially visual literacy, is not about simply learning a fixed set of skills or grammars. [ source : Research related to visual literacy] ... visual literacy is not about passive reception. It also involves creativity, construction, manipulation, and an ability to communicate . [ source : ufetcontent / Visual Literacy - PBworks] Visual literacy in its broadest sense will be understood as the process by which images are constructed, organized, and expressed to communicate meaning, as well as the competencies associated with these processes (Nelson 66). The key element from this definition is the idea that images are used to communicate meaning. Visual literacy is not about eye candy. It is about knowledge. [ source : Designing YouTube Instructional Videos to Enhance Information Literacy, by Robert Monge in Brick and Click Libraries Symposium Proceedings November 2, 2007] 'Nowadays, with verbal literacy rates so high, visual literacy is not viewed as a vital form of communication. In truth, it is so vital a form that "computer-based communication," which includes visual elements, "has been called the 'fourth cognitive revolution' after speaking, writing, and printing" (Stafford 92)'.  [ source: Visual Literacy by Katherine Seiffert] On the same shelf : Six blind men is a parable that has crossed between many religious traditions and is part of Jain, Buddhist, Sufi and Hindu lore. Read more Six blind men and an elephant, by ben vershbow ideas from the famous Librarian, Thomas Mann: The Oxford Guide to Library Research. quoted in Database Searching -- Information Literacy for Library Technicians The Blind Men and the Elephant Musings on INTERFAITH ]] Here is an answer from Carnegie Mellon University ]] 404? is the Top Word of 2013 followed by fail!, hashtag, @pontifex, and The Optic Global Language Monitor s 14th Annual Survey of Global English . Toxic Politics is the Top Phrase, and Pope Francis the Top Name , Number of Words in the English Language:  1,025,109.8 (projected January 1, 2014 estimate) Extract : The Top Phrases of 2013 Rank / Phrase / Comment Toxic Politics Federal Shutdown Global Warming/Climate Change Federal Deficit Tread Lightly Boston Strong . .. To continue reading this list, click here. The Top Names of 2013 Rank /Name / Comments Pope Francis ObamaCare NSA Ed Snowden . Kate Middleton IRS ... To continue reading this list, click here Top Words of the Decade Click on the link above to see the Top Words of the First Decade of the 21st Century, including: Global Warming, 9/11, and Obama outdistanced Bailout, Evacuee, and Derivative; Google, Surge, Chinglish, and Tsunami followed. Climate Change was top phrase; Heroes was the top name. The Top Words of the Individual Years of the 21st Century thus far follow: 2012 Top Word: No. 1 ApocalypseArmageddon, No.2 Deficit, No. 3 Olympiad Top Phrases:  No. 1 Gangnam Style, No. 2 Climate Change/Global Warming, No. 3 Fiscal Cliff Top Names:  No. 1 Newtown and Malala Yousafzai, No. 3 Xi Jinping 2011: Top Words: No. 1 Occupy, No.2 Fracking, No.3 Drone Top Phrases:  No. 1 Arab Spring, No. 2 Royal Wedding, No.3 Anger and Rage Top Names:  No. 1 Steve Jobs, No. 2 Osama bin-laden and Seal Team Six, No.3 Fukushima 2010: Top Words: No. 1 Spillcam, No. 2 Vuvuzela, No. 3 The Narrative Top Phrases: No. 1 Anger and Rage, No. 2 Climate Change, No. 3 The Great Recession Top Names: No. 1 Hu Jintao, paramount leader of China, No. 2 iPad, No. 3 Barack Obama 2009: Top Words: No. 1 Twitter, No. 2 Obama-, No. 3 H1N1 Top Phrases: No. 1 King of Pop, No. 2 Obama-mania, No. 3 Climate Change Top Names: No. 1 Obama, No. 2 Michael Jackson, No. 3 Mobama Click here to see the Top Words of the First Decade of the 21st Century ]] By Chris Miles October 31, 2013 @ policymic.com ( Click to browse/view the chart , also via Reddit ) Extract: Ten mega corporations control the output of almost everything you buy; from household products to pet food to jeans. According to this chart via Reddit , called "The Illusion of Choice," these corporations create a chain that begins at one of 10 super companies. You've heard of the biggest names, but it's amazing to see what these giants own or influence. ( Note : The chart shows a mix of networks. Parent companies may own, own shares of, or may simply partner with their branch networks. For example, Coca-Cola does not own Monster, but distributes the energy drink. Another note: We are not sure how up-to-date the chart is. For example, it has not been updated to reflect PG's sale of Pringles to Kellogg's in February.) continue reading ]] Growing Veganism at a price , Shilpa Raina, Weeklyvoice Nov 2, 2013, p. A-6 . Note: The vegan food pyramid when visualized as a graphic becomes a great guide to plan healthy eating. A visual chart shows you how to include organic /or plant foods into your day to day life. On the same page (see the image in the above article of The Vegan Food Pyramid, such as, given in the following link): The Vegan Food Pyramid Visualized ]] These Fascinating Maps Show The Origin Of Words We Use All The Time Michael Kelley Nov. 5, 2013 Business Insider Extract: U.S. playwright Rita Mae Brown said : "Language is the road map of a culture. It tells you where its people come from and where they are going." That quote comes to mind looking at these fascinating European etymology maps of various commons words posted by reddit user sp07 , which provide a kind of cultural commentary on Europe. The word for "church" shows the influence of ancient Greece. "Bear" appears to be influenced by Russia, where largest brown bear population in Europe can be found. Notice the dominant word literally means "honey-eater." "Apple" has a lot of diversity: Notice how the word in Finland and Estonia may come from a Indo-Iranian origin. "Orange" is an interesting one. In the west it comes form Sanskrit while the dominant word in much of eastern and northern Europe comes from a word meaning "apple from China." Continue browsing ]] National Flags Created From the Foods Each Country Is Commonly Associated With, Posted by Paul Caridad visualnews.com Extract: Brazils flag made from banana leaf, limes, pineapple and passion fruit. Chinas flag made from pittaya/dragon fruit and star fruit. Frances flag made from Blue cheese, brie and grapes. Greeces flag made from Kalamata olives and feta cheese. continue reading ]] 9 Awesome Reasons to Use Infographics in your Content Marketing Extract: Source: Web Marketing Group 1. Compelling and Attractive 2. Easily Scanned and Viewed 3. Viral Capabilties 4. Portable (Embeddable) 5. Worldwide Coverage 6. Brand Awareness 7. Increases Traffic 8. Benefits Search Engine Optimisation 9. Shows an Expert understanding of a Subject On the same shelf: The Importance of Infographics or Information Visualization ... Why You Should Use Infographics For Marketing | DreamGrow ... Data Visualization Blog | Visual.ly Why Use Infographics? | serious fun -- Three opinionated school librarians explore library links so you don't have to Libraries and Literacy: Break the Cycle Infographic and Reading Advancement ]] Revisualizing Visual Culture (Digital Research in the Arts and Humanities) Chris Bailey  Contents : Introduction: making knowledge visual, Chris Bailey; Do a thousand words paint a picture?, Mike Pringle; The semantic web approach to improving access to cultural heritage, Kirk Martinez and Leif Isaksen; Resource discovery and curation of complex and interactive digital datasets, Stuart Jeffrey; Digital exploration of past design concepts in architecture, Daniela Sirbu; Words as keys to the image bank, Doireann Wallace; For one and all: participation and exchange in the archive, Sue Breakell; The user-archivist and collective (in)voluntary memory: read/writing the networked digital archive, James McDevitt; Internet art history 2.0, Charlotte Frost; Museum migration in century 2.08, Jemima Rellie; Slitting open the Kantian eye, Charlie Gere; Revisualizing Visual Culture is the sixth volume of xvi Revisualizing Visual Culture. " Revisualizing Visual Culture is recommended for information professionals who are currently navigating the challenges of arts and humanities analysis and display." ( Online Information Review). "... The collection has a distinctively British emphasis. Many of the contributions to the volume grew out of the Computers and History of Art (CHArt) group, which has been an active force in research on the application of digital technology to visual culture since 1985. While there are references to British projects and cultural institutions, readers will find the problems and ideas articulated relevant and accessible. " ( Canadian Journal of Information and Library Science ) On the same shelf: Exploring Digital Technologies and Historical Thinking What is/are Digital Humanities ? | Townsend Working Groups visual history special: Topics by WorldWideScience.org Digital Humanities - Research Guides - Western Michigan University University of South Australia Course Reading Visual Culture Suggested Readings | 21st Century Literacies: Digital Knowledge ]] One minute on the Internet, 2012 vs 2013, Info courtesy: ResearchBuzz News A snapshot of one minute on the internet, today and in 2012, By Leo Mirani @ lmirani November 26, 2013 Extracts : " Expressed in terms of percentage growth, one minute on the internet has grown along these lines: " (More graphics, click here ) Continue reading ]] stephenslighthouse.com Are We Overlooking a Powerful Engine for Social Economic Change? A one-page infographic outlining how libraries can contribute to social and economic development. beyondaccess.net ]] Stephen Abram ]] 