 A couple of years ago, I wrote a post about Atlantic City and its prolonged losing streakand Im sorry to report, things arent looking a whole lot better today. After a rocky 2009, revenues in AC fell again in 2010 by nearly 10%. And forecasters say that 2011 could be even worse. In an attempt to rejuvenate the fading gambling mecca, NJ governor Chris Christie, citing the complete incompetence and corruption in Atlantic City, recently pushed through legislation that makes him the citys de facto mayor. (Which led actual Atlantic City mayor Lorenzo Langford to complain  the state is treating Atlantic City like a pimp treats a prostitute .) One of Christies first moves was to spearhead the formation of an Atlantic City tourism district , which covers a large portion of the resort city. The state will take over responsibility for public safety, cleanliness and business development. Not a bad idea, given the seamy vibe that permeates AC once you set foot outside a casino. With that backdrop, let me tell you about a recent trip I made to the Trump Marina casino and hotel. First thing you should know about Trump Marina is that US billionaire Donald Trump is nowhere to be found. A few years ago, the three Trump casinos in Atlantic City were about to go broke, and he sold off all but 10% of the properties. So its really Trump in name onlyand at Trump Marina, soon even that will be gone. Houston-based Landrys Restaurants, owners of the Golden Nugget in Vegas, are buying the casino and will reportedly rebrand it with the Golden Nugget name. My trip to the casino occurred during a recent boys night out to attend the Atlantic City Beer Fest, followed by some obligatory late night gambling. With my trusty Trump One players club loyalty card in hand, I hit the casino floor late on a Friday night into Saturday morning. The place was half-dead and I mean that literally, as half the casino floor was shut down due to a lack of business. Its not a bad place, actually a welcome break from the more glitzy and more crowded Borgata and it wasnt a bad night either, which for me means I walked out with the same amount of money I walked in with, while enjoying a few cold beverages on the house. (My buddy Jim fared a bit better clearing over $400 from a four-hour session at the poker tables.) Now, I dont expect much from my Trump One loyalty card while Im at the placeIm a lower tier memberbut I do expect a little recognition and better customer experience when I go to the Web site , which I did a few days later to make sure my playing was being tracked. It was, but I felt a little less than welcome. A few notes on my Web experience:  I had trouble remembering my passwordI had selected it late one night with a code word that probably made sense at the time, but was now totally lost to me. I sent a message asking for help, but received a canned e-mail reply telling me the only way I could retrieve my password was to go to the casino. No password reset function. No one to call.  After 50 or so tries, I did remember the password to my Trump One accountlet me tell you, it was pretty obscureonly to find little relevant information for me on the site. I click to view my Statementits not there, I need to call to get the info. I click on Rooms and a blank screen appears.  Even if I hadnt hit the threshold to receive an offer or room reward, the site needs to engage me. Give me a few dollars off on my next stay. Offer me a free app if I eat at the restaurant. Tell me you cant wait for me to come back. Show me some love! But it looks like Ill have to wait for the new regime to get some personalized attention. A NY-based management company is now running the Trump casinos, and according to a company exec quoted in the press, theyre focused on cutting costs, including marketing programs that were deemed to be too expensive...we were over-incentivizing our customers ...it was not a sustainable model. Granted the house needs to make money, but cutting back on incentivizing our customers seems like the wrong way to go about it and a good way to lose an ever decreasing pool of loyal customers that is opting to go to the more glamorous Borgataor other, newer casinos that have popped up in Philly , Delaware and New York . But my guess is now that the Trump Marina has been sold, the caretakers have packed their bags and are waiting for the new owners to arrive so they can turn over the keys. Soon the Trump Marina will be historyand the Golden Nugget will take its place. Itll be interesting to see if they bring new vim and vigor in the attempt to attractand more importantly, retaincustomers . This post, by Tom Rapsas , originally appeared on Loyalty Truth , May 11, 2011.]] I borrowed the headline above from a recent B-to-B article by Jeff Ernst, a principal analyst at Forrester Research. I think it perfectly underscores something Ive been saying for a while now: Its about the power of the idea, not the tactic. (My colleague, loyalty expert Bill Hanifin , has a similar mantra: Technology enables. Imagination wins.) While most companies are now testing the social media waters with a presence on Facebook and Twitter, its best to have a strategic plan of attack before diving in. In the words of Ernst, Starting with tools and tactics spells disaster. You need to start by understanding the social behaviors of your target audience and defining the big ideas that will attract and engage them. But before discussing big ideas in social marketing... First things first: youve got to show up. To paraphrase Woody Allen, 90% of social marketing is just showing up, and by that I mean being active on whatever social media tool youre using. That means starting conversations, answering queries, and when necessary, defending your company or brand. To do this, youve got to set aside a small portion of your day to social media activities. (For me, its 20 minutes each morning.) Next step: you need a big idea. Whats a little more challenging is the next 10% of the equationcoming up with the big ideas that give your customers something to talk about. As Jillian Ney pointed out in a recent post on Social Media Today, The motivation has been to collect fans and followers, which have resulted in many branded social spaces not actually providing any entertainment or value. In many ways, a great social media campaign has much in common with a great traditional ad campaignthe best ones are centered around a big idea. To achieve big status, your idea needs to have the power to inform, entertain and/or engage your customers, while getting them to take a desired action, whether its signing up for e-mail, retweeting a message or checking in with you on Foursquare. Here are three social media ideas that I think work hard for their brands. Why? They go beyond simply blasting messages into the social media space, and actually get people to interact with the brand. They also leverage ideas that are natural tie-ins to the image and essence of the brands being promoted. Paula Deen and  the real women of Philadelphia  . A promotion for Philadelphia Cream Cheese, it invites customers to submit original recipes using Philadelphia brand products, with 16 finalists selected to join celebrity chef Deen in a live Cook Off where four grand prize winners will be chosen. While Im not a big fan of celebrity endorsements, this one feels like a natural, since its easy to imagine the down-home Deen actually using Philadelphia Cream Cheese in her recipes. Importantly, the site has done a nice job of putting Paulas ebullient personality to use through online videos and social media like a live chat on Twitter. Coleman, the original social networking site. Coleman, the camping gear company, has done a great job of tying their brand into social networking, starting with their clever original networking site positioning. A Facebook page promotes their easy-to-build tents with a Summer Time in no Time giveaway. Theres a Twitter page that could be a little more active, but does address the occasional customer query, plus a YouTube channel and Twitter app that fittingly let you check out creepy campfire stories. Fair Tweets from Ben Jerrys . Another big idea comes from ice-cream maker Ben Jerrys. We think of Ben Jerrys as a very socially conscious brand and they prove it with Fair Tweets , which uses Twitter in a way I havent seen before to promote Fair Trade, a global organization that works to get better deals for farmers. It works like this: You go to the Ben Jerrys Fair Tweet page, and being typing in a tweet. The site then puts your unused Twitter characters to use, by turning any leftover characters (from your 140 character cap) into a message about Fair Trade. 33 characters left? A 33-character message is tacked on to the end of your tweet. Very cool and an ingenious way to spread a public service message. How about you. Have you seen or worked on any big social media ideas lately?]] Saucony is a mid-sized running shoe company thats battling for customers with athletic gear giants like Nike, Reebok and Adidas. So how do they compete? By making an emotional connection with first-time buyers, and then introducing them to an online community that helps turn them into loyal customers. Now, no one develops a loyal customer base without having a great productand Saucony does. Their constantly evolving product line generates consistently strong reviews from customer influencers like Runners World magazine. But what really sets Saucony apart, is its engaging and inventive advertising, specifically its Web and social media presence. Last month I wrote that the key to a great social media campaign is a big ideaand Saucony has one that starts with its general ad campaign, and is then layered into its Web and social media efforts. The campaign theme is What is Strong and in TV and Web spots, runners are challenged to define what strong means to them and encouraged to Find Your Strong. The strong theme is featured prominently throughout the Saucony Web site. Runners are invited to  Create Share Your Personal Strong  by entering the things that make them strong, including how they train and what inspires them. You can then share these thoughts via the Web site, Facebook or Twitterand even have your strong statements made into a T-shirt. Coolest of all, is the campaigns interactive online gallery . You can choose to participate in, or just view, a clever and well-designed series of word portraits that show how other runners have answered the query This is My Strong. Call-outs include things like 6am Run, My Mom and My City-New Orleans. As expected, the Sacuony Web site is chock full of pages on the latest running shoes and apparel, as well as the technology behind it. But whats compelling and differentiating here is the online community , where runners can gain inspiration from both elite and everyday runners. The writing is great throughout, as well. For instance, the Community page greets you with language that runners (like me) just eat up: We all share a common love of running. A common pride in personal bests. A common disdain for potholes and cramping. A common interest in other runners. Welcome, runners all. Great job, Saucony. And while I must admit to being a long-time Nike loyalist, Ill be taking a very close look at Saucony the next time I go shoe shopping. This post originally appeared on Loyalty Truth and was written by writer and creative director Tom Rapsas . ]] One of the primary reasons for a company to be on social media is to build relationships and engage customers in a dialogue. So why are a lot of big-time pharmaceutical companies about to walk away from their Facebook pages? It seems that up to this point, Facebook gave pharma companies the ability to turn off commenting on their pages, a privilege they didnt grant to other industries. This suited the risk-adverse pharma folks just fine as it gave them the ability to block comments they didnt like. But all that came to an end on Monday, August 15. You see, a few months ago Facebook sent an e-mail notifying all pharma page administrators that the social media site was changing the rules and that pages that currently have commenting disabled will no longer have this entitlement after August 15th. As reported on Web site ClickZ , this poses a major problem in the US: Pharma marketers are required to report adverse effects of their drugs, so if someone posts a comment about an adverse effect on a Facebook page, the company is responsible to report that to the Food and Drug Administration. Also, when they become aware of online conversations including incorrect or off-label information about their drugs and products, they need to notify the FDA. Can anyone say big can of worms? It also means the pharma companies can no longer prevent those who have had adverse side effects from a drug from posting their comments online for all to see. As pointed out in the Pharma Marketing Blog , all it takes is one disgruntled customer to cause havoc. The European drug company Sanofi-aventis chose to shut down its Facebook page after a string of negative comments from a cancer survivor who had permanent hair loss after taking the drug Taxotere. So whats next? As pointed out in the blog Pharma Exec , companies now have three choices: 1. Go dark and wait for the FDA to issue guidelines on how to report potential adverse events they may discover on their Facebook pages. 2. Go dark temporarily and build the infrastructure to cope with the real time flow of consumer commentary. 3. Continue on with Facebook, backed by the staff to monitor Facebook and other social networking sites. A few major drug makers have already chosen options one and two. Over the weekend, the Washington Post reported that AstraZeneca and Johnson Johnson, have decided to remove their Facebook pages as a consequence of the policy change. Other companies said they will monitor their pages more closely now that the changes have taken effect. But my thinking is, as more and more consumers lean on the Web as their primary source for information, youve got to have the social media bases covered, including Facebook. After all, if someone has something bad to say about your product, if it doesnt come out on Facebook, its bound to appear somewhere else. And its better to be in a venue where the playing field is level and you at least have the chance to respond. What do you think? ]] Ive long been a fan of Amazon and as proof carry an Amazon.com-branded Visa Rewards Card in my wallet. Sure, the interest rate is a few points higher than my primary credit card, but Im a sucker for the points. I earn one for every dollar I spend and a whopping 3 points for every dollar spent on the Amazon Web site. Over the past several years, the Amazon program worked like most others: you waited for your points to add up to a certain threshold, continually checking your balance online or on your monthly bill, and then ordered your reward. While there were a number of options, I always went for the $25 Amazon certificate available at 25,000 points. But last month, something changed: while checking out, I noticed a small prompt about using my current point balance toward the payment of my order. Sure enough, I had earned 1693 points since my last cert was issuedand was able to apply a $16.93 credit to my purchase, right on the spot. I mean, how convenient was that! No checking my points balance to see if I had reached the 25,000 point threshold, no ordering a certificate, no waiting 3-4 weeks for the cert to appear in the mail. I was able to get instant savings and in turn, instant gratification. Now I can imagine this scares the bejesus out of some loyalty marketers because, having worked in hardcore points-based loyalty for several years, I know the philosophy. By forcing people to reach elevated point thresholds, you keep them as customersbecause they have to stick around and make additional purchases to reach these thresholds, and are less likely to abandon their points for a competitor. But you know whatthe times in the loyalty marketing game are changing, with a mix of established and newer companies leading the charge. For example, check out the following recent developments: *Marriott announced Marriott Rewards Instant Redemption which enables members to redeem points on the spot at participating US hotelsfor dinner, cocktails, massage, golf...even a room upgrade...with no certificates, no waiting. *Location-based marketer Foursquare inked a deal with American Express to enable its 10 million cardholders to redeem location-based deals by swiping their AmEx cardgiving them access to instant membership rewards. *Online retailer Soap.com (as reported by Internet Retailer ) rolled out a customer loyalty program with a new twist. Instead of launching a traditional customer loyalty program that lets shoppers gather points...they reward customers with instant product discounts. I say its only a matter of time before all the traditional points-based loyalty marketers, including the airline programs, jump on the instant rewards bandwagonor find themselves left behind by the competition. Sure, there may be a place for the hard-earned mega-point reward, but you better give your customers the option of quick and instant rewards and recognition. What do you think? This post originally appeared on Loyalty Truth and was written by Tom Rapsas . ]] As I scanned the rapidly moving traffic on my Twitter feed the other day, there was one tweet in particular that caught my eye. It was from the journalist David Carr who was quoting Adam Moss, the editor of New York magazine: "I think the advertising business is in greater upheaval than the journalism business." As an ad guy, I had to dwell on that one for a moment. When I think of industries in crisis due to the onset of the digital age, the newspaper businesswhich is bleeding customers to free online news sitespops up neck and neck with travel agents. But after careful consideration, I realized that Moss had a point. Putting aside for a moment the dismal state of the economy and its impact on ad spending, the upheaval in advertising has been going on for several years. First it was a move away from traditional advertising vehicles (TV, radio, print) to online media (e-mail, banners and Web sites). This set off the first wave of advertising is dead claims. In 2005, with an article titled Chaos Scenario, and with a follow-up in 2007 called  Chaos Scenario 2.0 , Ad Age columnist Bob Garfield wrote about  a post-apocalyptic media world substantially devoid of brand advertising as we have long known it . In 2009, IBM issued a white paper titled  The end of advertising as we know it  that discussed,  the shift in consumer attention from television to other media formats.  But these commentaries, while pointing out the move from traditional media to digital, only hinted at whats taking place in 2011. Today, t he really big change involves the continuing evolution of social media and consumer review sites. Some pretty big names in the world of marketing are again saying its the end of advertising, but their message has been tweaked a bit. The claim: the ever-rising influence of Facebook, Twitter and now Google Plus , and consumer review sites like Yelp, Angies List and Trip Advisor, have made advertising obsolete. Here are a few notable, recent examples of those whove jumped on the 2011-version of advertising is dead:  In May, at ad:tech San Francisco , Antonio Lucio, the global marketing chief of Visa, claimed that  recommendations are the new advertising . Lucio and suggested that brands develop " an army of advocates " to promote their products via social media in lieu of traditional media.  In June, writing in Forbes , the head of global agency Gyro, Rick Segal, extended the advertising is dead claim to B-to-B marketing. He stated that:  Death was inevitable when people began carrying their telecommunications and computing power with them .  In September, at the interactive OMMA Global conference , futurist Faith Popcorn got even more declarative. She said that with arrival of the hyper-connected consumer  advertising is so over. If the consumer believes youre paying for their time, they dont really believe in it . Add to this scenario several years of shrinking advertising budgets, and its easy to see how some might gravitate to an advertising is dead mindset. After all, its easier and cheaper to plow your limited marketing dollars into social media and gaming the consumer review sites than trying to target a market whose media choices are increasingly fragmented. My take: advertising will survivebut its morphing into something new. Traditional advertisingand I think that category now has to include e-mail and Web bannerswill stick around. After all, social media alone is not right for every business, every target market and every marketing situation. But theres no doubt that the way we reach customers is continuing to change, as we recalibrate the best ways to reach customers in a personally relevant and timely manner. A good communications program is still about engagement, our ability to attract new customers and nurture relationships with our current customers through a compelling and strategically sound message. And when it comes to achieving these aims, theres no one-size-fits-all solution. Especially with the ever-changing way customers digest their information. A surprising recent study (albeit, by the US Postal Service) showed that direct mail was actually preferred over e-mail by the Gen X demographic. And social media burnout has been well-documented as well, with a groundswell of people choosing to shut down their Facebook and Twitter accountsor at least interact with them a lot less frequently. So in the future, I think that successful marketing campaigns will be as diverse as the audience youre trying to reach. Its as likely to include a personalized e-mail as a promo on Foursquare, a targeted mail piece as a video on YouTube. The key is in finding the right mix for your target market, and making sure that your communications are as compelling, timely and relevant as possible. What do you think?]] Im a former customer of the now defunct U.S. bookseller Borders and a past member of their Rewards Perks program. While I freely admit to moving a lot of my business to Amazon.com over the years, I was sorry to see Borders go. Maybe its nostalgia, but every once in a while I like to walk into a book store, stroll the aisles, and leisurely look for a title or two I may have missed. Just like reading a physical book has a tactile advantage over an e-reader, I also think a physical store has a sensory advantage over a virtual storefrontwhich for me, unfortunately, ultimately gets trumped by the superior selection and lower prices of an Amazon. But back to Borders. When the pieces of the company were sold off, competitor Barnes Nobel made an important purchase that went beyond the chains physical inventorythey bought Borders customer contact info and importantly, their purchase history, giving them the data they need to send out personally relevant communications. The wooing has begun, as B N is now attempting to turn me from a qualified prospect to a customer. Theyve sent me a few e-mails to date and while I think my scant recent personal history prevents them from sending truly relevant messages, I do appreciate their efforts. From a communications perspective, I think theyve made a smart progression from showing sympathy over the loss of Borders, to being transparent when revealing the use of my Borders customer data, to being justifiably retail-y as they seek my business. See the messaging sequence below: October 1: Sympathy Over the Break-Up Dear Borders Customer, My name is William Lynch, CEO of Barnes Noble, and Im writing to you today on behalf of the entire BN team to make you aware of important information regarding your Borders account. First of all let me say Barnes Noble uniquely appreciates the importance bookstores play within local communities, and were very sorry your Borders store closed. October 15: Honesty and Transparency Dear Borders Customer, As a reminder, on September 30, 2011 Barnes Noble acquired the Borders customer list. The transferred personally identifiable information in the customer list includes customer e-mail addresses and purchase history. No credit card data was transferred. If you would like to opt out of having your customer data transferred, please go to www.bn.com/borders by November 2, 2011. November 7: Asking me out on a first date. Subject line: Lets get to know each other, starting right now. Youll always be welcome here. Nothing says welcome like an extra 30% off your first purchase at Barnes Noble. November 26: Attempt at a second date. Subject line: A convenient 40% off at the always convenient BN.com Your nearest Barnes Nobel is open 24/7at BN.com. Take an Extra 40%off one item. I think Barnes Noble is in a tough spot and agree with many that theyll be the next domino to fall in the radically changing book industry. That said, I do think theyre doing a good job trying to convert prized prospectsformer Borders customers like meto the B N fold. In fact, I recently used the 40% off coupon above to make my first purchase. Now the true test will be whether or not they can convert me into a regular customer. This post is by writer/creative director Tom Rapsas who can be found here .]] Theres a fascinating article titled  The Dawn of the Relationship Era in Marketing  that recently appeared in AdAge magazine. Its written by David Rogers and Bob Garfield, the latter the same guy who caused a stir a few years ago with the essay  The Chaos Scenario  which (semi-correctly) predicted the end of advertising as we know it. This piece isnt quite so controversial, but it does point out that the role of marketing in the selling equation is changing. The authors posit that were witnessing the end of the Consumer Era and are now moving into the Relationship Era. The Relationship Era is based around the idea that companies that succeed in the future will do so because theyve made some sort of human connection with their customer base. The belief is that in the Relationship Era, the big winners will be companies that people trust because they have solid core values and transparent and honest practices". T hese companies will spend little on advertisingbecause they won't need it. Theyve made a personal connection with a core group of customers who trust them implicitly, because theyve backed up their core values with actions. They can then rely on these loyal customers to spread the word about their products and services and attract new customers. The authors believe these brand-fan customers will: "...share your links and retweet you on Twitter and post a photo of themselves with your product on Facebook and like you on Facebook and generate all these network conversations, which go back to the top of the funnel and influence other customers in your network at their own stage of awareness, consideration, preference or action." So how do you get to be one of these beloved companies who people are tweeting and posting about? It starts with a purpose according to Rogers and Garfield. You have to explain to all comers why you're in business. Among the companies identified as successfully explaining themselves and their values are Apple, Whole Foods and Trader Joes. One prime example thats cited is outdoors outfitter Patagonia who for years has had a purpose that resonates with its customers: Build the best product, cause no unnecessary harm, use business to inspire and implement solutions to the environmental crisis. The company then backs up this mantra with real-world actions, donating 1% of its gross sales to environmental causes, promoting environmental sustainability in every aspect of its operations and providing progressive workplace policies like paternity leave and paid sabbaticals. Another company identified as a having authentic purpose: Krispy Kreme. After a rough start to the decade, in 2009 a new management team went searching for the companys raison detre and came up with: " Touching and enhancing people's lives through the joy that is Krispy Kreme. Management then decreed that the joy ethic inform every interaction at every level of the business. My take: I can buy into the Relationship Erabut only to a point. Its hard to argue with companies like Trader Joes and Patagonia, that have carved out their own unique niche in the marketplace with little to no advertising, but lots of positive word-of-mouth and social networking buzz. After all, whats not to like about free advertising? But the fact is, these kind of companies are few and far between. Put under a microscope, Id say the majority of US companies would be unable to pass the authenticity sniff test. Even successful companies often arent nimble or visionary enough to coalesce around a single purpose and execute it in the marketplace. Its just not in their DNA. For instance, I wonder if every Krispy Kreme franchise has really been able to add the joy ethic to every business transaction. The good news: companies that lack a specific purpose their customers can rally around, have other ways to grow their business and increase brand loyalty. This includes doing all they can to improve the customer experience from pre-sale to post-sale. It also means enhancing customer engagement, so that customers are communicated with in personal, relevant ways across a variety of touch points. What do you thinkis the Relationship Era upon us? This article is by Tom Rapsas. You can reach him via LinkedIn . ]] About once a week, Ill go into my Google e-mail account and check out my Spam folder. There, Ill usually find e-mails from a few retailers who, even though Ive opted to receive e-mails from them, have broken some unwritten Google rules about what constitutes Spam. A few observations: The Google Spam detector doesnt like exclamation points in subject lines. Take this one from Staples: Penny deals and more ways to save! or this one from Hallmark: TOM, see 4 new Recordable Storybooks! It also doesnt like numbers in subject lines, as evidenced by this example from Lending Tree: Tom, rates are as low as 2.5% (3.244% APR) and this one from ProFlowers: 40% off, Tom...Just because we like you? All wound up in my Spam folder. But whats most interesting and entertaining in my Spam box are the many scam e-mails I find there. These scams fall into a few categories, but they all have something in common: their tortured use of the English language, including misspellings and painfully awkward phrases, and their total lack of believability. Below are two types of scams Ive noticed in abundance lately, as well as a new one. Scam Category #1: Youre the lucky winner of a sweepstakes. If you had checked my Spam box over the past few months, youd see that Im one lucky dude. For Ive won everything from the Irish Sweepstakes to something called the Microsoft Lottery. Heres an excerpt from my latest bonanza. It appears Ive won a million-million dollars, which I think adds up to a gazillion. Subject: Dear Lucky Winner Your e-mail address have been Chosen today on the 1st March 2012,To free lotto Tickets No. lotto/2012/ATMcard. You have therefore been approved to claim a total sum of US1,000,000 Million Dollars in cash credited to file KTU/9023118308/03. All participants for the online version were selected randomly from World Wide Web sites through computer draw system and extracted from over 100,000 unions, This compensation is proudly sponsored by the Microsoft Corporation, Coca Cola, MTN, Toyota and Toshiba. Scam Category #2: Somebody died. Lets share the inheritance. Most of this type of e-mails center around something really bad happening, including plane and helicopter crashes, the Japanese Tsunami and even a military coup. In just the past week, Ive heard from almost a dozen friends and relatives of the deceased whose stories always go like this: somebody suddenly died, theres several million dollars in a bank somewhere, and my help is urgently needed to get it out. This recent entry will give you a good idea of the approach: Subject: THANKS AND REMAIN BLESSED DEAR FRIEND, I AM MR.FADI HASSAN A STAFF OF ISLAMIC DEVELOPMENT BANK IN BENIN REPUBLIC. I WANT TO TRANSFER AN ABANDONED SUM OF US$5.5MILLION INTO YOUR BANK ACCOUNT FOR US TO SHARE IT. THE DEPOSITOR IS LATE SAIF AL-ARAB GADDAFI. ON 30TH APRIL 2011, THE LIBYAN GOVERNMENT REPORTED THAT SAIF AL-ARAB AND THREE OF HIS YOUNG NIECES AND NEPHEWS WERE KILLED BY A NATO AIRSTRIKE ON HIS HOUSE DURING THE 2011 LIBYAN CIVIL WAR LEAVING NOBODY FOR THE CLAIM. I HAVE ALL THE INFORMATION ABOUT THE DECEASED CUSTOMER`S ACCOUNT AND AS SUCH, WE CAN BOTH COLLECT THE MONEY WITHOUT ANY PROBLEM. THERE IS NO RISK INVOLVE IN THIS TRANSACTION. YOUR SHARE WILL BE 40% WHILE 60% WILL BE FOR ME. KINDLY FORWARD YOUR BANKING DETAILS FOR THE TRANSFER AS INDICATED BELOW.... New Scam Category: Love is in the air! So give me your bank account info. Since I imagine the sweepstakes, inheritance and bank phishing scams are now growing a little tired, heres a new one: a love letter of sorts from a tall and fair Guinean vixen. Of course, there are some strings attached to her appeal for a relationship. Subject: My Dear, My Dear, How are you today? I know this mail will come to you as a surprise, because you don't know me and I don't know you well. Let me first of all introduce myself to you, My name is Miss Gladys Ijere Paul, 21 years old girl from Guinea Bissau. I am tall and fair in complexion, I am loving and caring. After finish my prayer, I got your email from yahoo trust search when I was searching for a foreign partner who will help me for business transaction. Please reply me if only you are interested and ready to help me and provide an account that will be use in receiving the fund into your bank account. Please I need your help so that we can proceed. Honestly Speaking I have a special something I want to discus with you about my life and this transaction; I know age will not be a beerier to our relationship. What I need is just your love and caring. I will give you my best; I really want to have a good relationship with you. I will send my pictures to you and also tell you more about my self, Have a wonderful day with love and trust, bye for now; I am waiting to hear from you soon, Miss Gladys. Sorry Miss Gladys, but my wife would not approve. And I could be wrong, but I have a funny feeling youre more interested in a relationship with my money than with me. (Maybe I can connect her with the guy holding my sweepstakes winnings.) This post was written by Tom Rapsas and previously appeared on Loyalty Truth . ]] Each day en route to my office in New York City I pass a bright blue billboard on the New Jersey Turnpike. Its for the newly redesigned United Airlines MileagePlus loyalty program and it makes the rather bold claim that its The worlds most rewarding loyalty program. Ive been curious as to how the Continental and United merger was working out, specifically in regards to the loyalty program. For several recent years I was a very frequent flier and Continental was my airline of choice. I had a Gold Elite card and have to say I had no complaints whatsoever, especially on those LA to NY flights where getting bumped up to first-class was a godsend. So when I paid a visit to the now super-sized airlines MileagePlus loyalty rewards page, I was surprised at what I found there . For there, right on the airlines very own turf, the program and customer experience around the program were getting roundly and soundly thrashed. On a page titled  The facts about MileagePlus account numbers, PINs and passwords, theres an open comment thread where frequent United fliers can Post a Comment and say pretty much whatever they want. As the page notes: At the United Hub we welcome lively and courteous discussion, so we do not screen comments before you post them. Well, if MileagePlus was hoping for a lively discussion, they got it. I read all 18 online comments that were posted over a 7-day period from March 21-27, and the program scored a perfect 18 for 18. Every single one was negative, most in a scathing I dont care how long weve been together, Im ready to get a divorce kind of way. Below youll find some of the messages posted by MileagePlus members. Ive edited down the longer entries, but the content is 100% genuine. Begin Comment Thread: MARCIA FRIEDMAN 7:51 AM on March 21, 2012 I have been trying for 2 weeks every day to get my account set up. The phone disconnects me after holding on and the email is not answered. United service is nonexistent. UNDEFINED 9:29 AM on March 22, 2012 United.... OMG. This new system is absolutely HORRIBLE!!!! You lost my mileage... All my flights this month have not been credited. Customer service is WORTHLESS. I have been flying United for the past 7 years but I am considering leaving and taking my tens of thousands of dollars that I spend elsewhere. Get it together United. CONNIE SISKA 11:29 AM on March 23, 2012 United - really - what happened here? I loved the previous United website. this new one - you can keep - it is horrible, not user friendly, stuff goes missing and I can't tell if my reservation is waitlisted for upgrade or not. I am at GOLD Status, but you sent my mileage card for SILVER and I can't get anyone to respond back to me to see if my new one has been mailed. I have been a loyal United customer for the past 12 years and I am not happy about the change. CHRIS SHAW 11:22 AM on March 24, 2012 This is now an airline that blows PR all over the place BUT does not answer or respond to whatever means me the PREMIER customer tries. How do you spell JET BLUE??? RISCILLA APPEL KENNEDY 1:26 PM on March 26, 2012 Since the switch from Continental to United my 6 years worth of miles are currently unretrievable in outer space. I have been on hold with United for over (6) hours since last Tuesday to get technical support to retrieve these miles. There is no urgency in their part... CHRISTOF ABSOLUM 5:16 PM on March 26, 2012 Hello. I have been trying to connect but none of my Mileage number and password work anymore. My access in now blocked...I have been sending messages to the Mileage plus support as mentioned but after 5 messages sent over the last 3 weeks, no answer at all from United. UNDEFINED 6:04 AM on March 27, 2012 Absolute worst service, ever. Took my over 90 minutes just to check in, with the rudest staff (in san francisco) that I have ever encountered. Their system is totally jacked. It's a joke that they actually have customer service, nobody was willing to offer service. It's a miracle that one worker was able to "break the system" so I could actually fly home. Why I would want their miles program is beyond me. VYNESSA ALEXANDER 4:59 PM on March 27, 2012 I have been working with both United as premier exec and Continental as gold elite...... I have been unable to log on to the site. There is no web support. Ask alex is a farce. United service and support was always better than continental. I have been trying to get help for over a week. Sent emails for help on refunds no response. This is really annoying. End Comment Thread. You get the idea. There appears to be a major meltdown happening at the MileagePlus Web site, and it has obviously alienated a whole lot of Uniteds frequent flyer base. Yet, curiously, it seems like theres no one minding the MileagePlus store with customer queries going unanswered for days and even weeks. I see two valuable lessons to be gained from this situation, especially as it relates to opening a dialogue with customers: 1. Never, ever leave a comment system unmanned. Having an open, uncensored comment system is a bold and commendable move. But you absolutely have to have someone onboard ready to respond, answering questions and doing their best to assist program members. Its an opportunity for a dialogue, not one-way customer diatribes. 2. W hen absolutely everything is going wrong, disable the comments. When you reach Three Mile Island meltdown stage, its time to shutdown the comment section and regroup. Sure, it goes against your  we do not screen comments  philosophy, but sometimes practicality is the better course when your good intentions have been turned into a weapon thats being used against you. Heres hoping they get things straightened out before I start flying again. Editors note: As of March 29, when this post appeared on Loyalty Truth , all the initial negative comments on the MileagePlus site were deleted. But as of today, April 16th, a new crop of negative comments has emerged--with no responses from anyone at United. Once again, someone appears to be asleep at the MileagePlus response desk. ]] A friend at an ad agency recently shared with me some spec creative work they had pitched to a big national company. The primary focus, per the client brief, was an overhaul of the company Web site. And I thought my friends agency had done a nice job. The design they came up with was neat and clean, the information was well-organized and there were a couple of nifty bells-and whistles. There was just one thing missing: the big idea. The agency later found out they hadnt won the business and frankly, I wasnt surprised. Because had I stumbled upon the proposed site, I couldnt have told you what the company stood for, what separated them from their competitors or why I should buy from them . It was another me-too site. And I dont think this lack of originality was an isolated incident. Over the past few years, it feels like the power of the idea is often trumped by the power of technology. Coolness wins over substance, and when that happens the opportunity to connect with consumers in a meaningful way is often missed. You may make a one-off sale, but the emotional connection that leads to return visits, repeat sales and brand loyalty is lost. In the creative department we often say that the creative work is only as good as the strategy or brief behind it. (The exact phrase we use is  Sh-t in, sh-t out .) And I believe a leading cause of the dearth of the big idea, is a faulty or non-existent strategy from the outset. The upfront thinking (aka heavy lifting) thats required for meaningful work is often kicked down the road and then retro-fitted into whatever creative/technological solution thats deemed the most cutting edge or fashionable. In a recent blog post , Seth Godin touched on this less than consumer-friendly approach to marketing, specifically as it relates to strategy. Godin posited that the culprit was often the fact that there were too many strategies out there:  an email strategy and a social media strategy and a web strategy and a mobile strategy  and that they often ignored the  one and only one thing that matters, and it's people . Godin goes on to point out the pitfalls that come with an incoherent strategy: All of these media are conduits, they are tools that human beings use to waste time or communicate or calculate or engage or learn. Behind each of the tools is a person. Do you have a story to tell that person? An engagement or a benefit to offer them? Figure out the people part and the technology gets a whole lot simpler. When we put more value on the tools and tactics than the upfront thinking, what results are poor strategies that lead to weak ideas that fail to engage the consumer. While the finished product, for instance a new Web site, may look shiny and hip on the outside, it often has a pixel-thin appeal and lacks the emotional resonance that sparks people into developing a real relationship with your brand. One company thats getting it right: Anthropologie. My wife is a big fan of this female-focused companys clothing and accessories and a visit to their Web site helped show me why. The Anthropologie site successfully sells an alluring lifestyle that varies by season. Currently themed The Island Life, the site features a mix of beautiful island photography, video and copy thats carried through on each of the sites main sub-pages. It sets a great mood and romances the customer before trying to make a sale. As far as the companys use of personalization, upon entering the site it immediately called up the nearest store location (helpfully informing me it was currently closed for remodeling from head to toe, but pointing out another nearby location). And I know from e-mails my wife has received, they also do a fine job of personalizing e-mails, apparently by analyzing her past purchasing behavior. Kudos on a job well done! ]] Normal.dotm 0 0 1 467 2246 MENY 249 106 3275 12.0 0 false 18 pt 18 pt 0 0 false false false Theres a quirky online e-tailer named Fab thats taking a unique approach to building their customer base. Theyre relying almost solely on word-of-mouth through social media, including Twitter, Facebook and Pinterest, to both grow sales and encourage customer engagement. The thinking behind Fab is different from virtually every other online retailer. For starters, you have to join Fab as a member to gain entry to the site. Then, once youre on board, you can invite your friends to join in exchange for a nice commission. You receive a $30 credit for getting 10 new members to join, and a $25 credit if your referral makes a $25 purchase within 30 days of joining. The site is well-designed, clean and simple, but its real beauty is the way it has integrated social media into its DNA in order to keep its members active and engaged. There are ubiquitous social media links around most product pages, as well as omnipresent ad banners inviting users to Shop with Facebook friends. Theres a  Live Feed  page that connects customers and lets you peek in on who is buying and faving what. So far, this unique social shopping scheme appears to be working. Fab opened for business just last year and already has 4.5 million members and is generating $400,000 in sales each day. And theyre doing it without any advertising and without any discernable brand voice . This got me thinking: is community the new loyalty? In my days at pioneering loyalty marketing shop Frequency Marketing, we talked about loyalty in terms of reward and recognition. Reward usually involved a points-based program that got customers to stick around for a tangible payoff once they reached a preset spending level, while recognition involved soft benefits like complimentary upgrades or services. But in the digital age, that feels more and more like a limited approach. As best I can tell, Fab has no loyalty program. Their brand voice is muted at best. And while it does offer a cool and diverse product line, there are dozens of other e-tailers doing the same the thing. (For starters, check out The Real Real , Uniqlo or Styloko .) I believe that Fab could be on the leading edge of a new way to gain customer loyalty thats based not on your relationship with the brand itselfbut on the relationship you have with the brands community. On Fab, thats the friends and acquaintances with whom you share links about whats cool and whats not. The fact is no matter how compelling your brand story might be, a consumer is still more likely to relate and bond with like-minded shoppers, who share their whims, desires and tastes. Bring enough of these shoppers together in a community, and you could have a force more powerfully able to retain customers and increase customer spend than even the savviest loyalty program. What do you think? Note: This post originally appeared on Loyalty Truth on 6.4.12. ]] Gwen Bell Every once in a while, its good to get back to the marketing basics. I was reminded of one recently while reading Reverb , an interesting e-book by writer and consultant Gwen Bell . While its primarily about building a small business from the ground up, theres one quote in the book that really struck a chord with me, as it relates to all businesses and the way we talk to customers: The priority of running a business is to help your customers meet their needs, while staying in alignment with your principles.  Help your customers meet their needs...  Pretty obvious, right? But how often do we get so caught up in promoting the features and talking points of a product, service or loyalty program, that we forget to address a basic premise: how does what Im selling meet the needs of my customer? The first step in answering that question is figuring out what your customers really want from you. Remember: Its not about what youre selling, its about why theyre buying. Do they want you to save them money? Make their lives easier? Sexier? More fulfilling? Less stressful? More fun? Until you can determine what basic customer need youre meeting, or customer problem youre solving, you should put your advertising, social media and loyalty efforts on the back burner. Because how you answer the needs question is one of the most important factors in determining the communications strategy and tactics that will work best for you. About the second part of that quote:  staying in alignment with your principles . Weve all worked for clients whose key guiding principle is lets sell more stuff so we can make more money. But ideally, the products or services youre selling and marketing are integrated with the companys core purpose, its raison d'etre . For me, the gold standard for a company thats in perfect alignment with its principles is Patagonia, the purveyor of all things outdoors. Go to their Web site and click on the Company Info link youll see in big bold type Patagonias mission statement: Our Reason for Being Build the best product, cause no unnecessary harm, use business to inspire and implement solutions to the environmental crisis. Is that beautiful or what? Short, principled and to the point. And it fits perfectly with the products Patagonia sells and the customer needs they meet. Now I know that not every company is going to have such a noble mission, but I dont think its a coincidence that so many successful and highly regarded companies do. From Starbucks to Southwest , each one has a set of rules they do business by which has helped them become leaders in their particular business vertical. What about the companies you work with and forare they helping your customers meet their needs while aligning with a core set of principles? ]] I was recently reminded of a series of commercials that ran for the American beer Michelob Lite in the 1980s. Based around the syrupy jingle Who says you cant have it all?, the spots showed a certain demographic, at the time called yuppies, who supposedly did have the whole enchilada. As Hugh MacLeod points outs in his humorous, do-the-work-you-love book Evil Plans: The campaign for Michelob Lite beer tritely asked the question Who says you cant love your work and leave it too? as a sly substitute for the question Who says you cant get great, satisfying taste in a beer that also happens to be kind of light and watery. Some of the other themes in the campaign included the head-scratching " Who says you can't be somebody and still be you?" as well as the paean to lost youth "Who says you can't have pinstripes and rock ? and roll? " The answer in every case was an emphatic  Oh yes you can!  (You can check out one of the commercials here .) The Who says you cant have it all? ad campaign only had a shelf-life of about a year and in hindsight its not hard to see why. At its core, the brand was making a statement thats just not believable. In beer, as in life, there are usually trade-offs involved. And while a beer with less calories may be a good thirst quencher, it probably doesnt qualify as a super premium beer, as Michelob Lite liked to refer to itself. Today, there are more than few brands who exhibit this same over-promise, under deliver behavior (Im talking to you, banking sector). But there are several companies and brands that are doing an excellent job of nailing down their own unique market positioning by promoting a product benefit that resonates and separates them from their competitors. A few examples: *Wendys. Im the opposite of a fast food fan, but Im almost tempted to stop by a Wendys. Their new ad campaign is centered around whats called Wendys Way with an emphasis on high quality ingredients. Check out their nifty Web site where you can tour a picturesque 3-D farmland that brings to life the Wendys point of difference. Does Burger King or McDonalds use the same fresh ingredients? Probably. But for now at least, Wendys has seized and owns the fresh mantle. * Apple. Ive seen several of the new genius commercials, and Im less than impressed, as are the critics . After years of superior advertising, Apple has put out a series of corny slice-of-life spots about an employee from their Genius Bar assisting customers in need. Yet, while the execution feels very Dell/Best Buy-ish, they do point out a huge point-of-difference that Apple has over these competitorsthey offer great customer service from helpful employees who really know their stuff. * Meijers . In the supermarket category, I could tell you about the superior shopping experience and quality of a Whole Foods or Wegmans. But instead Id like to talk about convenience. As reported by the Zing! blog , the Meijer chain has set up a radical new way to redeem coupons. Open an account at their m-rewards Web site and you can enter all the coupons you want online before you go to the store. Then, just enter your mobile phone number at check-out and  your coupons will be miraculously applied to your purchase . Its a frictionless way to pass along savings, without all the clipping and paperwork. One final note on Michelob Lite. While their You cant have it all spots failed, so has virtually every other campaign theyve tried over the years. (Remember,  Light up the night ? I didnt think so.) Ill again let Hugh MacLeod weigh in on this less than successful brand: Twenty-plus years after declaring their ability to be all things to all people, that brand is still struggling, trying to be somethinganythingother than unexceptional. What about the companies, brands and loyalty programs you work for and with: Do they offer a real point-of-difference? Do your customers see them as exceptional? ]] 0 0 1 511 2915 MENY 24 6 3420 14.0 I recently reserved a car online for a pending vacation and without much searching went right to Avis. I have a soft spot for the company having worked as creative lead on the Avis U.S. advertising account from 2006 through 2008, including their top-tier loyalty program, the Avis Chairmans Club . Rather than go directly to the Avis Web site to make the reservation, I went though a new program I had just joined called Geico Privileges . Its basically a tack-on discount program for Geico auto insurance customers and in this case I was promised a discount of up to 25% on my next Avis rental. From the Geico Privileges Web site I connected to a co-branded area of the Avis site. There, I chose my location, added my discount code and booked a weekly rental. Not seeing a discount applied to the total, I initiated an online chat where I was informed Id get my discount at the time of the rental. There was just one issue. When I picked-up my car, I looked at my new paperwork and didnt see a discount, just the regular price. I inquired about it and was told by an ever-smiling Avis agent that the location I was standing in did not and had never offered this type of discount. My next step: a phone call to Avis customer service where I was informed that if I looked at the teeny-tiny block of mouse type at the bottom of the original estimate I would find the words:  Offer is available only for rentals at participating locations . And sorry, but this location was not participating. When I complained that this should have been spelled out at the time I made the reservationafter all, I input the discount code at the Avis site and indicated my pick-up-locationmy customer service rep blamed Geico. She said they never should have offered me the discount in the first place. At which point I asked to talk to a manager. The new perception of customer service in a Zappos world. The funny thing is in todays digital world we often expect an immediate resolution to our customer service problems. Recent online service issues I had with Eddie Bauer and yes, the reigning champs of a superior customer experience, Zappos, had me thinking we had reached a new paradigm in customer service. If things werent right, by golly, they got fixedand pronto. So I was a little taken aback by the initial response I got from Avis. On top of this, it was recently reported that Avis has dropped their tag line of nearly five decades, We Try Harder for the mystifying Its Your Space. It apparently has something to do with the various ways businesspeople use their cars while on the road. ( Note to Avis: is that really a point-of-difference between you and other rental car companies?) It all had me wondering if customer service was now a secondary consideration of the new Avis. Had they decided, like so many airlines, that it was all about the ability to offer the cheapest price, customer service be damned? Well, alls well that ends well. My customer service rep relayed the problem to manager Thomas Mayfield at Avis headquarters in Tulsa who promptly called me. With sincerity, he apologized for the mix-up, said the Avis site should have warned me I wouldnt be getting a discountits something theyre working onand offered me a $50 credit for my next rental, good at any location, including the one I was just at. Good job, Avis. Maybe an old dog can learn new tricks. This post was written by vacation-loving creative director and writer Tom Rapsas . ]] I just finished the book $100 Start-Up by Chris Guillebeau. Its a smart, inspiring read and a must for anyone thinking about starting a small business. Guillebeau has pulled together a ton of really interesting examples of start-ups that have made it, many with a minimal upfront investment. There was one passage that I found especially interesting and it related to success. Through his studies, Guillebeau determined that most successful small companies had a few attributes in common. He then came up with a simple formula to explain it: Passion Skill + Usefulness = Success This got me thinkingthere are several areas of business and marketing where this equation could be applied, including most loyalty initiatives. Because while its possible to come up with a great idea thats of value to customers ( Usefulness ), the same effort and expertise ( Passion Skill ) must be put into its execution and promotion for the initiative to be a success. Here are three loyalty and CRM-related efforts that I believe are hitting on all cylinders, providing a valuable resource for customers, while backed by the passion and skill that lead to a successful outcome. 1. Push a button, get a pizza. In a recent issue of Trendwatching , a customer loyalty initiative from Dubai in the United Arab Emirates caught my eye. Its for a standalone pizza shop called Red Tomato Pizza , and theyve developed a truly amazing way to increase sales from existing customers. The pizzeria has a loyalty club and it recently sent all its members a Red Tomato Pizza VIP Fridge magnet. Let me tell you, its no ordinary magnet with the pizza shops phone number on it. Its a high-tech gadget that offers the ultimate in convenience, allowing you to About the size of a small box of matches, the magnet is shaped like a pizza box with a lid on it. Open the lid and theres a button inside you can push for hunger. The device then uses Bluetooth functionality to connect to the Internetand automatically orders your favorite pizza to be delivered to your registered address. No picking up the phone. No clicking on to the Internet. Just push a button on your fridge. (Check out the cool demo .) 2. Conquering the fear of flying. Miles, schmiles. The airlines need to come up with new and unique ways to attract and retain customers and I think Virgin Atlantic Airlines in the UK has a brilliant one. Its a unique effort to capture an underserved part of the flying marketthose who fear flyingand turn them into regular Virgin Atlantic customers. The airline has developed a program called Flying Without Fear , including a comprehensive Web site that claims to be the Internets biggest resource for fearful flyers. There you can find videos, success stories and support networks for dealing with flying phobia. Live workshops are available and theres an active online community discussion on overcoming the fear. (Sample passage:  I was able to manage the flight without valium and without tears! ) For iPhone users, there even a mobile app to assist you, that includes a personal greeting from Sir Richard Branson himself, answers to common questions from a pilot, and an in-flight tutorial that can guide you as to whats going on during each portion of your flight. The program claims a success rate in excess of 98%, and Im guessing Virgin Atlantic has attracted a plethora of new and loyal customers because of it. 3. A belly-full of rewards . Belly is a US-based digital loyalty program that allows c ustomers to sign up online and automatically start earning points at over 1,000 small businesses. But what really sets the program apart are its tech-y nature and unique rewards. Each p articipating merchant is equipped with an iPad that customers can use to sign in and track their points. No membership cards or key fobs necessary. But for me, the coolest aspect of the program is the fun, seldom monetary, often wacky rewards. For instance, you can: Earn cut the line privileges at several coffee shops and grocers. Get a sandwich named after you at a local deli. Earn a punch the owner in the stomach reward (!?) at a comic book shop. Get a 10-minute all you can eat pass at famed Chicago sausage shop Devil Dawgs . How about youhave you noticed any new loyalty or CRM initiatives of late with the passion, skill and usability to be a success? This post by writer and creative director Tom Rapsas originally appeared on Loyalty Truth . ]] The Mets' mascot "Mr. Met". I m a long time fan of the baseball team the New York Mets . Im also a long-time admirer of Richard Branson . So as I was reading an interview with Sir Richard the other day, it got me thinking: could his advice on delivering a superior customer experience help turn around my struggling Mets. Branson: The key is to set realistic customer expectations, and then not to just meet them, but to exceed thempreferably in unexpected and helpful ways. As a baseball fan, the last thing you want to hear is that your team is rebuilding. After all, no one wants to wait four or five years to be a playoff or World Series contender, even if the reality is your team is comprised mostly of middling and unproven ballplayers. But if youre in top management for the Mets, why set realistic customer expectations when you can promise to exceed them? Witness Mets COO Jeff Wilpon who recently said : I think well be competitive this year. Theres a lot of ways to get to the postseason now, with the extra playoffs and everything. Sounds to me like hes talking about a postseason appearance and as a fan, thats just what I want to hear. Realistic? Absolutely not. But if the Mets do make the playoffs, it will more than cover Bransons advice of exceeding my expectations in unexpected ways. Branson: One way to exceed expectations is through your front-line employeeseveryone who works with customers. For the Mets, the front office is more or less invisible to the customersso the front-line employees are really the ballplayers themselves. And now that were in the off-season, Im glad to say they are exceeding expectationsor were. The Mets held their annual holiday party at Citi Field last month and bussed in 100 kids from Far Rockaway, Queens, an area especially hard hit by Hurricane Sandi. In attendance: Cy Young award winner R.A. Dickey and the always photogenic Mr. Met. And recently pitcher Jon Neise toured the storm-ravaged area of Long Beach with his beautiful fiance in tow. Then, theres Met all-star David Wright who has also been pitching it to Sandy relief efforts and has been making public appearances for his own foundation which provides aid and assistance toward the health, emotional development, and education for children in need. Great stuff. But then, true to form, within a three-day period the Mets traded away fan favorite Dickey while announcing they were raising ticket prices for the 2013 season. So now fans can pay even more to see a less competitive team. Branson: Consistently over-deliver on your promisesyou will leave your competitors struggling to catch up. Like Bransons airline biz, Major League Baseball is a hyper-competitive vertical. Especially if, like the Mets, you reside in the National League East division. Washington made the playoffs last year and keeps adding players, Philly is a recent world champ with an imposing pitching rotation, and the Atlanta Braves are always tough. Yet, the GM of the Mets, Sandy Alderson , recently said the Mets 2013 roster will look similar to the way it did at the end of last year. This would be the same team that had one of the worst records in the National League during the second half of 2012, and finished a full 24 games out of first place. Which makes Wilpons playoff promise look even more like a pipe dream. But, as they say in baseball, hope springs eternal and every MLB team starts with the same 0-0 record. But by trading Dickey and with no movement toward signing any veteran ballplayers, I fear the only ones struggling to catch up will be the Mets. Heres a thought: Im sure Branson is flush with cash after his recent sale of 49% of Virgin Atlantic to Delta Airlines. Im not sure if the Wilpons are selling, but they appear to be under some severe financial constraints. So what do you say Richard, why not consider buying a baseball team? I have a feeling youd do a whole lot better in exceeding customer expectations that the current Mets owners. ]] 0 0 1 356 2031 MENY 16 4 2383 14.0 Im being followed. I dont see them all the time, but I know theyre out there. Sometimes I catch them out of the corner of my eye and try not to look their way. Other times they just blatantly jump out in front of me and make themselves known. Im talking about banner ads. Because more and more lately I cant help but notice that some of the things I search for or look at on the Web are obviously noticing meand then following me to the other sites I visit. I had banner ads for the movie Les Miserables following me around the Web for about two weeks. A site called Christian Singles was on my tail for a month with ads popping up every time I went to the NY Times Web site. And lately, ads for the Fairmont hotel chain seem to be on every Web page I visit. Sometimes my connection to the banners is obvious. I did recently look up some rates on the Fairmont hotel site. And I had checked out the reviews at the Le Miz movie site. But Christian Singles ? Im happily married and have never identified myself as Christianbut figure this may be due to a spirituality blog site I write for and visit now and then. Are they following you too? Then you probably noticed that at least some of these banner ads have a small icon titled Ad Choices in the lower right hand corner. When you click on this icon, youre brought to a Google page with the following message: The AdChoices symbol appears on web pages and ads to let you know when information about your interests or demographics may have been collected or used to show you ads  whats known as interest-based advertising. In other words, Im being cookied and followed. And while Im not totally against this attempt to put interest-based ads in front of me, it does have the feeling of a car salesman following me off the lot after Ive taken a peek at the new models. Enough already, if Im really interested Ill come back. It has also struck me that the technology is pretty dumb. Already a Verizon FiOS TV customer, I visited their Web site to find out how to connect my DVD player to my TV set top boxand then had banner ads for the FiOS Triple Play, at a super low price, following me around for weeks. But like it or not, I supposed this new technology is here to say. At least until Google figures out a way to read my e-mails and offer up advertising related to the content of my personal messages. Oh wait a second, they already do that. ]] 0 0 1 499 2849 MENY 23 6 3342 14.0 0 I was recently sifting through some marketing trade articles I had collected and came across this compelling quote from Edward Boches, the chief creative guru at the Mullen agency. Its about the difference between good advertising and great advertising: Good advertising tells you what a product does and why you should buy it. Great advertising expresses what a brand stands for and invites you to share in its beliefs. On the same day while reading DMNews, I noticed this strategic insight from Aimia Vice President of Knowledge Development Rick Ferguson: Theres a difference between capturing a customers wallet and capturing his heart...brands that integrate emotional components into their loyalty strategy have more opportunities for retaining their customers and expanding their value. It struck me that these were really two versions of the same idea: whether youre trying to attract or retain customers, you need to strike an emotional chordyou need a message that customers can relate to and believe in. You need a good story. Every product, service and loyalty program has a story to tell. The film director John Sayles once said that he believed his purpose in life was finding and telling the stories that move me. He believed that the stories that moved him also had the power to move others. I believe thats part of our job as marketersto find the story inherent in the brands we work forstories that we believe in and can tell to others. Its easy to see that some brands, often by the nature of their product, have great stories to tell. Take Nike and last years TV spot called  Find Your Greatness , which showcases the efforts of a pudgy lad jogging down a country road. The message: if he can do it, I can do it (with the help of a pair of Nike running shoes, of course). As Boche points out Nikes  advertising doesnt push shoes; it encourages, inspires and promises individual achievement.  And for years, even decades now theyve been doing this with the stories they tell. But what about the less interesting verticals and brands? Or loyalty programs? Do they really have stories to tell? Well, here is a recent brand example that really stood out to me, from a category I didnt expect it from: beer. With the market so flooded with craft brews these days, it can be difficult to separate one beer from the other. And even though Im a self-proclaimed beer connoisseur, Im often stumped by the sheer variety of choices at my local beer market, often choosing beers on the attractiveness of their label or their geographic location. But while doing a little research, I recently stumbled upon the Web site of one of my favorite craft brews, Sierra Nevada, and found they had an amazing tale to tell. Now the key to a good story is the telling and Sierra Nevada has a beauty about their rich heritage. Its featured in a short online video on their home page and if they gave out Academy Awards for this kind of thing, it would get the best short in the brand storytelling category. Another example is the excellent story told by the leading loyalty program... wait a second ...I cant think of a single good example of a loyalty program with a really good story behind it. So let me put the question to you: does your loyalty program or a program you know about have a good story to tell? If yes, let me know. This post, by Tom Rapsas, originally appeared on Loyalty Truth . ]] Do you remember when Seth Godin first released Permission Marketing ? At the time I had just joined Frequency Marketing and I can recall my boss Pat LaPointe handing me the book and telling me it was a must-read. I gobbled it up and soon after helped the company build permission and dialogue into its communications offerings. Back then, our goal was to make every piece of loyalty communications as relevant as possible, striving for the holy grail of one-to-one marketing. But limited to direct mail and e-mail, our messaging wasnt so much one-to-one as it was one-to-many. It was just too cost prohibitive to personalize every mailing, so we had to bucket customers into specific messaging streams. Of course, with the advent of social media, achieving a true dialogue with customers through one-to-one communications has actually become doable. Via leading social sites like Facebook and Twitter, you now have the opportunity to truly engage with customers in real-time. In fact, most of your customers expect it. Yet it recently struck me that most marketers play social media on defense. When it comes to engaging with customers in a true customer dialogue, theyre in a reactionary mode, not a proactive one. So the company-customer dialogue works like this: A company has a person or team assigned to monitor the social space. They search for tweets or posts that call out the brand or product by name, and when they spot one, they spring into action. Most of the time its to address a problem or customer care issue that has surfaced. Sometimes its to say thanks for a compliment. But either way, its all about playing defense. When it comes to offense, for most marketers the social media game plan is to blast out Facebook posts and tweets with promo hashtags, then wait for customers to respond. But theres a vital piece missing. The one-to-one interaction or dialogue that recognizes me as a valued customer. I believe theres a huge missed opportunity here, and its the chance to proactively engage with best customers via social medianot because something is wrong, or because you have a new promotion or product to pushbut because you want to engage them in a relevant dialogue to show these customers you really care about them. For example, what if American Airlines reached out to me after a flight and asked me how things went? Or if my local Bonefish seafood restaurant let me know my favorite fresh seafood dish was now available? Or the Doubletree hotel let me know they were glad my family was visiting again and I could have a late check-out? It would be possibleif these chains had made the effort to collect my personal social media information and had it on file. They could then use their massive databases to cross-reference my activities and personal preferences to proactively reach out to me via Facebook and Twitter. I was recently reminded why this was so important by the godfather of permission marketing and dialogue himself, Seth Godin. In one of his recent blog posts he wrote: Dialogue leads to connection, which leads to trust which leads to engagement. Godin also points out that in todays over-saturated communications world it can be exceedingly difficult to hold a dialogue, yet the attempt to engage with a customer is demonstrably better than the alternative. Because the alternative is still the mass-blasting of communications, even if the vehicles have changed from on-air media to social media. So whats holding you up? Are you using social media to hold a relevant dialogue and engage with your most valued customers? If not, why not? This post was written by Tom Rapsas and originally appeared on Loyalty Truth , April 15, 2013. ]] 0 0 1 549 3133 MENY 26 7 3675 14.0 In a recent DM News article titled Big Data Must Create Big Experiences , direct marketing vet Ernan Roman pointed out that for all the data thats apparently being collected, marketers dont seem to be doing much with it. And judging by my e-mail inbox, I couldnt agree more. An appraisal of the brand and loyalty marketing e-mails Im receiving reveals scant few that mention my relationship with the company or that address my past buying behavior. Thats a serious omission, because research shows that if a company provides me with personally relevant information, Im much more likely to make a purchase. The unfulfilled promise of big data also came up during a recent DM News roundtable . While there were a few on the panel who paid lip service to combining research, analytics, and transaction data...to produce more tailored communications, the conversation was long on talk and short on examples. However, there was one roundtable statement that rang true, and I think it sums up the current state of big data. It came from a straight-shooter by the name of Ilana Rabinowitz, the CMO at a company called Lion Brand Yarns, who said: I think that for most small and midsize companies Big Data is irrelevant. Its like the Wild, Wild West of information. You cant use it, you dont have people who can analyze it, and if its there, you dont know how to get to it. A damning but, I believe, true claim. And the concerns about big data extend into the loyalty marketing business, as well. A recent report in Retail Wire asks the pointed question:  Why Aren't More Companies Connecting Big Data Dots for Loyalty Programs?  The online pub cited a serious lack of effort on the part of marketers, coming to the conclusion that: While most respondents feel the need to engage customers based on their needs and expectations, they're not leveraging the data in a way that maximizes the potential loyalty offered by customers. To use a football analogy, big data feels like the first round draft pick who has tremendous potentialbut who hasnt yet proven himself on the field. The coach isnt quite sure how and when to use him, so for now hes relegated to the bench. He may play in the future, but when is anyones guess. Is there a better way to personalize customer communications? Since it appears a lot of marketers havent yet gotten a handle on how to use the voluminous amount of data theyre collecting, maybe its time to go old-school. I again quote DM sage Ernan Roman who made this astute observation: Customers, both B2B and B2C, are sophisticated enough to recognize that to receive increasingly relevant offers, they must share detailed preference information. And if youre not able to leverage big data, the best way to compile accurate customer preference data is through surveys, both online and off. With this approach, you start a dialogue with customers asking them to share their wants, needs and expectations. This allows you to continue the dialogue by serving up relevant, personalized communications featuring the products, services and benefits that interest your customers most. For me, this idea is an e-mail blast from the past. Several years ago, my former employer Frequency Marketing had a major client who committed the time and dollars to collect customer information via surveysand it allowed us to send out personalized, relevant e-mails. The result was a sharp increase in incremental sales and customer share-of-wallet. Are customer preference surveys the sexiest, most cutting edge way to personalize customer communications? Probably not. But until big data gets its act together, it may be all weve got. This post previously appeared on Loyalty Truth , May 29, 2013. ]] There was recently some ginormous news in the ad industry where the Publicis and Omnicom holding companies announced a $35 billion mega-merger. But perhaps most surprising wasnt that the merger took place, but how it was positioned. As reported by the online pub Digiday : (Omnicom) CEO John Wren explained the merger, saying that gathering, sorting and using data had become a fundamental part of agency work, and combining would help the two agencies do the job better. The new mega agency...would be able to use data at a scale that would put them on par with data rich companies such as Facebook and Google. Which raises the question: will the merger of a bunch of ad agencies really result in a better use of big data? Not everyone, yours truly included, is convinced that bigger means better. Dave Morgan, the CEO of Simulmedia and a leading voice in the ad technology sector, remarked: I think its a total misdirection to think that you can leverage the scale and advantages of big data if youre bigger. Quite the opposite. Doubts about the effectiveness of big agencies getting a handle on big data were also expressed by Jon Morris, founder and CEO of independent digital marketing agency Rise Interactive, on the pages of DMNews . I think Morris nailed it when he questioned whether the mega-merger portends that anything different will be happening in the future: Both of them already have access to so much data that theyre not leveraging. So how is merging and becoming a larger enterprise going to help them out more? Its basically two identical companies merging together. Not one person can point to the technology that Omnicom has or the technology that Publicis has that would speak to how this makes sense from a Big Data standpoint. Meanwhile, I continue to be surrounded by dumb data. Personally, what Im seeing most frequently on my computer screen lately isnt the much ballyhooed big data, but what I like to call dumb data. While some of the banner ads I see may be aiming for the new digital nirvana of showing the right message to the right person at the right time, what I most often notice are the stalking ads. I wrote here a few months ago about various companies following me around the Web after I had visited their sites, from a sneaker company to an online MBA school. For instance, back in February I visited the Web site for the Broadway show Pippin. I bought tickets to the show at the theaters ticketing site and saw it in back in March. Several months later, I am still seeing Pippin banners popping up everywhere I go. As the online pub Digiday recently opined, these follow-you-everywhere banners are becoming the new equivalent of the pop-up ad. Theyre mildly annoying, but judging by their widespread and continued use, they seem to be working. The only danger, Digiday correctly points out, is their overuse: The industry just needs to hope that consumers dont become so frustrated with seeing the same pair of shoes for two weeks that they decide to do something about it. Otherwise itll only have itself to blame. Will the new Publicis-Omnicom entity be able to better figure out how to put big data to usenot just to attract new customers but retain and grow existing ones? Personally, Ill believe it when I see it. And with a new set of banner ads from a hotel chain starting to follow me around the Web, Ill be glad when they do. How about you? Do you think there are any agencies, companies or brands who have a real handle on effectively using big data? Can you cite any examples? This post originally appeared on Loyalty Truth , August 2, 2013. ]] 0 0 1 544 3101 MENY 25 7 3638 14.0 There was a recent story in the New York Times business section that caught me eye. It was about the giant US-based marketing and data company Acxiom and the news that, in the interest of transparency, they were now giving consumers a peek behind the curtainand letting you see just what data they had collected on you and your family. According to the article, Acxiom has amassed details on the household makeup, financial means, shopping preferences and leisure pursuits of a majority of adults in the United States. This data includes everything from your income, family status (married? kids?), to the car you drive and house you live in. Plus, and heres where it gets interesting, your recent purchase categories like plus-size clothing or sports products; and household interests like golf, dogs, text-messaging, cholesterol-related products or charities. So what does Acxiom know about you? Its easy to find out. The company just launched a free Web site called AbouttheData.com that reveals all. And even though I work in marketing myself, I was curious. What data do they have? Is it correct? Do they really know about my family and all our past purchases? Is the data then evident in the advertising materials I receive? After all, the primary purpose of collecting this data is to tailor offers that are relevant to me and my family. So I went to the Axciom, answered a few simple questions that ensured I was looking at my data and not somebody elses, and glimpsed the same vital marketing information that direct marketers and list buyers see. The result of my query? A mixed bag. While Acxiom knew the ages of my family members and my income, they had greatly overestimated the income of my wife. And while they knew the make and model of our primary vehicle, my home details were missing even though we had moved into a new place well over a year ago. When it came to purchase categories, they did nail several that were big in our household, including pet supplies. (With nine cats, were in crazy cat lady territory.) They also called out the womens fashion category, no surprise with a pair of fashionistas in my home. (Which helps explain the nearly daily fashion catalogs that wind up in our mailbox, many from marketers weve never purchased from.) But according to a recent report in the online pub Digiday, Acxiom did a lot better with my data than they did with others. Among their staffers who checked out the site, one was incorrectly identified as a military veteran, another household was incorrectly flagged as having children, while a third person who doesnt own a car was listed as having their auto insurance due the following month. Their conclusion: The tool allows consumers to see what type of data is being used to target ads and offers to them, but it also highlights just how inaccurate that information is. One could easily see the site as a way to convince people they shouldnt be alarmed by data brokers because who they think you are is far different from who you really are. Does Axciom have your data right? You can find out here . This post originally appeared on Loyalty Truth , September 19, 2013. ]] 0 0 1 480 2741 MENY 22 6 3215 14.0 When I read the recent headline  Only 16% of Consumers Redeem Loyalty Rewards  on the pages of Direct Marketing, I was taken aback. Are loyalty programs really that ineffective these days? If so, thats not good, because if your customers arent redeeming for rewards, theyre likely not seeing any value in your program. The 16% redemption figure was one of the key findings in a recent report from Forrester Research titled The State of Loyalty Programs 2013, which was based on surveys of executives at 50 member companies of Loyalty360. A Forrester analyst suggests the results signal a movement away from traditional loyalty programs. Loyalty marketing is on the cusp of an evolution, says Forrester analyst Emily Collins, who directed the study. There's a shift in focus from the idea that loyalty is all about transactions and discounts. In the future it needs to be more about engagement and emotion. Im feeling a sense of deja vu and maybe you are, too. Almost three years ago, I penned an article titled  The Death of Loyalty Rewards As We Know Them ?  for Loyalty Truth , but in actuality this movement away from transactions and discounts toward engagement and emotion goes back much further than that. I would argue that the idea of engagement was first introduced as permission marketing by Seth Godin way back in 1999. At the firm Bill Hanifin and I once worked at, Frequency Marketing, we took this idea and ran with it in the early-2000s, promoting dialogue between customers and companies and stressing the need for engagement across multiple customer touch points. Thats why this recommendation from the same article on The State of Loyalty Programs 2013, sounds positively retro, at least until you hit the words in bold type: Embrace channels featuring two-way interaction . The top three channels used by marketers in communicating with club members are email, websites and Web portals, and call centers. Forrester strongly recommends that businesses begin dialogs with loyal customers via mobile and social media . The addition of these two new ways to communicate with customers are the fresh components in the mix, as the way we engage with customers continues to expand. And its interesting to note that, while not mentioned in this article, old-school direct mail continues to be one of the best ways to interact with many segments of the population. Theres one more passage in the story had me smiling, as it also brought me back to the past, and it had to do with the nature of rewards. Again, what is being passed as a current recommendation sounds dated to this loyalty vet: Balance the reward mix with personalized offers that present customers with one-of-a-kind experiences, such as concert tickets or cooking lessons. Its something we at Frequency Marketing called experiential rewards, a phrase that John Bartold (or was it Mike Charron or Tom Parker?) coined a decade ago and has been in the loyalty marketplace for years. But just like the emphasis on engagement, maybe everything old is new again. Or as the saying goes, the more things change, the more they stay the same. This post, by Tom Rapsas , was previously published at Loyalty Truth , October 23, 2013. ]] I read a headline in the trade pub Ad Age recently that instantly grabbed my attention and got me looking for the details. Heres what it said: " Verizon tracks sports fans after the game. Precision Insights Division can tell a team if attendees heeded sponsors messages." Call me dim-witted, but at first glance I was scratching my head. How would Verizon know that after attending a NY Jets football game and seeing a sign for Buffalo Wild Wings, I then went there for a cold beer and post-game snack? And then it quickly dawned on me. Of course, they know where I am Ive got a global positioning device sitting in my pocket, aka a cell phone . The program is run by Precision Market Insights , a division of Verizon Wireless. Looking at their Web site their mission is pretty straight forward: use actionable insights...(to) provide unprecedented 360-degree views to help you understand your target audiences, engage them more precisely and ultimately transact with them more profitably. In the case of tracking stadium fans and their behavior post-game, the site says the idea is to help teams and arenas know more about event attendees, and connect the dots between sponsor messages at the game and who went to that sponsors location later. The company has already run this type of program for the NBAs Phoenix Suns in conjunction with advertisers like Jack in the Box. Is this cool or creepy? After all, it appears the sports patron doesnt know theyre being tracked. And its not like Foursquare where Im voluntarily offering up my geographic location. I can see how some might have concerns with privacy issues, but lets face itas soon as you turn on your cell phone, your wireless carrier knows where you are at all times. So to this direct marketer it seems fairly innocuous that Verizon Wireless is providing this information behind-the-scenes to upscale fast food joints. That said, I can see how this could get some privacy advocates riled up. It also got me wondering, if there might be a bigger marketing play for Precision Market Insights: Might this service have implications for loyalty marketing? For instance, what if they got me, the customer, to opt-in to being tracked instead of doing it surreptitiously? And in exchange for my opting-in, I received a discount on my wireless service and/or a special deal from whatever retailer or restaurant I visited the moment I walked through the door? Im betting this ideathe real-time delivery of offers via your wireless carrierwill be coming to a market near you soon. And personally, if Buffalo Wild Wings wants to send me a free beer with purchase after I suffer through the next Jets loss, I wont mind Verizon Wireless tracking me one bit. This post originally appeared on Loyalty Truth , December 6, 2013. ]] 