 The following is a press release issued 1/14/13.  Please feel free to share. January 14, 2012 Contact: Paul Ellis Phone:  845-469-7563 FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE Air Pirates Voted Best Performing Troupe of 2012 For the sixth time The Air Pirates Radio Theater was voted the Best Performing Troupe in the Hudson Valley by the Times Herald Record Readers Poll. The Air Pirates completed their sixth season at the Lycian Centre (now Sugar Loaf Performing Arts Center) and are now planning the seventh to open in March. As of now the highly popular live radio comedy troupe has no home. This is a real honor for us, says Paul Ellis, writer and director of the company, We perform for a truly appreciative audience and we just have fun. The audience has a great time with these comic plays and allowing them to participate makes for a great evening. Audiences are returning on a regular basis for the next episodes of mystery, western and science fiction. What these actors do is not easy. At anytime they are playing up to five roles a night. When all is said and done the actors fill the stage with exciting and funny performances, said Ellis. The new season of Air Pirates was planned to begin March 16 th at the SLPAC in Sugar Loaf, however; the Board of Directors has decided not to allow the Air Pirates to rent the space. The company has been performing at the Pavilion since its beginning and now we have to find a new home, said Paul Ellis, Producer of the Air Pirates. There was a falling out with the Board of Directors over content in a previous show and it seems censorship is at the core of the discrepancy. Not having a place to perform interferes with the companys ability to secure sponsorships and advertisers and may cause some problems with funding. The Air Pirates have been funded by both the County Tourism Grant and decentralized funding from the NY State Council on the Arts. They also have a following of loyal supporters evidenced by the unprecedented sixth time they have been selected Best Of by the readers of the Times Herald Record. The Pirates are not done, they intend to find a new home for their live broadcasts and will be back this season. Anyone who can help the Air Pirates Radio Theater find a home please call 845-469-7563 or visit www.airpirateradio.com . Brian Nieves, Alan Andrews and Marylee Shorr in the Air Pirates production of It Aint Over til the Fat Lady Swi ngs ### Alan Andrews Basso For Hire ]] http://spicie.com/amanda-fox/im-secretely-wonder-woman-and-you-can-be-a-superhero-too/ No power in the 'verse can stop me. Alan ]] Jenny Jenny is a Walker Coonhound.  She is about 8-1/2 years old, and has lived with us since she was 1.  Her likes include barking and howling at absolutely ANYTHING, marathon naps, having her hipbones scratched, and chasing our cats around the house.  Her dislikes are loud noises (ironic, I know, considering the howling), vacuum cleaners, and wet feet.  She's never really cared for playing with toys. ? Billy Billy is part dachshund, part fox terrier (or maybe Jack Russell), with maybe a little Basset Hound thrown in for good measure.  If you asked most grade schoolers to draw a picture of a dog, you'd probably get something that looks an awful lot like Billy.  He has lived with us for a little over half a year, and is probably 4 or 5 years old.  Billy's likes include snuggling, barking at meal times, patrolling "his" backyard like a cop on a beat, and playing with toys.  His dislikes include not being the center of attention, and being made to move from wherever he's napping. As I mentioned, Billy loves playing with his toys.  When he's done playing with them,  he leaves them in the corner of the living room, under our baby grand piano, which makes it a hassle when trying to tidy up. Saturday, Billy was lying on the love seat in our living room with my lovely wife, Lenna.  Billy was doing some serious snuggling, and loving every moment of it.  Jenny decided she wanted to curl up on the love seat, too.  Unfortunately, the love seat just wasn't big enough for all three of them up there, and Billy wasn't willing to scooch over to make room. Jenny and Billy stared at each other for a minute or so, and then Jenny appeared to give up, turning away.  "Appeared" is the key word here.  What she actually did was go under the piano, grab one of Billy's favorite toys (a bit of heavily chewed rope), bring it into the middle of the room, and start chewing on it. Billy took the bait, and jumped off the couch to lay claim to his treasured rope toy.  He pounced on it and took it from Jenny's mouth (he's literally half her size).  As he took it from her, Jenny looped around him and jumped up onto the love seat next to my wife, curled up and was firmly entrenched before Billy ever realized he'd been set up. New tricks learned:  Old dog - 1 New lessons learned:  New dog - 1 ]] Originally posted on Booksellers Without Borders BWOB "Kolony," by Glynn Burridge (Calusa Bay Publications, 2008) is described on the front cover as "a novel of the Seychelles." I undertook my assigned mission of reading this book with boyish glee, as it appears to be rigt up my alley: Pirates, unidentified monsters, deeds of daring, etc. Burridge paints beautiful imagery of the Seychelle Islands, which are north and slightly west of Madagascar, in the Indian Ocean. His love of the area is present, even throughout some of the more gruesome events depicted in "Kolony." The novel begins with a prologue, set in 1882 England, in which a young, aristocratic woman is wooed and then deceived, brutally raped and murdered by one Eric Liddle, who we learn is a pirate. Liddle's escape via ship ends the prologue. The first chapter takes place far away, on one of the Seychelle Islands, and depicts the human sacrifice of young boy by a mysterious man whose most distinguishing feature is an extremely long thumbnail, which has been filed on one side to almost razor sharpness. So we're clearly dealing with some bad folks, here. Burridge introduces us to his protagonist, Timothy Scully, at the beginning of the third chapter. Scully is returning to the Seychelles from the Far East, where he had been working as a diver (SCUBA, not Olympic). His return is prompted by the news that his fiancee has disappeared. Mystery, intrigue, and mayhem ensue. I'm not going to get into much more, if any, detail about the plot itself. My overall experience with the book was disappointing, unfortunately, for more than one reason. First of all, after the prologue, there is really no clear indication that the story has jumped forward to the 21st Century until well into the 2nd chapter. Nothing in the description of the characters in the human sacrifice episode gave me any clue that the story was no longer set in the late 1800s. In fact, we don't actually learn that little detail until about halfway through the entire book, which is over 600 pages long (paperback). That was more than a little annoying to me, because until thumbnail man reappeared, I had no idea why the first chapter was even in the book. Plotwise, it wasn't necessary as written. I also had difficulty keeping track of who was speaking throughout much of the story. Part of this may be related to publishing and printing choices, which I'll address shortly. But the main problem was Burridge's frequent habit of writing dialogue without beginning a new paragraph whenever changing speakers. If a writer is going to stray from that convention, he should at least throw in a "he said," or "she said," just to help the reader stay with him. There were several times when I had to back up almost an entire page just to retrace whose turn it was to speak. This next issue could either be attributed to Burridge, or perhaps to his publisher. I mentioned the dialog not being sufficiently broken up into paragraphs. But the paragraphs themselves were often difficult to identify. Usually, a book will indent the beginning of a paragraph, or skip a line, as I'm doing in this post. Sometimes both, but that's really overkill. Kolony does neither. The only indication that a new paragraph has begun is that the previous line of text does not reach all the way to the right hand margin. As with the dialogue issues, this sometimes made it very difficult to follow the story. More difficult than I would have thought, actually. There is quite a bit of action in Kolony, but something about Burridge's style made it very hard for me to follow it. Many times I read a passage thinking that the characters were standing within arm's length, only to find out later (through inferrence only) that they were in fact barely within earshot of each other. It certainly changes the dynamic of a situation to find out that, not only could two rivals not touch each other; they wouldn't have been able to have a successful rock fight. A few more points, and I'll be on my way... There was a little too much Deus ex machina for my taste. My favorite character was a dog. So many characters were revealed to be in league with "the bad guys" that it stopped being a revelation after a while, and more of a "okay, I was wondering when we were going to find out." The dog was really big. The good guys win, sort of. That was one awesome dog. Burridge's account of how the bad guys got to be the way they are did not make me suspend disbelief. In other words, throughout the entire novel, I was fully aware that I was "reading a book," and not experiencing a story. Big difference. One of the most badass dogs ever. The epilogue was in the form of a letter from one character to the protagonist. By the time I got to it, I didn't really even care that it was set in a script font that was almost too small to read. I really wanted to be able to recommend "Kolony." But I'm afraid that dog will eat me if I do. COMING ATTRACTIONS Next time I'll have a much more positive review, of Mira Grant's "Newsflesh" Trilogy. Until then, keep reading! Alan Andrews Basso for Hire? ? ]] To see the original post, and many other wonderful reviews and discussions of books, films, and television, please click through to www.booksellerswithoutbordersny.com .  Or feel free to read on... Joe Abercrombie's first novel, "The Blade Itself," is the first in his "The First Law" trilogy. US publication was in 2007. I don't know why I just recently found this series, but I'm glad I did. It's given me a well needed dose of Epic Fantasy while wondering if "A Song of Ice and Fire" will ever be finished. For a first novel, let alone a trilogy, Abercrombie really delivered. His characters are diverse and complex. From Jezel dan Luther, a haughty young noble who gradually learns more of the value of others, and himself, to Bayaz, the self-proclaimed "first of the Magi;" who is either a complete charlatan, or a centuries-old wizard. Then there is Logen Ninefingers, a Northman, also known as "the bloody nine." Here is truly a berserker with a conscience. A warrior who has lost everything, but has more to offer than he seems. One of his most intriguing characters, however, is Sand dan Glotka, a Superior for the Inquisition. In other words, he is one of the chief torturers in the kingdom. Glotka is an expert torturer partly because he has spent time on both sides of the torture chamber. His wrecked body reminds him constantly of the man he was, and the man he has become. Abercrombie's narrative flows whether he is portraying the political maneuverings of the Closed Council, a game of cards, a lovers' quarrel, or the mayhem of battle. This is epic fantasy/swords and sorcerers fare. The First Law trilogy consists of "The Blade Itself," "Before They are Hanged," and "The Last Argument of Kings." In my next entry, I will discuss both the second and third books. Highly recommended for any "Game of Thrones" or "The Lord of the Rings" fans. Alan Andrews Basso for Hire ]] Click here... http://www.copyblogger.com/digital-sharecropping/ Or, here's the full article by Sonia Simone... The Most Dangerous Threat to Your Online Marketing Efforts We have a great bookstore in my town  the kind of place you picture in your mind when you think of a great independent bookshop. Its perfect for browsing, with lots of comfy chairs to relax in. The books are displayed enticingly. Theres a little coffee shop so you can relax with an espresso. They get your favorite writers to come in for readings, so theres always a sense of event and excitement. They do everything right, and theyve always had plenty of customers. But they still closed their doors last year. No, not for the reasons you might think. It wasnt Amazon that killed them, or the proliferation of free content on the web, or the crappy economy. They closed the store because they were leasing their big, comfortable building ... and when that lease ran out, their landlord tripled the rent. Literally overnight, their business model quit working. Revenues simply wouldnt exceed costs. A decision made by another party, one they had no control over, took a wonderful business and destroyed it. And thats precisely what you risk every day you make your business completely dependent on another company. It might be Facebook. It might be eBay. It might be Google. Its called digital sharecropping, and it means youre building your business on someone elses land. And its a recipe for heartbreak and failure. Whats digital sharecropping, anyway? Digital sharecropping is a term coined by Nicholas Carr to describe a peculiar phenomenon of Web 2.0. One of the fundamental economic characteristics of Web 2.0 is the distribution of production into the hands of the many and the concentration of the economic rewards into the hands of the few. In other words, anyone can create content on sites like Facebook, but that content effectively belongs to Facebook. The more content we create for free, the more valuable Facebook becomes. We do the work, they reap the profit. The term sharecropping refers to the farming practices common after the U.S. Civil War, but its essentially the same thing as feudalism. A big landholder allows individual farmers to work their land, and takes most of the profits generated from the crops. The landlord has all the control. If he decides to get rid of you, you lose your livelihood. If he decides to raise his fees, you go a little hungrier. You do all the work and the landlord gets most of the profit, leaving you a pittance to eke out a living on. Well, were not subsistence farmers any more, and our work doesnt involve 12-hour days in grueling conditions. So is sharecropping still dangerous? It is, for a couple of reasons ... Landlords are fickle More and more small businesses are moving all of their marketing to sites like Facebook. Its local, its free (or at least cheap), and it makes businesses feel like theyre doing something cutting-edge. But what happens when Facebook thinks youve done something that violates their terms of service and deletes your account? Or changes the way youre allowed to talk with your customers? Facebook is a particularly fast-changing platform, but its not the only one. An entire industry has sprung up based on trying to figure out what Googles going to do tomorrow, both as a search engine and as an advertising platform. If youre relying on Facebook or Google to bring in all of your new customers, youre sharecropping. Youre hoping the landlord will continue to like you and support your business, but the fact is, the landlord has no idea who you are and doesnt actually care. Landlords go away The other problem with sharecropping is that the landlord may or may not be here next year. Sharecroppers have put millions of hours into sites like Digg or MySpace. And those sites still exist  but theyre no longer bringing the traffic they once did. Sharecropped land, in other words, has a tendency to become less and less fertile over time. Maybe Facebook or LinkedIn or Google+ will buck the trend. Maybe theyll continue to stay healthy and vibrant for decades, rather than a year or two. The best we can do is guess. And if we guess wrong, our business goes into a slow and steady decline. So are Facebook and Google bad for business? Of course not. Facebook, Google, LinkedIn, Twitter, and many more sites are all superb tools to add to our marketing mix . The secret is to spend most of your time and creative energy building assets that you control. There are three assets you should be building today, and should continue to focus on for the lifetime of your business: A well-designed website with your own hosting account An opt-in email list, ideally with a high-quality autoresponder A reputation for providing impeccable value These things are the equivalent of buying your building instead of renting it. Now any of these can fall prey to outside influences. The bookstores building can burn down. And your site can be hacked, your email account closed down, your reputation smeared. But repairing your assets is in your control. You can fix the hacked code, export your email list to another provider, and respond effectively to manage your reputation. More important, you can proactively protect those assets by taking website security seriously, avoiding any spammy or dodgy practices with your email, and cultivating a loyal audience who will vouch for you as being one of the good guys. Youve put a lot of time and effort into your business  dont put it all at risk by building on rented land. How about you  do you feel confident that youre developing your own online assets? Hows the balance between assets you control and third-party sites like Facebook or Twitter? Let us know about it in the comments. About the Author: Sonia Simone is co-founder and CMO of Copyblogger Media. Get more from Sonia on Twitter and Google+ . ]] Yes!  There's still time!  You, too can become a Basso For Hire groupie before 2012 comes to an end.  Not one.  Not two, but THREE chances this month! I'll be performing on Saturday, December 15th, at the Sugar Loaf Performing Arts Center, with the rest of the Air Pirates Radio Theater.  If you're within driving distance of the "SugarPAC," I strongly suggest you come out and enjoy Herb Marks, Freelance: It Ain't Such a Wonderful Life. This will definitely be better than "Santa Claus Conquers the Martians."  For more details, go to www.airpirateradio.com . But wait!  There's more!  The following weekend I will be performing the role of Donner, in "The Eight: Reindeer Monologues." You'll learn things you never would have imagined about the goings on at the North Pole.  For instance, it's not a good idea to go into the toy shop when Santa's been drinking.  This comedy is for adult audiences only, and just might blow your antlers off. Find out Comet's nickname.  Hear why Prancer HATES claymation.  Learn something you never knew about ballet.  For tickets, click http://sugarloafpac.org/ . And yes, we are doing a show on the 22nd.  So IN YOUR FACE, MAYANS!!! ]] Alright, alright.  Here's a little background. This morning I was coming out of my sleep induced stupor.  As I'm picking out my clothes for work, the television is on.  Specifically, it's showing me a commercial for a book on simple home remedies and cleaning products that are more natural, environmentally safer, and less expensive than many chemical products you'd buy at the store, or maybe they're just clever ideas.  A lot of them I'd heard before, and I've tried a number of the suggestions. Some of these common "wonder solution" things include pouring hot water mixed with a little dish soap on your frozen cement steps to keep them from refreezing.  Baking soda is an abrasive cleaner that can be used on apparently anything from crayon marks on walls to human teeth.  Cardboard toilet paper tubes can be used to eliminate "wire spaghetti" under your computer desk or entertainment center.  Hairspray can knock most flies and mosquitoes out of the sky, and the little fellers will look fabulous afterward.  White distilled vinegar... ...is amazing. White distilled vinegar can be used to clean many surfaces, kill weeds and grass in unwanted areas, neutralize garden lime, and relieve sunburn pain. But wait.  There's more.  What garlic is to vampires, white distilled vinegar is to practically EVERYTHING else.  You can use it to keep cats out of your kid's sandbox (do kids still even have sandboxes?), kill moths and slugs, keep rabbits, ants, and any number of pests away from your house. So my wife (the afore-mentioned Lenna) said, "if you put a pan of it on your front porch, it'll keep the zombies away." Pest deterrent. Hmmm. Obviously she's onto something.  So I asked, "do we need to put it out by every entrance?" "Nope?  Just one pan of it on the front porch.  Of course, you could also use flypaper." I said, "flypaper might slow them down, but eventually they'd pull free of it.  Or whatever part of them was stuck would just break off, and they'd keep coming, although slower." She thought about that and said, "you're right.  Vinegar's got to be the way to go." None of this has been field tested, of course.  But still, if vinegar will keep a cat from taking a dump in a sandbox, it's worth a try. That actually raises another question.  Will vinegar keep zombie cats from pooping in your sandbox?  I honestly don't know. And what if you're away from home at the beginning of the zombie outbreak?  I may start carrying a spritzer bottle full of vinegar with me.  Or a bottle of vinegar and a bowl.  Will any open container work?  Or maybe a small pan.  Because according to Lenna, "a pan" of vinegar "on your front porch" is what does it.  So does that mean it has to be a pan?  But what if the porch is an integral part of the solution?  Am I supposed to carry lumber, vinegar, a pan, carpentry tools, and a mailbox with me everywhere I go?  Just start building a front porch right there on the spot at the sound of the first moan?  Does it have to support my full weight?  Do I need a certificate of occupancy? So much for traveling light!  Maybe a machete is a better idea, after all.  And the spritzer bottle. Be careful out there. Alan Andrews Bassoforhire ]] Hudson Valley's "Best Of 2012" - recordonline Thanks to everyone who supported The Air Pirates. We have once again been voted the Best Theater Troupe of 2012 by the Times Herald Record readers poll. Congratulations to Paul Ellis and all rest of you (us). Six years in a row. To find out more about the Air Pirates, go to The Air Pirates Radio Theater . As of this writing, the Air Pirates are looking for a new performing venue for their 2013 season.  Keep posted to find out where we'll be performing next! On another, personal note, I was once again voted Best Opera Singer in the recordonline.  Many many thanks to all of you for voted for me, and for all of you who support local artists, wherever you are. Alan Andrews Basso for hire ]] http://www.booksellerswithoutbordersny.com/2013/11/tarbabies-by-allen-r-brady.html I just recently finished reading Tarbabies, by Allen R. Brady.  It's an apocalypse told on a local scale.  When the protagonist first hears about them in Manhattan, they're considered more of a nuisance than an actual threat.  But soon after that, they continue to spread outward from the city.  Finally, there's nowhere to go. What are tarbabies?  Well, we're not entirely sure.  It's not like they're fast, vicious monsters like werewolves or vampires, and they're not really zombies, either.  Just don't let them touch you.  In fact, they've been called different things by different people.  But "tarbabies," named after Brer Fox's scheme to catch Brer Rabbit in the Uncle Reemus tale, seems to be the name that "sticks." Here's an excerpt... "That thing on the porch won't go away. I called the police, but I don't think they're coming. They've got their hands full with the Manhattan quarantine, so they can't waste their time on a nothing little town like Otterkill. That means it's up to me and the neighbors, and there are fewer of us every day. Fewer of us, and more of them. Every person we lose is one more monster to deal with. The Spiller family, the folks from the Retirement Center, even the Mathises' Rottweiler are now stalking the streets, waiting for someone to get too close. A single touch is all it takes. I don't know which of my neighbors became the thing on the porch, and I suppose it doesn't matter. I've got to get out of here, but the Tarbabies are already showing up in Albany, and Philadelphia, and Pittsburgh. There's nowhere left to run, and there's no point in hiding. Not when the shadows themselves are after you." The menace of the tarbabies builds throughout the book, as the creatures start appearing everywhere.  There is a particularly harrowing scene on the Appalachian Trail, when the main character and his wife are pursued by a "thing that was a duck."  If that sounds funny, it's because it is.  But Brady still makes it frightening. Allen Brady is a local writer here in the Hudson Valley, and I've performed in a couple of shows that he's written or co-written.  Tarbabies is published by Spore Press.  I look forward to more novels from Allen in the future. Hopefully in December, I'll be able to give you a little blog about my NaNoWriMo efforts this month.  Until then, keep reading!!! Alan Andrews Bassoforhire ]] The continuing adventures of Chloe and Eboli.  First appearance of Eboli. ]] We lost one of my favorite authors this week. Tom Clancy passed away at the age of 66. With the publication of The Hunt for Red October in 1984, Clancy, according to some, practically invented the modern day military-espionage-thriller genre. Clancy had 17 of his 28 books on the New York Times best-sellers list, with many of them reaching the #1 spot. His works are not for everybody, as his generally conservative politics may turn many readers away from a great story. But with 17 NYT best-sellers, he apparently didnt turn away too many. What I enjoy most about Clancys novels are the attention to detail found in them, particularly when he was writing about technological processes or gadgets. Legend has it, in fact, that this attention to detail gained the attention of the Federal Government, who wanted to know how he knew so much about military hardware. Clancys stories typically take two or three (or more) separate threads and then weave them together. In The Sum of All Fears, for instance, he takes such unrelated elements as an undetonated bomb in the middle east and the construction of a Japanese temple, and uses both to bring the world to the brink of nuclear war. For my part, its his story telling, more than his characters that really pulled me in. Thats not to say that he didnt write strong characters. While Jack Ryan is the principal figure of most of his novels, Clancy breathed life to dozens of rich characters, both heroes and villains, many of whom appear in several of his novels. I have my personal favorites. Mr. Clark, for instance, is a CIA field officer who, like a fine wine, just gets better with age. His partner, Domingo Chavez, started out as a sergeant in a Light Infantry division, then went back to school and earned a masters in International Relations, which he describes to Clark as, two nations trying to #*%+ each other. My favorite Clancy character, and in fact one of my favorite characters in fiction, appears in only one novel. He is Colonel Mikhail Semyonovich Filitov, the title character in The Cardinal of the Kremlin. In one scene, Filitov, a former Soviet tank commander during the Great Patriotic War, and 3 time Hero of the Soviet Union (analogous to a 3-time Medal of Honor winner) has been captured by the KGB as a suspected spy. The old colonel is interrogated for days, and at one point is asked why he hates the Motherland. I do not, Filitov replied. I have killed for the Motherland. I have bled for the Motherland. I have burned for the Motherland. But I did not do these things for the likes of you. The Cardinal of the Kremlin Tom Clancys novels took us through the latter part of the Cold War, and on into the War on Terror. He died at Johns Hopkins Hospital in Baltimore (where Jack Ryans wife, Kathy was a surgeon) following a brief illness. According to the Daily News, his surprising death comes two months before the scheduled publication of his next novel, Command Authority likely the latest in Clancys run of blockbuster books. Rest in Peace, Tom Clancy. Alan Andrews http://www.booksellerswithoutbordersny.com/2013/10/tom-clancy-in-memorium.html ]] Last night I dreamed that I was explaining that previous dream to the same two friends, while we were walking through the same area on the same college campus, at the same time of the evening (probably about 10:00 - 11:00pm).  Before I finished describing it to them, I saw the same man/werewolf walking across the lawn to go into the woods.  Just as he disappeared from view, he turned his head and looked directly at me. Weird. That's all.  Just weird. I described this to my cousin this morning.  He's someone whose opinion I value greatly.  He said that it could possibly represent difficulty balancing relationships, dealing with stress issues, and a need for a pina colada at Trader Vic's. Not sure about that...because my hair was perfect. ]] Originally posted on http://www.booksellerswithoutbordersny.com/ First, let's start off with a quiz to see if you should read Mira Grant's "Newsflesh" trilogy. Do you like stories about Zombies? If you said yes, then read it. Medical research, specifically epidemiology? If you said yes, then read it. Politics? If you said yes, then read it. Journalism? If you said yes, then read it. Cloning? If you said yes, then read it. Blogging? If you said yes, then read it. Intrigue? If you said yes, then read it. Post-apocalyptic civilization? If you said yes, then read it. Do you like science fiction? If you said yes, then read it. Do you like scary movies? If you said yes, then read it. Do you like mystery/thrillers? If you said yes, then read it. Do you like to poke things with a stick? If you said yes, then read it. Would you like to find out how George Romero saves the world, and why "George" becomes one of the most popular first names in the English language? If you said yes, then read it. Do you consider yourself a "germophobe?" If you said yes, then read it. The "Newsflesh" trilogy contains something for anyone who said "yes" to any of the questions above. In the first novel of the series, "Feed," Mira Grant (the open pseudonym for Seanan McGuire) introduces us to Georgia and Sean, who run a blogsite called "After the End Times."  "Feed" is told in first person from "George's" (don't call her Georgia) perspective.  The story is set in the mid-21st century, a few decades after a global zombie apocalypse.  The world has changed greatly, because civilization has prevailed over the undead, to a point.  There are still zombies, and anyone who dies is going to come back as one.  This is due to an incident in 2014 in which there was an unfortunate combining of two different molecular strains from two completely different medical research specialists.  Now everyone is infected.  Mankind has gone to great measures to protect itself from "amplification," the process by which one becomes part of the legion of walking dead.  Finger-prick blood tests abound.  By the time I was halfway through the book, my fingers tingled.  Bleach showers are a part of everyday life. People don't travel as much as they used to, for fear of running into someone or something (any mammal large enough to "amplify") that will try to eat them.  But they still want information and entertainment.  That's where Sean and his sister Georgia come in.  They live blog encounters with zombies and post all their activities on the net.  They are frequently accompanied by their friend Buffy (whose real name is Georgette). The trio are chosen to cover a presidential candidate's campaign, and are plunged into a vast web of intrigue, with even more danger than their usual fare of zombie poking. The second book, "Deadline," continues the story from Sean's perspective.  Mira Grant does an excellent job of distinguishing the two voices.  The presidential campaign is over, but the intrigue and constant danger continues and even escalates.  We become more familiar with additional members of the After the End Times crew, as they attempt to uncover more secrets behind zombie amplification, and the tragedies occurring in "Feed." The trilogy ends with "Blackout," in which the After the End Times team is seemingly safe from no one.  Not their friends, their families, the CDC, or their political allies.  To get into more detail would run the risk of  having to post a "Spoiler Alert." I first picked up "Feed" because I liked the cover, and I thought the title was pretty cool.  I quickly became engrossed in the story, and subsequently devoured all three books. "Rise up while you can."  Pick up "Feed" at your local bookstore.  Or you can acquire the entire trilogy at once.  That way you won't have to make as many trips out of the house, thus avoiding all those bleach showers. Alan Andrews Basso for Hire ]] Comedian/Actor/Writer (and who knows what else) Albert Brooks has been making people laugh for years.  Now, with his new novel, 2030 , he's making us think. Twenty Thirty, The real story of what happens to America , shows us a very convincing picture of what can and may happen in the U.S. as the baby boomers (myself included) continue to get older and older.  Thanks to advances in medical research, including finally a cure for cancer, Americans are increasingly looking at their eighties and nineties in their rearview mirrors. Surely curing cancer is a wonderful achievement, right?  After all, is there anyone reading this blog that doesn't know at least one person who has battled cancer? So, Americans are living longer, but they still need medical care, right?  And they still are entitled to benefits like social security, etc., right?  There's just one big problem.  The US is trillions of dollars in debt, and younger citizens are now struggling under the financial burden of caring for the "olds."  Some individuals are even gathering supporters, in an effort to bring about change. At a time when the US economy is already at the breaking point, "the big one" finally happens.  A major earthquake levels Los Angeles, leaving literally millions of people homeless and penniless.  Insurance companies go bankrupt, and relocation centers are hastily erected all along the west coast. The president of the United States is faced with the harsh reality that America simply cannot afford to rebuild Los Angeles.  Projected costs run in excess of 20 trillion dollars, and we don't have it.  The only alternative is to go to their principle lender, China, and ask to borrow more money. China values the United States as a business partner because America is the biggest consumer of Chinese goods.  But can they afford to extend even a portion of such a vast amount to the US?  Do they even want to?  Or is there another alternative? Brooks's prose is very to the point, and non-judgemental.  He doesn't go to any great lengths to point fingers at any one particular ideology or political agenda.  He builds this scenario of the too-near future very logically.  He uses a wide range of characters, and all of them are treated with empathy.  I highly recommend 2030 to anyone interested in a very thought-provoking look at where we are now, and where we may go. Alan Andrews ]] So I asked "MarkO's" permission to share his blog, and he very graciously assented.  The link to his site is at the bottom of this blog, but here are pictures the entries that struck a chord with me... Meat Nativity... ?This one's not strictly a Nativity scene.  It's Christmas lawn art depicting the flogging of Jesus on the way to Golgotha.  Fa la la la la, la la la la. Zombie Nativity... This one is particularly dear to me.  Shotgun shell Nativity (I'm guessing 12 gauge for Joseph, 20 gauge for Mary, and .410 for the Christ child... But as far as thoughtful creativity goes, I have to say this is my favorite.  Just keep thinking about it...? As promised, here's the link to the full site.  There are 42 in all.  God bless them all, every one.  And many thanks to Mark Oestreicher, for his kind permission. http://whyismarko.com/2012/the-42-worst-nativity-sets/ Alan Andrews Basso for Hire ]] If there was any punishment meted out from this incident, I never heard it. Maybe my dad told me, but I must have been laughing too hard to hear it. Ive been a fan of the Tarzan of the Apes books by Edgar Rice Burroughs since my dad got me hooked on them when I was in 3 rd or 4 th grade. Dad was pretty into Tarzan, aka John Clayton, Lord Greystoke when he was a kid, too. Once when he was maybe 12, he was stalking through the jungle with his spear, hunting for prey. Now, when I say stalking through the jungle, I mean he was in his backyard somewhere in north central Texas. And when I say spear, I mean he had a flounder gig. Whats a flounder gig, you may ask? Its a long pole with anywhere from one to four metal points on it, and is used for gigging flounders. Flounders are of course, the salt water flatfish that commonly hide under a layer of sand, waiting for whatever comes their way that might be a tasty snack. Heres a picture of a basic flounder gig, almost exactly like my dads spear, except his had only one point. ? Flounder gig ? So, thats what he had, and thats what he was doing. As my dad tells the story, he sensed the presence of another jungle predator behind him (probably a lion). Suddenly he, the hunter, had become the hunted! Whirling quickly, he drew back his spear arm and launched his missile at the beast. His aim was true (this is Tarzan were talking about after all, remember?) and his spear found its mark. Unfortunately, the role of the lion happened to be played by my grandfather, who had come outside to sit in his lawn chair. The iron point of the flounder gig stuck him in the calf of one leg with enough force that the tip poked out the other side. Can you even imagine the horror my dad must have felt when he realized what hed done? What happened next? Were there shrieks of agony? Well, no. Not so much. Grandaddy looked at the spear hanging out of his leg, and then at my dad, the youngest of his 4 children, and said, My God, Son! Come over here and pull this thing out of me. I believe he then called out to my grandmother, Mable! Come on out here! So my dad did indeed safely retrieve his spear from his wounded prey. And when my grandmother saw what had happened, she handled it with the practical decisiveness for which she was known. Call an ambulance? Drive Grandaddy to the hospital? Oh, settle down and don't get all wound up. Her remedy?  J ust pour some kerosene into both sides of the wound, bandage it, and get on back to her chores. I mean, after all, it wasnt like anybody was seriously hurt or anything. Right? I wonder which hurt worse, the actual spearwound itself, the act of dragging out of the wound, or the kerosene? ]] Rrrriiiiiggghhhhht Do you ever find yourself thinking, "I could accomplish so much, if only I weren't so ( fill in your perceived shortcoming)?  Take a moment and read this great article by Dave Kerpen that I found on LinkedIn this morning. One of the things I do when trying to commit something to memory is to write it down, even if it's already printed before me.  So I did that with this article.  I've also pasted the link at the bottom of this post, so you can pick up the links to some of the sources he cites. + + + + + + + + + + ? How to Turn Your Weaknesses Into Strengths - by Dave Kerpen We all have weaknesses, and we tend to try to work on eliminating them  changing ourselves in order to become better. But change is difficult  very difficult. What if instead of trying to eliminate our weaknesses, we embraced them for what they were? Several months ago, my friend Ben Rosner, CEO of e-home and a fellow member of Entrepreneurs Organization, led an activity on weaknesses and strengths with my EO Forum group, based on the excellent Freak Factor manifesto by David Rendall . I found the activity to be so insightful and inspiring, I did the activity with my team at Likeable Local  and then with our team at Likeable Media . I thought Id share it with you here as well. Think about your biggest weaknesses at work and in life. What qualities are you most unhappy about? Of the following list of 16 typical weaknesses, look carefully and choose the three that resonate most with you: 1. Disorganized 2. Inflexible 3. Stubborn 4. Inconsistent 5. Obnoxious 6. Emotionless 7. Shy 8. Irresponsible 9. Boring 10. Unrealistic 11. Negative 12. Intimidating 13. Weak 14. Arrogant 15. Indecisive 16. Impatient Got your three biggest weaknesses? Great (dont be too depressed, the rest of this activity is more fun). Next, look at the below list, find the same three weaknesses, and look at the traits to the right of each of your three biggest weaknesses: 1. Disorganized  Creative 2. Inflexible  Organized 3. Stubborn  Dedicated 4. Inconsistent  Flexible 5. Obnoxious  Enthusiastic 6. Emotionless  Calm 7. Shy  Reflective 8. Irresponsible  Adventurous 9. Boring  Responsible 10. Unrealistic  Positive 11. Negative  Realistic 12. Intimidating  Assertive 13. Weak  Humble 14. Arrogant  Self-Confident 15. Indecisive  Patient 16. Impatient  Passionate The three qualities to the right of your three weaknesses are all strengths. Hidden in your weaknesses are your strengths. Every weakness has a corresponding strength. The idea here is simple: Instead of trying to change your weaknesses, accept them. Dont try to fix them  its too difficult. Instead, be sure to leverage your associated strengths. You can look to colleagues, direct reports, and even supervisors to fill in the gaps where you are weakest. Dont be afraid to ask people for help  they can add value where you are weaker. But be sure to embrace your strengths, and build upon them. After all, your strengths (even those disguised as weaknesses) will get you far in your career, and in life. Now its your turn. Did this activity resonate with you? Were the strengths corresponding with your weaknesses accurate? What are your greatest weaknesses  and strengths? What are the takeaways for you at work and in life? Let me know your thoughts in the Comments section below! And heres to your secret strengths! Dave Kerpen is disorganized, unrealistic and impatient  which means hes creative, positive and passionate! For more information about this activity, be sure to check out the excellent book Freak Factor by David Rendall. For more on Dave Kerpen, check out the New York Times best seller Likeable Social Media and the Amazon #1 best seller Likeable Business . Or click the follow button below for more of Dave's posts on LinkedIn . + + + + + + + + + + + As promised, here is the link to the original article. http://www.linkedin.com/today/post/article/20130325120757-15077789-how-to-turn-your-weaknesses-into-strengths ]] I read the book a couple of years ago and highly recommend it to any zombiphiles. One thing that many people have complained about is that the movie isn't true to the book.  I'll agree with that. It's very different, told from a different perspective.  Max Brooks's book is written as "an oral history of the zombie war."  It is told in a series of interviews after the "zombie war" is over, and civilization has adapted to life among the undead.  The "interviews" provide insight into where the virus originated, how it spread, and our early disastrous attempts at defending ourselves.  The movie follows the efforts on Gerry Lane (Brad Pitt), a former UN Undersecretary called back to service.  Lane's mission is to accompany an expert in infectious diseases to South Korea, in an effort to discover both a cause and solution to the crisis.  Mayhem ensues.  Lots more stuff happens.  Lane has to improvise. One of the most intense scenes in the book is the "battle of Yonkers," which is where it became apparent that destroying the brain was really the only way to stop "Zeke."  The battle of Yonkers doesn't appear in the movie. But there are plenty of intense moments:  the rush hour traffic jam in Philadelphia, Lane and his family's escape, the refueling stop in Korea, swarms in Jerusalem, mid-air massacres, and the World Health Organization labs, had me on the edge of my seat. It's different enough that if you haven't read the book yet, but were planning to, I'd say go ahead and see the movie. It's not going to ruin the book for you. Nor will the book ruin the movie, as long as you don't go in expecting the everything to see the same. World War Z is rated PG-13.  If you're thinking about taking your kids, or letting them see it, use your own discretion. It's very intense, as I said.  But there's not nearly the gore (or language) that you're going to encounter in any given episode of "The Walking Dead."  Also, there are no naked naughty bits. After seeing the movie, I'm going to have to read the book again.  Just for grins. Alan ]] It's that time again here in the Hudson Valley.  Yes, it's time to go online and cast your votes for the "Hudson Valley's Best of 2012." Record online: Best of 2012 Support your local businesses, artists, entertainers, venues, etc.  It only takes a couple of minutes of your time. (It's okay if you want to vote for me for a few of these categories) See you in a couple of days with a new book review! Thanks for your support of the Hudson Valley's best! Alan Andrews Basso for Hire? ]] First in a series. http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NnZ6FPDrdxw ]] I've just been informed that I have one of the top 5% most viewed @LinkedIn profiles for 2012. http://www.linkedin.com/pub/profile/15/33a/174 Okay, then. AA/BFH ]] Cruising through the internet this morning (where everything is true, and nobody fabricates anything, ever), I found the following facebook post, which had been shared by an online friend of mine. "By XXXX XXXXX So Westboro showed up here in Texas at the memorial service in West for the first responders who lost their lives in the explosion. The chief of police promptly had all 20 or so of them arrested and put into holding cells (all the men in one and all the women in another) When they told him he couldn't do that, he let them know he could. Since he hadn't officially charged them, he could hold them for 24 hours before he had to charge them or let them go! (plenty of time to hold the memorial service). I guess Westboro didn't think it through too well... This is Texas. As quickly as we fry people down here, did they really think they would be allowed to show that kind of disrespect?? Their photos were also released to the other small towns surrounding West, where services would be denied to them. Sometimes you just have to admire the way we do things down here in Texas! Thanks, XXXX XXXXXX" "Westboro" refers to Westboro Baptist Church, which has gained noteriety recently through a number of inflammatory statements, and controversial protests at veterans' funerals and other events.  "West" refers, of course, to the town of West, Texas, where there was a fertilizer plant explosion, resulting in the loss of many lives.  Although I don't know anyone personally from West, I always think of that little town fondly.  When I studied at Baylor University, any time I was driving back up home and went through West early enough, I would stop at this little Czech bakery and pick up some pastries. Doing a little more research (very little, really - it IS Monday morning), I found that there is disagreement over whether the detainment of any WBC members/protestors actually occurred.  I don't have any verification one way or the other at this time.  Snopes.com says it's probably not true, and here's their link. http://www.snopes.com/politics/religion/wbctexas.asp That being said, I would like to make something clear regarding this issue.  I am a believer in Christ.  Although I belong to a non-denominational evangelical church now, doctrinally I am a Baptist.  As such, I am continually sickened and appalled by some of the things I have heard attributed to the leadership of Westboro Baptist Church.  If half of the things that people say this church did or said are actually true, then their leadership is clearly not exhibiting Christian principles.  They are not "the salt of the earth" (Matthew 5:13), nor are they following Christ's teaching, "In the same way, let your light shine before others, that they may see your good deeds and glorify your Father in heaven" (Matthew 5:16).  They are instead destroying themselves as witnesses to the doctrine of salvation by grace through faith, and the sanctification and discipleship of believers.  Additionally, they are leading astray many in their fellowship.  In this way they are fullfilling Scripture, although not in the good way.  Here are a few places where they are mentioned: Jesus said, "Beware of false prophets, who come to you in sheep's clothing, but inwardly they are ravenous wolves. You will know them by their fruits" (Matthew 7:15,16). The Apostle Paul met with the elders of the church in Ephesus before leaving that city and said, "For I know this, that after my departure savage wolves will come in among you, not sparing the flock. Also from among yourselves men will rise up, speaking perverse things, to draw away the disciples after themselves. Therefore watch, and remember that for three years I did not cease to warn everyone night and day with tears " (Acts 20:29-31). Paul also expressed similar concern in one of his letters to the church in Corinth. "But I fear, lest somehow, as the serpent deceived Eve by his craftiness, so your minds may be corrupted from the simplicity that is in Christ" (2 Corinthians. 11:3). Again, speaking to the Galatians this time, Paul writes. "I marvel that you are turning away so soon from Him who called you in the grace of Christ, to a different gospel, which is not another; but there are some who trouble you and want to pervert the gospel of Christ" (Galatians. 1:6,7).   And, "O foolish Galatians! Who has bewitched you that you should not obey the truth, before whose eyes Jesus Christ was clearly portrayed among you as crucified?" (Gal. 3:1). The Apostle Peter also warns about false teachers.  In 2nd Peter, 2:1,2, he writes that "there will be false teachers among you, who will secretly bring in destructive heresies, even denying the Lord who bought them, and bring on themselves swift destruction. And many will follow their destructive ways, because of whom the way of truth will be blasphemed." In 3:17,18, he concludes by saying, "You therefore, beloved, since you know this beforehand, beware lest you also fall from your own steadfastness, being led away with the error of the wicked; but grow in the grace and knowledge of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. To Him be the glory both now and forever. Amen." So as someone who falls pretty firmly into the "right-wing evangelical" or "fundamentalist Christian" camp, that you here about on the news all the time, let me make it very clear that these people who are going about trying to disrupt funerals (of anyone), are NOT representing the teachings of Christ, nor are they bearing the fruits of the Holy Spirit.  They have instead fallen victim to false teachings, or have themselves deliberately set out to deceive others, for their own personal benefit.  If that's the case, it will not benefit them in the end. Alan Andrews Basso for Hire ]] 