 http://www.forbes.com/sites/joelkotkin/2011/12/15/heavy-metal-is-back-the-best-cities-for-manufacturing/ ]] Hey, what in the world is that? This would be a "Wordle." So, what is a "Wordle?" If one were to visit Wordle.net, they could create their own. This example right here refers to an article (located here: http://www.themanufacturinginstitute.org/~/media/A07730B2A798437D98501E798C2E13AA.ashx What you do, is take an article, any article, and copy the text into the Wordle site. What the site then does is scan the article for words that are used the most. In this case, the article dealt primarily with "The Skills Gap in U.S. Manufacturing." As one can see- words like skills, talent, production and manufacturing are enlarged. When a word is enlarged, this in turn means that the article places emphasis in those words and uses them more than others. Why create a Wordle? Well, browse the article below and take a listen to the this audio sample taken from NPR. When employers talk about a "skill gap," they are saying that we have jobs to fill but not enough skilled workers to fill the position. Please visit this link and listen in: http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2012/01/13/145039131/the-transformation-of-american-factory-jobs-in-one-company ]] http://www.jsonline.com/business/hiring-survey-bullish-on-industry-ue3k5ds-136511983.html ]] Answer..... On-The-Job training is not something that was recently developed. This is a proven method for employers to find the skilled workers they are looking for. When an employer works with Workforce Development, it is surprising to them to see that they can be reimbursed for this training. Go ahead and browse this article below and tell me if you think On-The-Job training would be beneficial to the economy and more specifically, Manufacturing companies. We NEED to keep our manufacturing jobs here and this is the most efficient method to do exactly that! http://bottomline.msnbc.msn.com/_news/2012/01/18/10183148-factories-rev-up-but-hiring-doesnt Below is the exact chart from that article. Does anyody else see the need for us to get OJT (On-The-Job Training) into the minds of employers? ]] Where People and Jobs Connect! ? Please feel free to take a look at our website: http://www.wfdc.org/ Take a browse and discover all the great things that Workforce Development can do for you. This blog may have a focus on the $4.9M grant, but our organization offers individuals much more than just employment in the Manufacturing industry. Whether you are a job seeker, employee or employer- WDI can help you in many aspects of your life and career goals. If you have specific questions, feel free to walk right in or contact us directly. Our contact information for the WOW area is located on the home page, under the 'Contact us" tab. In Waukesha- We are located on the WCTC campus In West Bend- We are located on the MPTC campus In Mequon- We are located on the MATC North campus. Look here for detailed explanations: http://www.wfdc.org/locations/index.htm ]] Ladies and Gentleman: The President of the United States Now, Doesn't what he is talking about sound an awful lot like what we have going on right here- right now? You heard it here first (sort of) so stop in the Workforce Development Center near you and find out what WE can do for YOU! ]] Putting the pieces together: A combination of W.O.W Workforce Development, Inc, WRTP/BIG STEP, Milwaukee Gear and Waukesha County Technical College worked together for one common cause: to create jobs. On February 3, 2012- 15 individuals graduated from the interconnected program with a certificate in Entry Level Manufacturing Skills- CNC Certificate Training Program. These individuals, who come from all different aspects of life and socio-economic statuses, represent success to the fullest extent. This is the main goal of the TIME grant- to create a skillset in our workforce that enables those individuals longevity in their current position as well as assuring for their future employment. Congratulations to those graduates and we wish them nothing but success moving forward. http://www.biztimes.com/manufacturingweekly/2012/2/6/w-o-w-grant-to-train-550-new-workers http://wrtp.org/index.php http://wfdc.org/ http://wctc.edu/ Manufacturing is the backbone of Southeastern Wisconsin and it is our duty to create a workforce that other's envy. There is too much negativity in the papers and news about the city of Milwaukee and surrounding areas; all this crime, poverty, segregation, etc. We need to turn this unconstructive view into a positive one. Let's make Southeastern Wisconsin a place where people and businesses want to come and grow. Let's make Wisconsin a state that represents success- where people are working together and making things happen. It is time for a new era in SE Wisconsin, a positive, energy driven era where the workforce is skilled and the work is stable. It is time to take advantage of what we have right in front of us! All companies, big or small, can benefit from the TIME grant. Get in touch with us today by calling 262.695.7894! OPPORTUNITY HAS KNOCKED, WILL YOU ANSWER THE DOOR? ]] Bringing the JOBS back home to the United States You may or may not have heard the term, "insourcing" before. Read the article below and feel free to discuss your thoughts and/or opinions on the transformation of our jobs back to America. It is a very interesting article! http://news.yahoo.com/lemming-exodus-manufacturers-look-u-165814959.html;_ylc=X3oDMTNraHJvdjc4BF9TAzc2NjQ4MTEEYWN0A21haWxfY2IEY3QDYQRpbnRsA3VzBGxhbmcDZW4tVVMEcGtnA2U1NjQzMGQzLWY3YzItMzNiOS05ZGE0LWQ1ZDY4M2JlNzY4ZQRzZWMDbWl0X3NoYXJlBHNsawNtYWlsBHRlc3QD;_ylv=3 ]] Before you watch the video- give this a brief thought. This picture represents what a typical job searcher may see while browsing job postings in today's economy. This is real life for millions of Americans and what you see below suggests that those who are unemployed, through no fault of their own, may be discriminated against because of their work situation. Is this fair? Meet the new underclass -- the four million Americans who have been unemployed for more than a year. With every additional week out of work, their chances of finding a job dwindle. It turns out that many employers don't want to hire the currently unemployed. Enter Joe Carbone, who is determined to return the American dream to the long-term unemployed in Connecticut. And he's succeeding, one job at a time. How's Carbone doing it? ]] ...... until we see a whole lot more of what you are about to read below Hiring at home -- and even 're-shoring' As the presidential election campaign heats up, you're almost certain to hear one line repeatedly: "The U.S. doesn't make things anymore." It's a canard that's been kicking around since the 1980s. Yes, there have been lean years for some types of manufacturing -- and ensuing job losses -- that have devastated some local economies. But U.S. manufacturing didn't die; on the contrary, it's bouncing back ferociously. "The manufacturing sector is leading the recovery," says James Paulsen, an economist and market strategist with Wells Capital Management. More than a third of the 3% growth in the gross domestic product in the fourth quarter of 2011 came from manufacturing, though the sector makes up just 11% of the economy. And during the past four months, U.S. factories have contributed 17% of the new jobs. Key indicators such as industrial production and rail freight volumes are also showing solid strength. In fact, "manufacturing has been a true bright spot in the economy over the last few years," says Chad Moutray, an economist with the National Association of Manufacturers . Expect this to continue for three reasons. First , the U.S. economy is growing, and as demand rises, producers will add capacity, says Todd Lowenstein of the HighMark Value Fiduciary Fund ( HMVMX ). They'll be creating jobs and buying tools, machine parts, cranes, trucks and other equipment. Second , a middle class has emerged in the developing world because we have bought so much stuff made there. "Over the last couple decades, we were building a brand-new world to sell to," says Paulsen. To wit: Exports of manufactured goods exports jumped 15% in February, and they accounted for three-fourths of a $16 billion gain in exports, says NAM's Moutray. Third , the idea that China will take all our manufacturing jobs is proving false. In fact, jobs are coming back home, a trend christened "re-shoring." U.S. companies are fed up with low-quality production, counterfeiting and logistical headaches, says Michael Zinser, a manufacturing-sector expert with the Boston Consulting Group, and wages in China are rising rapidly. Please note: The source of the above information and a whole lot more can be found here: http://money.msn.com/investing/10-companies-making-more-in-the-usa-brush-2#scpti2 On another note: how about some more TIME Grant #'s? Total # of contracts: 94 Average wage: $16.45 Total amount of reimbursements: $305,953 Total # of companies receiving benefits: 35+ In not even ONE month, we have nearly doubled our numbers! ]] Hey, Guess What?? On-the-job training works!!! Well folks, as the month of March winds down and 80+ degree weather has already made it's appearance- I thought it may be TIME to give those who take a glance at this blog, an update. The TIME grant, brought to you by the Department of Labor and managed by WOW Workforce Development, has taken off in the very few months since it has been active. By the numbers, it is easy to see that employers are interested and job seekers are benefitting. Since our very first TIME On-The-Job training contract was developed on 01/19/2012- a total of 52 more have followed in it's path. For those of you that are not to keen with numbers- we put 53 people to work in a matter of approximately 60 days. Of those 53 on-the-job training contracts, the average starting wage for all 44 contracts equals out to $15.95/hr. When you calculate these numbers, a total of $187,172 is due to be reimbursed to area employers. Yes, it is that simple. In a matter of maybe two more weeks- $200,000 in free money is set to be sent directly to those employers that chose to take advantage of this magnificent job-creating program. To make it a little easier on the eyes: Total OJT's: 53 Average TIME wage: $15.95 Total TIME amount: $187,172 Total number of companies receiving benefits: 26 And don't forget- this is in a time span of maybe 60 days- Can you imagine what the next 3, 6, 9 month numbers will look like? The companies are talking to one another, "Wow, that was easy." The unemployed are finding CAREERS, not just jobs. Companies are hiring! If you or somebody you know would like to get involved with this monumental grant- call our Employer Relations Unit today @ 262.695.7894]] THEN NOW Young Americans are shunning factory jobs because they think they are uncool. But they need to do some homework, because some positions are paying close to six figures.That's right- 6 figures! Now this may not be everywhere; but the point is, the Manufacturing industry isn't the dirty and low paying career that today's youth believe it is. Even if you don't want to take notice- Manufacturing Is and Has Been the backbone of the great state of Wisconsin for many years. I heard a troubling statistic the other day while I was attending a dinner at the Hilton with some members of the TDMAW (Tool Die Machining Association of Wisconsin). Our guest speaker Timothy W. Sullivan, the former CEO of Bucyrus International and currently serving as a Special Consultant to Governor Walker, presented some interesting facts during his speech. The one fact that I seem to remember vividly is this: there was a survey amongst Wisconsin residents asking them if they felt that Manufacturing could alone be the key to the economic recovery in Wisconsin. Do you want to know what the results were? A staggering 70% believed this was true. Yes, 70% of those surveyed believed that Manufacturing could very well be the answer! Of that 70% that believed in Manufacturing: only 17% admitted that they would be willing to work in Manufacturing or would want their children working in Manufacturing. It is time to open up the eyes of our youth. An industry that was once believed to be back-breaking and low-paying, has become high-tech and high salaried. Please take the time to read the article below and see for yourself. We need to pass this information on to our youth- after all- the future of this country is in their hands. A skilled workforce is the foundation of a thriving economy in today's age. http://money.cnn.com/2012/02/27/smallbusiness/youth_manufacturing_jobs/?source=linkedingoback=%2Egmp_97260%2Egde_97260_member_100827196 ]] No. 10: Milwaukee-Waukesha-West Allis, Wisc. The center for manufacturing of machine tools and other precision equipment boosted its industrial employment 3.6% last year to 118,000 jobs. http://www.forbes.com/sites/joelkotkin/2012/05/24/seattle-is-leading-an-american-manufacturing-revival/ As I read through the Forbes article listed above, I was thinking to myself...whoa whoa whoa; where is Wisconsin on this list? It turns out I was not disappointed as here we are- right in the mix at #10! I can't help but celebrate that, once again, Wisconsin is recognized for its Manufacturing. We have had a visit from our country's President, national recognition from various news outlets, our Governor regularly visiting the manufacturing facilities and now most recently...the awarding of the TIME grant. I also can't help but wonder what those numbers will look like if we continue moving forward like we have been. The interest in the grant continues to pick up, the employers are continuing to hire, the reimbursements are continuing to grow, and more and more people are getting back to work. I would like to see Wisconsin leading the way; and, if the team running this grant have anything to say about it, we will be. I thought about providing you viewers (all the thousands of you that there are) with some updated numbers, but I think I will hold off until the next post and let the anticipation sit in a little bit. Wisconsin is not just a bunch of cheese head Packer fans. Wisconsin is not just about Farming, Dairy and State Fairs. Wisconsin is not just about Hunting, Fishing, and the Northwood's. Wisconsin is not just about people driving at least 5 below the speed limit. Wisconsin is not just about Noah's Ark and the Wiscnsin Dells. Wisconsin is about working together and putting people to work. Wisconsin is about creating a skilled workforce that will set the standard for the way economic and workforce development is created. Wisconsin is about making BIG things happen- some of which you don't know about yet and some of which you will hear about soon! Forbes , take note: Wisconsin is going to be #1 in Manufacturing --- it's only a matter of TIME... ]] The following term and phrase used together can signify an assortment of things. 1. Wisconsin 2. Best in the Nation Let's start with the Green Bay Packers - the best Football team in the nation. Next up, Summerfest - the Nation's/World's Largest Music Festival. Following that, Bob Uecker, Mr. Baseball - the most prolific sports commentator in the nation. Friday Night Fish Fry's - the best in the Nation and the backbone of Wisconsin food...speaking of which, today is Friday, mmmm- is 10 am too early for a fish fry? Ok, one more...The famous Milwaukee Brewer Racing Sausages - the best team mascots in the Nation. You see, there are just so many great things about Wisconsin that it's difficult to pinpoint what it is that the media would report about. How about this little topic; Employment outlook in southeast Wisconsin best in the nation Ah yes, that sounds good. Sure, Wisconsin has hundreds of great things that make us unique; but, this topic is by far the most important. If people aren't working, how can they enjoy all of the great things this state has to offer? Packer Games, Summerfest, Fish Fry's and Brewer games, to name just a few, wouldn't be as historic and popular as they have become- without Wisconsin natives spending their hard-earned money supporting the events. As you will see when you read the article below; here is a tidbit of what will be mentioned... MILWAUKEE  A new Manpower survey shows the employment outlook in southeast Wisconsin is the best in the nation; and companies are more likely to hire in Milwaukee t han anywhere else in the country. http://fox6now.com/2012/06/12/employment-outlook-in-southeast-wisconsin-best-in-the-nation/ Now doesn't that put a smile on your face on this beautiful summer day in Wisconsin? 75 degress and sunny, a few passing clouds and a growing job market. Slowly but surely, we are eliminating the unemployment in Wisconsin. Employers are hiring, we (Workforce Develoment) are reimbursing, and all along the way- we are paving a foundation for the future, our children. What a way to enter into the weekend. Hey, what about that TIME grant...is anything happening? You betcha! Updated TIME Grant Statistics: January 2012-June 2012 Total # of OJT Contracts: 159 Average wage of new hires: $16.45 Total Reimbursement $: $505,506 Total # of Companies benefitting: 50+ ]] When you hear the words Boot Camp, you may be thinking...no thanks. I mean, after all, Boot Camp can be correctly described in either of the following two ways according to the internet: Boot Camp Noun: A military training camp for new recruits. A prison for youthful offenders, run on military lines. Not this Boot Camp though... ? ? ? ???? ?? ??? ? ? ?????W.O.W Workforce Development's Boot Camps are specific to what the workforce demands. In this case, what we have here is a CNC ?Boot Camp. Time and time again, we here the following phrase from employers: "I can't find any qualified and skilled workers." If you happen to browse a job board for manufacturing careers, I can almost guarantee that wherever you look- you will see openings for a CNC machinist in SE Wisconsin. How it worked: 11 unemployed individuals are currently enrolled in the Workforce Investment Act (WIA) program. Those 11 individuals are sent to school to receive FREE training in Computer Numerical Control (CNC) Machining. This specific class will endure a very intense 6 week training that, upon completion, will certify them as entry-level CNC machinists. The training takes place both in the classroom as well as in the state-of-the-art machining lab on the Waukesha County Technical College (WCTC) campus. These individuals will attend training on Monday-Thursdays from 12:00pm-9:00pm and Fridays from 8:00am-5:00pm.  In depth training includes: Blueprint Reading, Math, Manual Machining, CNC Turning and CNC Machining. Upon successful completion of the 6 week crash course in CNC; Workforce Development, Inc. is working to have a 100% placement rate upon graduation. How do we do that? About half way through the training, the Employer Relations Unit of Workforce Development Inc. (WDI) works together to bring in employers that are hiring for exactly that: CNC Machinists. Invitations were sent out to a large number of Waukesha County Employers, and the 12 company maximum filled up literally overnight. The goal of this event is to give the individuals some one on one interviewing and facetime with a potential employer. As you can see in some of the pictures- applications can and will be filled out on the spot for future employment. Alongside the Employer Visit Day, we have also arranged for two guest speakers to come in and speak to the class about Manufacturing as a whole, career paths to pursue, what it takes to be successful and job security as a skilled worker. This has shown to stabilize our retention rates of the participants under such a demanding schedule. The picture(s) above and the ones that follow were taken on Employer Visit Day. This event was held at the Waukesha County Workforce Development Center on July 25th, 2012. The program is designed to align our current trainings with what the employers are screaming for: skilled workers. Upon successful completion, it is our goal to have all the individuals start a job with On-the-Job (OJT) funding...compliments of the TIME grant from WDI! A special thank you goes out to those employers that came out and interviewed our fellow Boot Camp participants: A.S. Pindel Corp: New Berlin GE Energy: Waukesha Generac Corporation: Waukesha Grede Holdings LLC: Menomonee Falls In-Place Machining: Milwaukee Premier Paper Converting Machinery: New Berlin ValveWorks USA: New Berlin VL Tool: Waukesha Versevo Inc: Harland Waukesha Metal Products: Sussex Waukesha Foundry: Waukesha Wisconsin Metal Parts: Waukesha ? ? ? ? ? ? ? ?]] From left to right: Dale P. Kooyenga , Wisconsin Legislator-14th Assembly District Representative; Reggie Newson, Secretary, State of Wisconsin - DWD; Carrie Hersh, Program Manager -WRTP/BIG STEP; Joe Nicosia , Industry Representative -WRTP/BIG STEP; Rebecca Kleefisch, Lieutenant Governor - State of Wisconsin; Rhandi Berth , Vice President - WRTP/BIG STEP; Francisco "Paco" Sanchez, President - WOW Workforce Development Inc.; Dr. Barbara Prindiville, President - Waukesha County Technical College; Bryan Obst, Corporate Recruiter for Trace-A-Matic Corporation; and Ed Graunke , Operations Manager for Trace-A-Matic Corporation. ____________________________________________________________________________ Today we celebrate new beginnings. New beginnings for businesses, new beginnings for people's lives and their families, new beginnings for collaboration and new beginnings for workforce, economic and business development. Those individuals shown above, along with many others, are a prime example of what can be accomplished by working together. We come together today for the graduation of 11 customized training graduates. 11 graduates, whom before were unemployed. 11 graduates who stuck it out through the course of a grueling training period. 11 graduates (8 men and 3 women) who will be joining the manufacturing workforce! Congratulations to you and I wish you all the very best of luck. A brief informative workshop to explain this collaborative success : It all starts with the company; more specifically, a company that is hiring. A company that cannot find the skilled workers that they need. A company willing to work with others; and, a company that wants to grow. Yes, Trace-A-Matic ( traceamatic.com ), is the driving force behind this project. Recruitment efforts through the Wisconsin Regional Training Partnership (WRTP) is where our students came from. WRTP performs an in-depth recruiting process- sometimes starting with as many as 300 potential candidates. The company is established (Trace-A-Matic), the needs are identifed (CNC Machinists), and now we dip into the pots of two substantial forms of grant money available; TIME and WIA funding.  It is through the WIA funding that these individuals are sent to school, to be trained, absolutely free. While in the customized program, these individuals perform on the job shadowing at their soon-to-be employers; as well as training on machines and coursework, specific to what their job will entail. Once the individuals graduate (8-12 weeks: in this case- 8 weeks), they start their new job with (TIME) on-the-job training dollars. The employer will be reimbursed a portion of each new hires training salary during a clearly defined training period To make it short and sweet; Employers are getting freshly trained workers, trained specific to that companies unique skillsets, as well as receiving between $4-5,000 in training reimbursement (per each new hire). None of this is costing the Employer a dime; in fact, if you read that correctly- they are making money while gaining fresh talent. Sound familiar? This is our second successful project that has put people to work: http://www.jsonline.com/news/milwaukee/barrett-to-unveil-customtailored-job-training-plan-v545b5t-139166399.html There is training currently in session and several more in the works. If you would like to know more about how it works, just ask. For now-  It's TIME to celebrate some success. Have a great weekend! ]] WA County Fall Waukesha County Fall 2012 ]] As part of Workforce Development Month, Francisco Sanchez, President for Waukesha-Ozaukee-Washington Workforce Development Board., and featured speaker Lieutenant Governor Rebecca Kleefisch hosted the official launch of the TIME Program (Training Individuals for Manufacturing Employment), a $4.9 million on-the-job training program. In 2011 the Waukesha-Ozaukee-Washington Workforce Development Board, in partnership with the Wisconsin Precision Metalworking Council and the Milwaukee 7 Manufacturing Industry Partnership group, received a $4.9 million grant from the U.S. Department of Labor to train individuals for manufacturing employment. This 4-year grant will run through November 2015 and provide on-the-job training for 560 participants. Through the TIME Program, manufacturing employers are eligible for wage reimbursement during the participants on-the-job training period. Since the TIME Programs launch in January 2012, the Waukesha-Ozaukee-Washington Workforce Development Board has already placed 182 participants with 80 employers! The Waukesha-Ozaukee-Washington Workforce Development Board is grateful to have the support of Senator Herb Kohl and Senator Ron Johnson. Senator Kohl stated that Waukesha-Ozaukee-Washington Workforce Development, Inc. has a proud history of training employees in specialty fields. At a time when manufacturing is rebounding here in Wisconsin, this funding will go a long way in helping this sector prepare and train more workers in advanced manufacturing industries. A special thank you goes out to our other guest "Employer" speakers: Michael Mallwitz, President at Busch Precision, Inc located in Milwaukee, WI Matthew Mumper, President at Premier Paper Converting Machinery located in New Berlin, WI ]] Nobody can go back and start a new beginning, but anyone can start today and make a new ending." Help a youth get an education and work experience. BUILDING FUTURES starts now! Please contact Aaron Bucane for more information 262.695.7852 or abucane@wctc.edu ]] 