 European BPM Roundtable (bpmroundtable.eu ) se creo en 2012 como  punto de encuentro para que i nvestigadores y profesionales cooperen mediante el intercambio de ideas y la transferencia de  las investigaciones realizadas en Europa sobre las ultimas tendencias en la gestion de procesos de negocio y las mejores practicas . En Espana, esta iniciativa esta liderada por la Universitat Politecnica de Valencia (UPVLC) representada por PROS Research Center (Centro de Investigacion en Metodos de Produccion de Software ) Acaban de publicar un video que explica  brevemente que es BPM y afirma el liderazgo de Europa en investigacion en BPM y su influencia e inspiracion para los otros continentes. BPM Round Table Movie Contenido del Video: Business Process Management (BPM) is the discipline that combines knowledge from information technology and knowledge from management sciences and applies this to operational business processes. Over the past two decades, Business Process Management has caused a radical change in the way in which organizations work. Organizations evolve around their key business processes and increasingly rely on Information Technology. Without well-designed processes and supporting information systems, organizations are unable to compete and will not survive. Typical BPM related activities included: - modelling business processes as starting point for process analysis and system configuration - enacting processes using IT systems that control, support and monitor the flow of work in organisations - Managing processes by responding to changes in workloads and shifting priorities - Analyze process using actual event data and crosses models BPM facilities process improvements in various ways: - Streamline processes using BPM will help to reduce flow times and shorten response times - Process automation will allow    organizations to do more work with fewer people - BPM technologies  can detect and remove  waste and inefficiencies  as the result Processes will be  Cheaper, more reliable and faster Europe is leading in Business Process Management (BPM) research.  Europe s top BPM researchers are among the most cited computer scientists in the world.  There is a long European tradition in process thinking. The European BPM Round Table was established in 2012 and is a federation of more than 20 national BPM round tables aiming to transfer cutting-edge research into new products and services in the area of Business Process Management. The goal is to attract the attention of decision makers and secure support for large-scale European BPM initiatives. The European BPM Round Table invites all European BPM researchers and practitioners to join forces. For more information on the European BPM Round Table and its initiatives see bpmroundtable.eu ]] European BPM Roundtable (bpmroundtable.eu ) se creo en 2012 como  punto de encuentro para que i nvestigadores y profesionales cooperen mediante el intercambio de ideas y la transferencia de  las investigaciones realizadas en Europa sobre las ultimas tendencias en la gestion de procesos de negocio y las mejores practicas . En Espana, esta iniciativa esta liderada por la Universitat Politecnica de Valencia (UPVLC) representada por PROS Research Center (Centro de Investigacion en Metodos de Produccion de Software ) Acaban de publicar un video que explica  brevemente que es BPM y afirma el liderazgo de Europa en investigacion en BPM y su influencia e inspiracion para los otros continentes. BPM Round Table Movie Contenido del Video: Business Process Management (BPM) is the discipline that combines knowledge from information technology and knowledge from management sciences and applies this to operational business processes. Over the past two decades, Business Process Management has caused a radical change in the way in which organizations work. Organizations evolve around their key business processes and increasingly rely on Information Technology. Without well-designed processes and supporting information systems, organizations are unable to compete and will not survive. Typical BPM related activities included: - modelling business processes as starting point for process analysis and system configuration - enacting processes using IT systems that control, support and monitor the flow of work in organisations - Managing processes by responding to changes in workloads and shifting priorities - Analyze process using actual event data and crosses models BPM facilities process improvements in various ways: - Streamline processes using BPM will help to reduce flow times and shorten response times - Process automation will allow    organizations to do more work with fewer people - BPM technologies  can detect and remove  waste and inefficiencies  as the result Processes will be  Cheaper, more reliable and faster Europe is leading in Business Process Management (BPM) research.  Europe s top BPM researchers are among the most cited computer scientists in the world.  There is a long European tradition in process thinking. The European BPM Round Table was established in 2012 and is a federation of more than 20 national BPM round tables aiming to transfer cutting-edge research into new products and services in the area of Business Process Management. The goal is to attract the attention of decision makers and secure support for large-scale European BPM initiatives. The European BPM Round Table invites all European BPM researchers and practitioners to join forces. For more information on the European BPM Round Table and its initiatives see bpmroundtable.eu ]] 