 ... ]] Click to view a price quote on HLF . ]] NAMPA, Idaho, Jan. 24, 2014 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Home Federal Bancorp, Inc. ("Company") (Nasdaq:HOME), the parent company of Home Federal Bank ("Bank"), today announced results for the quarter and year ended December 31, 2013. For the quarter ended December 31, 2013, the Company reported a net loss of $2.3 million, or $(0.17) per diluted share, compared to net income of $219,000, or $0.02 per diluted share, for the same period a year ago. For the year ended December 31, 2013, the Company reported net loss of $255,000, or $(0.02) per diluted share, compared to net income of $1.8 million, or $0.12 per diluted share, for the same period a year ago. The Bank has entered into shared-loss agreements with the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation ("FDIC") in connection with two acquisitions. The loans and foreclosed assets purchased in these acquisitions that are subject to the shared-loss agreements are referred to as "covered loans" or "covered assets." Loans and foreclosed and repossessed assets not subject to shared-loss agreements with the FDIC are referred to as "noncovered loans" or "noncovered assets." ... Click to view a price quote on HOME . ]] SHREVEPORT, La., Jan. 23, 2014 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Home Federal Bancorp, Inc. of Louisiana (the "Company") (Nasdaq:HFBL), the holding company of Home Federal Bank, reported net income for the three months ended December 31, 2013 of $645,000, a decrease of $236,000 compared to net income of $881,000 reported for the three months ended December 31, 2012. The Company's basic and diluted earnings per share were $0.31 and $0.30, respectively, for the quarter ended December 31, 2013, compared to basic and diluted earnings per share of $0.36 and $0.35, respectively, for the quarter ended December 31, 2012. The Company reported net income of $1.4 million for the six months ended December 31, 2013, a decrease of $461,000 compared to $1.8 million for the six months ended December 31, 2012. The Company's basic and diluted earnings per share were $0.64 and $0.63, respectively, for the six months ended December 31, 2013, compared to $0.73 and $0.71, respectively, for the six months ended December 31, 2012. ... Click to view a price quote on HFBL . ]] IRVINE, Calif., Jan. 23, 2014 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Sabra Health Care REIT, Inc. ("Sabra") (Nasdaq:SBRA) today announced that certain subsidiaries of Sabra (the "Issuers") had received as of 5:00 p.m., New York City time, on January 22, 2014 (the "Consent Expiration"), tenders and consents from the holders (the "Holders") of approximately $210.9 million in aggregate principal amount, or approximately 99.8%, of the Issuers' outstanding 8.125% Senior Notes due 2018 (the "Notes") in connection with their previously announced cash tender offer (the "Offer") to purchase any and all of the Notes and the related solicitation of consents ("Consent Solicitation") from Holders of the Notes to proposed amendments that would eliminate substantially all of the restrictive covenants and certain events of default provisions (the "Proposed Amendments") contained in the indenture governing the Notes (as supplemented, the "Indenture"). The remaining conditions upon which the consummation of the Offer and Consent Solicitation are subject have also been satisfied. As a result, on January 23, 2014, payment of the tender offer consideration of $1,068.37 for each $1,000 principal amount of Notes (the "Tender Offer Consideration"), consent payment of $30.00 for each $1,000 principal amount of Notes and accrued and unpaid interest up to, but not including, January 23, 2014 to Holders who validly tendered and did not revoke Notes prior to the Consent Expiration was made and the supplement to the Indenture implementing the Proposed Amendments was entered into and became operative. The Offer is scheduled to expire at 11:59 p.m., New York City time, on February 5, 2014, unless extended by the Issuers ("Expiration Time"). Tendered Notes may no longer be withdrawn, except to the extent that the Issuers are required by law to provide additional withdrawal rights. Holders who tender their Notes after the Consent Expiration and prior to the Expiration Time will be eligible to receive on the final settlement date, which is expected to be February 6, 2014, the Tender Offer Consideration, plus accrued and unpaid interest to the final settlement date. ... Click to view a price quote on SBRA . ]] Editor's Note: Any reference to TheStreet Ratings and its underlying recommendation does not reflect the opinion of TheStreet, Inc. or any of its contributors including Jim Cramer or Stephanie Link. Trade-Ideas LLC identified American Realty Capital Properties Inc Clas (ARCP) as a "storm the castle" (crossing above the 200-day simple moving average on higher than normal relative volume) candidate. In addition to specific proprietary factors, Trade-Ideas identified American Realty Capital Properties Inc Clas as such a stock due to the following factors:... Click to view a price quote on ARCP . ]] Subscription revenue of $17.6 million up 21% year-over-year Enterprise business unit revenue up 87% year-over-year 42 new customer agreements signed in Q3 Signs Cisco partnership agreement; focus on Internet of Everything DETROIT, Jan. 23, 2014 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Covisint Corporation (Nasdaq:COVS), provider of a leading cloud engagement platform, today announced financial results for the third quarter of its fiscal 2014 ended December 31, 2013. "Covisint continues to produce strong gains in subscription revenue, with a 21% increase year-over-year in Q3," said David McGuffie, President and CEO of Covisint. "We are pleased with our subscription revenue growth, which was driven by both new and existing customer agreements. We expect that subscription revenue will continue to become a larger part of our revenue mix going forward, as the investments we have made in the platform for delivering repeatable, frictionless deployments is paying off for our customers." ... ]] In trading on Friday, shares of the SPDR SP Insurance ETF entered into oversold territory, changing hands as low as $58.96 per share. We define oversold territory using the Relative Strength Index, or RSI, which is a technical analysis indicator used to measure momentum on a scale of zero to 100. A stock is considered to be oversold if the RSI reading falls below 30. In the case of SPDR SP Insurance, the RSI reading has hit 26.9  by comparison, the RSI reading for the SP 500 is currently 38.2. START SLIDESHOW:Find out what 9 other oversold stocks you need to know about  A bullish investor could look at KIE's 26.9 reading as a sign that the recent heavy selling is in the process of exhausting itself, and begin to look for entry point opportunities on the buy side. ... Click to view a price quote on KIE . ]] NEW YORK (TheStreet) -- As I mentioned in The Wrap in yesterday's column, the gold price did nothing through all of Far East and early London trading on their Friday.  But the rally that developed shortly after 11 a.m. GMT got capped about 30 minutes later, with the high tick coming at the noon silver fix. From there, the gold price got sold down until just before noon in New York---and then it chopped quietly higher for the remainder of the day. ... Click to view a price quote on GLD . ]] Contango ORE, Inc. (OTCBB:CTGO.PK) announced today that it has engaged Petrie Partners Securities, LLC to advise the Company on its options going forward, which may include a merger with an existing mining concern, sale for cash, stock, or a combination thereof, a joint venture, or additional exploration on the Tetlin Lease if sufficient funds are available to the Company. The engagement follows the receipt by the Company of the initial mineral resource estimate for the Peak Zone located within the Companys approximately 700,000-acre gold-copper-silver project in east-central Alaska on the Tetlin Lease. The roadaccessible Peak Zone covers only 40 acres of the total lease area. The indicated and inferred resources for the Peak Zone are limited to the area that was intensely drilled in 2012 through 2013, and do not include any estimates for potential extensions of the Peak Zone or any other prospect on the companys historically under-explored leasehold. The following indicated and inferred resource estimates were completed by G.H. Giroux of Giroux Consultants Ltd. of Vancouver, BC, Canada. G.H. Giroux is independent of the company and is the qualified person responsible for the resource estimate. Mr. Giroux is a qualified person by virtue of education, experience and membership in a professional association. Indicated Resources at the Peak Zone, Tetlin project, Alaska.             Grade Cut-off             Cut-off (g/t) (AuEq)     Tonnes Cut-off (tonnes)     Au (g/t)     Ag (g/t)     Cu (%)     AuEq (g/t)     Total Grams     Total Ounces 0.3     6,100,000     3.39     11.67     0.25     4.01     24,461,000     786,439 0.4     6,070,000     3.41     11.71     0.25     4.03     24,462,100     786,475 0.5     5,970,000     3.46     11.00     0.25     4.08     24,357,600     783,115 0.6     5,830,000     3.54     11.95     0.26     4.17     24,311,100     781,620 0.7     5,610,000     3.67     12.14     0.26     4.31     24,179,100     777,376 0.8     5,410,000     3.79     12.29     0.26     4.44     24,020,400     772,274 0.9     5,210,000     3.92     12.45     0.27     4.58     23,861,800     767,175 1.0     5,030,000     4.04     12.57     0.27     4.71     23,691,300     761,693                             Inferred Resources at the Peak Zone, Tetlin project, Alaska.             Grade Cut-off             Cut-off (g/t) (AuEq)     Tonnes Cut-off (tonnes)     Au (g/t)     Ag (g/t)     Cu (%)     AuEq (g/t)     Total Grams     Total Ounces 0.3     3,980,000     2.01     14.07     0.23     2.62     10,427,600     335,255 0.4     3,950,000     2.02     14.11     0.23     2.63     10,388,500     333,998 0.5     3,850,000     2.07     14.28     0.23     2.69     10,356,500     332,969 0.6     3,680,000     2.16     14.56     0.24     2.79     10,267,200     330,098 0.7     3,550,000     2.23     14.76     0.24     2.87     10,188,500     327,568 0.8     3,410,000     2.30     14.95     0.24     2.95     10,059,500     323,420 0.9     3,250,000     2.39     15.24     0.25     3.06     9,945,000     319,739 1.0     3,050,000     2.51     15.64     0.25     3.19     9,729,500     312,811 ... Click to view a price quote on CTGO . ]] COSTA MESA, Calif., Jan. 23, 2014 /PRNewswire/ -- Experian , the leading global information services company, today announced a new product in its market-leading Trended Solutions SM suite  the Estimated Interest Rate Calculator (EIRC) for Revolving Credit  which provides lenders with insightful, optimized tools to make the right credit offers to the right customers. This product uses longitudinal credit data to determine the last six months of interest on consumers' credit cards, which can help credit card lenders make better decisions in the prospecting, underwriting and account management processes. These insights add another dimension to the credit tools lenders are using by providing the ability to identify the effective annual percentage rate (APR), as well as interest and fee revenue generated by each consumer. (Logo: http://photos.prnewswire.com/prnh/20130131/LA51658LOGO) ... ]] Discover Financial Services (NYSE: DFS) today reported net income of $602 million or $1.23 per diluted share for the fourth quarter of 2013, as compared to $539 million or $1.06 per diluted share for the fourth quarter of 2012. The company's return on equity for the fourth quarter of 2013 was 22%. Fourth Quarter Highlights Revenue net of interest expense was up $113 million, or 6%, from the prior year to $2.1 billion. Total loans grew $3.2 billion, or 5%, from the prior year to $65.8 billion. Credit card loans grew $2.0 billion, or 4%, to $53.1 billion and Discover card sales volume increased 3% from the prior year. Net charge-off rate for credit card loans increased 4 basis points from the prior quarter to 2.09% and delinquencies over 30 days past due increased 5 basis points from the prior quarter to 1.72%. Payment Services pretax income was down $6 million from the prior year to $26 million. Transaction dollar volume for the segment was $49.8 billion, down 1% from the prior year. ... Click to view a price quote on DFS . ]] HIGHLIGHTS: Net Income of $26.5 million for the current quarter increased 28 percent from the prior year fourth quarter and net income of $95.6 million for the current year increased 27 percent from the prior year.   Dividend declared of $0.16 per share during the current quarter, the third increase since December 2012, totaling 23 percent.   Glacier Bancorp, Inc. stock price of $29.79 at December 31, 2013 increased 21 percent from the prior quarter and 103 percent from the prior year.   The loan portfolio increased $61.7 million, or 6 percent annualized, during the current quarter. Excluding the acquisitions, the loan portfolio increased $278 million, or 8 percent, during the current year.   Transaction deposit accounts of $3.1 billion increased $103 million, or 14 percent annualized, during the current quarter.   Current quarter net interest margin, on a tax-equivalent basis, of 3.88 percent, an increase of 32 basis points from the prior quarter net interest margin of 3.56 percent.   Interest income for the current quarter of $73.9 million, an increase of 6 percent from the prior quarter, and interest income for the current year of $264 million, an increase of 4 percent from the prior year. Results Summary     Three Months ended Year ended (Dollars in thousands, except per share data) December 31, 2013 September 30, 2013 December 31, 2012 December 31, 2013 December 31, 2012 Net income  $ 26,546 25,628 20,758 95,644 75,516 Diluted earnings per share  $ 0.36 0.35 0.29 1.31 1.05 Return on average assets (annualized) 1.33% 1.27% 1.06% 1.23% 1.01% Return on average equity (annualized) 10.96% 10.85% 9.17% 10.22% 8.54% ... Click to view a price quote on GBCI . ]] Independent Bank Corp., (NASDAQ: INDB), parent of Rockland Trust Company, today announced 2013 fourth quarter net income of $10.6 million, or $0.45 per diluted share, as compared to $14.7 million, or $0.64 per diluted share, in the prior quarter. The Company acquired Mayflower Bancorp, Inc. (Mayflower) on November 15, 2013 and recorded $6.2 million of merger and acquisition costs during the fourth quarter. Net income for the full year was $50.3 million, or $2.18 on a diluted earnings per share basis, as compared to $42.6 million, or $1.95 for the prior year. Net income for the fourth quarter and full year 2013 contained items, such as merger and acquisition expenses and gains on life insurance benefits, security sales, and debt extinguishment, which the Company considers non-core. When excluding such items, net operating earnings for the fourth quarter were $14.2 million, or $0.61 per diluted share, versus the prior quarters net operating earnings of $14.4 million, or $0.63 per diluted share. Net operating earnings for 2013 were $55.2 million, or $2.39 on a diluted earnings per share basis, an increase of 17.2% and 10.7%, respectively, when compared to net operating earnings of $47.1 million, or $2.16 per diluted share in 2012. ... Click to view a price quote on INDB . ]] Highlands Bancorp, Inc. (OTC BB: HSBK.OB) parent company of Highlands State Bank, reported fourth quarter net income of $563,000 in 2013 compared to net income of $1,012,000 for the same period of 2012. Fourth quarter net income available to common stockholders was $545,000 or $.30 per diluted share in 2013 compared to $995,000 or $.56 per diluted share for the same period in 2012. Net income for the full year 2013 was $2,270,000 compared to $1,548,000 for the full year 2012. Net income available to common stockholders for the full year 2013 was $2,201,000 or $1.23 per diluted share compared to $1,484,000 or $.83 per diluted share for the year of 2012. The quarterly and annual results for both 2013 and 2012 were positively impacted by partial reversals of the Companys valuation allowance on deferred tax assets which resulted in tax benefits of $333,000 or $.19 per share for the fourth quarter of 2013 and $640,000 or $.36 per share for the fourth quarter of 2012, and $1,310,000 or $.73 per share and $640,000 or $.36 per share for the years of 2013 and 2012, respectively. Net interest income increased by $134,000 to $2,123,000 for the fourth quarter of 2013 compared to net interest income of $1,989,000 for the fourth quarter of 2012. For the year ended December 31, 2013, net interest income increased to $8,036,000 from $7,237,000 for 2012 as a result of loan portfolio growth and lower cost of funds. The provision for loan losses was $339,000 for the quarter and $727,000 for the year ended December 31, 2013. In 2012, the Companys provision totaled $373,000 and $1,077,000 for the fourth quarter and year respectively. The decrease in the provision for loan losses reflects improvement in non-performing loans and managements continued assessment of the reserves maintained on non-performing loans. Loans increased $28.8 million in 2013 compared to $29.8 million in 2012. Charge-offs for the year ended December 31, 2013 were $762,000 compared to charge-offs of $564,000 in 2012. Recoveries of previously charged off loans totaled $2,000 in 2013, compared to $34,000 in 2012. The ratio of non-performing loans and performing TDRs to total loans declined to 2.69% at year end 2013 from 4.18% at year end 2012. ... Click to view a price quote on HSBK . ]] Click to view a price quote on HLF . ]] TOMS RIVER, N.J., Jan. 23, 2014 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- OceanFirst Financial Corp. (Nasdaq:OCFC), (the "Company"), the holding company for OceanFirst Bank (the "Bank"), today announced that, as a result of the planned series of strategic initiatives disclosed in the third quarter earnings release, diluted earnings per share amounted to $0.11 for the quarter ended December 31, 2013, as compared to $0.23 for the corresponding prior year period. For the year ended December 31, 2013, diluted earnings per share amounted to $0.95, as compared to $1.12 for the prior year. Diluted earnings per share for the quarter and the year ended December 31, 2013 were adversely impacted by $0.19 per diluted share due to the previously announced strategic initiatives relating to the prepayment of $159.0 million of Federal Home Loan Bank ("FHLB") advances, at a cost of $4.3 million, and the consolidation of two branches into newer, in-market facilities, at a cost of $579,000. ... Click to view a price quote on OCFC . ]] LONDON, Jan. 23, 2014 /PRNewswire/ -- Reportbuyer.com just published a new market research report: US LEDs High Efficiency Lighting Market ... ]] FITZGERALD, Ga., Jan. 24, 2014 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Colony Bankcorp, Inc. (Nasdaq:CBAN), today reported net income available to shareholders of $1,241,000, or $0.15 per diluted share for the fourth quarter of 2013 compared to $203,000, or $0.02 per diluted share for the comparable 2012 period, while net income available to shareholders for twelve months ended December 31, 2013 was $3,120,000, or $0.37 per diluted share compared to $1,206,000, or $0.14 per share for the comparable 2012 period. This increase of 158.71 percent in net income for the comparable twelve month period was primarily driven by an increase in net interest income and noninterest income (excluding securities gains)  along with a reduction in provision for loan losses. "In addition to significant core earnings improvement, Colony again had marked improvement in asset quality. Substandard assets to tier one capital plus loan loss allowance ratio improved to 39.22 percent at December 31, 2013 from 40.94 percent at September 30, 2013 and 55.60 percent at December 31, 2012. Though we were successful in having regulatory agencies lift the memorandum of understanding during 2013 and realized significant improvement in earnings and asset quality, we still are committed to reducing our problem assets to an acceptable level and returning to acceptable earnings," said Ed Loomis, President and Chief Executive Officer. "Momentum carrying over from 2013 initiatives has Colony positioned for a successful and productive year in 2014." Capital ... Click to view a price quote on CBAN . ]] The Phoenix Companies, Inc. (NYSE:PNX) today commenced its previously announced solicitation of bondholders holding its 7.45% Quarterly Interest Bonds Due 2032 (CUSIP 71902E 20 8) seeking a consent to amend the indenture governing the bonds and provide a related waiver. The amendment to the terms of the indenture would allow Phoenix to extend to March 16, 2015 the deadline for all SEC reports required to be delivered to the bond trustee prior to that date, but will not alter the companys current obligation to pay principal and interest on the bonds as provided for in the indenture. ... Click to view a price quote on PNX . ]] Fourth Quarter and 2013 Highlights: GAAP earnings of $0.20 per diluted share, consistent with the prior quarter Full-Year 2013 earnings of $0.75 per diluted share compared to $0.40 per diluted share in 2012 Pre-Tax Pre-Provision income increased 3% QOQ Operating expenses declined to $225 million excluding certain nonrecurring items Net interest margin increased 1 basis point QOQ to 3.41% Fee income declined 2% driven by seasonally lower insurance commissions revenues Organic loan growth continues, with average loans up 9% annualized QOQ Average commercial business and real estate loans increased 7% QOQ Continued momentum in indirect auto loans, which increased by $246 million QOQ Noninterest-bearing checking balances increased 8% annualized QOQ Average core deposits increased 3% QOQ driven by higher customer balances Transactional deposits averaged 36% of deposits, up from 32% a year-ago Strong credit quality maintained NCOs averaged 0.34% of originated loans in 2013, consistent with prior year Nonperforming loans equaled 93 basis points of originated loans at year-end BUFFALO, N.Y., Jan. 24, 2014 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- First Niagara Financial Group, Inc. (Nasdaq:FNFG) today reported net income available to common shareholders of $70.1 million or $0.20 per diluted share for the fourth quarter of 2013, highlighted by stable net interest margin, balance sheet growth and positive operating leverage. ... Click to view a price quote on FNFG . ]] Editor's Note: Any reference to TheStreet Ratings and its underlying recommendation does not reflect the opinion of TheStreet, Inc. or any of its contributors including Jim Cramer or Stephanie Link. McKesson (MCK) pushed the Wholesale industry higher today making it today's featured wholesale winner. The industry as a whole closed the day down 0.2%. By the end of trading, McKesson rose $2.69 (1.6%) to $172.37 on heavy volume. Throughout the day, 3,347,840 shares of McKesson exchanged hands as compared to its average daily volume of 1,731,800 shares. The stock ranged in a price between $170.90-$174.30 after having opened the day at $174.14 as compared to the previous trading day's close of $169.68. Other companies within the Wholesale industry that increased today were: Watsco (WSO.B), up 28.5%, China Metro-Rural Holdings (CNR), up 17.1%, Armco Metals Holdings (AMCO), up 3.4% and Louisiana-Pacific (LPX), up 3.2%.EXCLUSIVE OFFER: Jim Cramer's Protege, Dave Peltier, only buys Stocks Under $10 that he thinks could potentially double. See what he's trading today with a 14-day FREE pass.... Click to view a price quote on MCK . ]] BRIDGEVILLE, Pa., Jan. 24, 2014 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Universal Stainless Alloy Products, Inc. (Nasdaq:USAP) announced today that it will report financial results for the fourth quarter of 2013 on Wednesday, February 5, 2014. In conjunction with the earnings release, the Company will host a conference call at 10:00 a.m. (Eastern) on February 5 th. The call will be webcast simultaneously for all interested parties over the Internet. Listeners can access the conference call live at www.univstainless.com . Please allow 5 minutes prior to the call to visit the site to download and install any necessary audio software. After the call has taken place, its archived version will be available at this web site. ... Click to view a price quote on USAP . ]] In trading on Thursday, shares of Rubicon Minerals Corporation (TSX: RMX.TO) crossed above their 200 day moving average of $1.41, changing hands as high as $1.48 per share. Rubicon Minerals Corporation shares are currently trading up about 14.7% on the day. The chart below shows the one year performance of RMX shares, versus its 200 day moving average: START SLIDESHOW:Click here to find out which 9 other Canadian stocks recently crossed above their 200 day moving average ... ]] SAN DIEGO, Jan. 24, 2014 /PRNewswire/ -- SolidProfessor, a SolidWorks Solution Partner focused on delivering the best eLearning resources for CAD, CAM and BIM organizations, today announced that it will demonstrate its industry leading eLearning platform at the SolidWorks World 2014 Conference, being held from January 26-29, 2014 at the San Diego Convention Center, San Diego, California, USA. The 16th annual SolidWorks World Conference brings together designers, engineers, managers, and partners to discuss ideas, trends, and the technology shaping the future of product design. Show attendees will see how SolidProfessor and SolidWorks software allow customers to stay ahead of the curve with the latest design practices, standardize skills across a global team, and get the most out of the design tools they rely on. (Logo: http://photos.prnewswire.com/prnh/20140124/PH52037LOGO) ... ]] 