 Apparatus After identifying the materials and subjects of the study, the apparatus or equipment used in the study are described. If the apparatus is not well known within an area of study, it should be described in detail. If an apparatus is used by participants in the study, you will need to describe from the participants perspective how this apparatus was used: As soon as the participants heard the bell ring, they pressed a button placed one foot from their desk, which recorded the time lapse between hearing the bell and pressing the button. You will also need to provide enough detail for anyone wishing to replicate the study. (Szuchman, L. T, 1999). This may range from describing an apparatus as simple as the mesh-size of a net used to sample fish, to details about a novel use for complex high-throughput devices for sequencing millions of DNA samples. Be sure to mention and limitations of the apparatus, and precautions taken to compensate for these shortcomings. If it was operating on settings other than the default settings, be sure to list whatever changes were made to the settings of the apparatus. Also, when describing elements of the apparatus, be sure to be consistent with the names used. In other words, do not say that participants pushed a red button in one section, and then later refer to it as a red switch. (Szuchman, L. T., 1999). Typically the names and addresses of manufacturers of well known apparatuses are given in parentheses. Any modifications to a well known apparatus should described here as well. A schematic diagram or photograph of the apparatus may be included, especially for novel or non-standard equipment used. If you need to describe in detail a novel apparatus that you constructed for the study, you may include this information in an appendix. (Szuchman,1999) In chapter 6, we noted how subjunctive clauses are used to communicate message of urgency or necessity. You might see warnings in a method section like the sentences below using the subjunctive. If you do not remember this construction, you may want to review subjunctive clauses in chapter 6. It is imperative that this flammable coating is applied in a well ventilated room. The manufacturers guidelines require that samples be sealed in a water-proof container. Since this is a known carcinogen it is highly recommended that standard laboratory safety practices be carefully followed when using this reagent. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] Data Analysis The content of the Data Analysis section will vary according to the type of statistical analysis used in your study. This section typically begins with a statement on how the data was summarized, including a measure of central tendency and the variability (Zeiger, M. 1999). For normally distributed data, the mean and the standard deviation typically summarize the data. For skewed data, the mean and the inter-quartile range give a more precise summary of the data: The median water withdrawn was 2.0 m 3 of water per ton of sugar cane, and the lower and upper quartile were 1.4 and 4.0 m 3 of water per ton of sugar cane, respectively (Fig. 2). In this section, the tests used for statistical analysis are identified. If you used a well-known test such as the Students t test, Chi-Square, or Wilcoxian signed-rank test, no reference is necessary. For less well-known tests, include a reference to a source that describes the test in detail. The following standard statistical tests were used for between-group comparison purposes: chi-square test; Fishers exact test; Students independent sample t  test; Mann-Whitney test, and Kruskal-Wallis test. This section should also include a statement on the P value in which differences are considered statistically significant: A p-value of 0.002 was considered significant. The data gathered will determine the statistical tests used in your study (Leedy P. D., 1997). While there is a wide variety of methods for testing and analyzing data, statistical testing has its limits. Gustavii, for example, advises caution when comparing baseline characteristics by statistical tests since a minor imbalance in a key prognostic factor can have a profound effect on a treatment comparison, even when the imbalance shows no significance. Significance testing can thus obscure an important imbalance. Therefore, in addition to the statistical testing (some experts say instead of statistical testing) compare the baseline characteristics with the use of clinical experience- and common sense ( Gustavii, B. 2008). Identify the computer software used in your data analysis, including the version, release number, and any non-default settings used. All analyses were performed through a SPSS software package for Windows Release 11.0.1 (15 Nov 2001) Various software programs are commonly used to analyze data, presenting numerous advantages including accuracy, speed and variety of perspectives: numerous tests and analysis can be performed on data in a matter of minutes. Yet, whatever analysis is being done, the ultimate interpretation will depend on the researchers understanding of the various tests and results of the analyses. For example, testing and rejecting the null hypothesis, only indicates that a significant difference between one data set and another exists. No computer software can fully interpret what this difference means. Ultimately, it is the researcher who needs to synthesize and interpret the results of the data analysis, providing compelling and new perspectives or insights into the data (Leedy, P. D. 1997) http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] Extended vs. Abbreviated Methods An overview of the study design is followed by a description of the methods and apparatus used. For quantitative studies, your goal is to give just enough information for a competent researcher in your field to be able to understand what you did, so that if they wished to, they could replicate your experiment. Although it may not be likely that anyone would replicate your study, if the journal editors are not convinced that they could carry out and replicate your study, your paper would be rejected. Consequently, you will need to take great care, being quite meticulous and detail-oriented in writing the Materials and Methods section. Of course, your ability to present a precisely detailed methods section is contingent upon your ability to maintain detailed notes during the experiments in a lab notebook. However, while you need to provide sufficient precise and detailed information for another researcher to replicate your study, you will need to be very careful not to give unnecessary detail. As Goldbort points out, rather than exhaustive detail or familiar minutiae, the priniciples on which the methods are based are more important to explain. (2006) A great deal of the information recorded in your lab notebook will not be necessary to include in the methods section. Finding a balance between providing too much or too little is a typical trouble spot of this section of the paper. If you are using a well-known method, it should not be described in detail, but instead a simple one sentence citation will suffice: Balb/c mice were immunized according to the protocol described by Farias et al. (2002). The amplification and primer selection was carried out as previously described (Wilson et al., 2007). Colonies were quantified and identified by classical phenotypic tests [17]. However, be careful with this sort of citation: if the method has been published but is not well-known, the reader would likely appreciate a few details about what was done: We surveyed the participants using the Primary Care Evaluation of Mental Disorders (Nelson, 2009). NOT: We surveyed the participants as done elsewhere (Nelson, 2009). Additionally, if you make significant changes to a well-known protocol, you need to specify the changes that you made. Swales and Feaks note that in general the material and method section can be either abbreviated or extended (2004). Using an abbreviated methods section assumes the reader has certain background knowledge about the subject. Consequently, abbreviated methods tend to provide less explanation, justification, definitions, examples and subsections with headings. An abbreviated methods section is more apt to rely on acronyms, abbreviated information in parenthesis, and citations without much elaboration. Abbreviated methods also tend to use compound verb clauses as opposed to a series of longer sentences with single verbs. See chapter 7 on telegraphic style for examples. Conversely, extended methods sections tend to provide more background knowledge, using subsections with headlines, as well as purpose statements, examples, and definitions. Extended methods sections are more commonly used in a dissertation, as well in research papers that use novel unknown methods. The subject of your paper and your audience will influence your choice using an extended or abbreviated method. If for example, the method of your paper is novel and significantly different from previous attempts to approach the topic you are considering, then you will need to create a more extended methods section. If however, the method you use in your paper has been commonly used in the past to address your topic, then an abbreviated method section would be the best choice. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] Study Design and Procedures Carried Out The descriptions of the materials, animal subjects or human participants and apparatus of the study is often followed by an overview of the study design, which begins by re-naming the original question or purpose identified in the introduction. This section typically lists in chronological order the interventions, measurements and experiments performed, as well as the duration of these events (Zeiger, 1999). In general, the study is described from the perspective of how the researcher organized the experiments. However, if human participants are involved, describe the particular tasks they performed from their perspective. In other words, do not say the experimenter gave the participants something to read, rate, rank, listen to or watch. Instead say the participants read, rated, ranked, listened to, or watched something (Szuchman, 1999). This section names the independent variables (interventions) and dependent variables (variables measured), as well as information about control groups and baseline measurements. This section will also clearly name any underlying assumptions the experimental design is based upon (Zieger, 1999). A strong study design will aim to minimize the influence of extraneous (Zobel, 2004) factors on the results. Be aware of any factors in a given experiment that may make it a special case limited to the variables and conditions of your study rather than a case that can be generalized beyond your study (Zobel, 2004). Certain benchmark tests and standard data are typically used to ensure that results are not the product of differences in data sets. When it not possible to used standardized data, then you should try to ensure that the data is representative (Zobel, 2004). Specify the conditions of the study and whether all animal subjects and human participants were subject to the same conditions or whether they were divided into groups subjected to various conditions. Whenever possible, for the sake of the reader, use names for groups that more clearly identify rather than general names such as Group A or Group B (Szuchman,1999). Non-alcohol consuming group exhibited better absorption of the formulation than the alcohol consuming group. NOT: Group A exhibited better absorption of the formulation than Group B. In some rare cases where this may be relevant, it is recommended to list hazards or potential problems that may ensue when replicating the experiments. You may indicate warnings in a separate paragraph labeled Caution( http://owl.english.purdue.edu , 2009). Choosing the best possible study design will require extensive knowledge of the limits and strengths of various possible experiment designs as well as a strong understanding of your data. It is useful to explain to the reader why you chose one design over another: do not take for granted that your reader will understand why you made certain choices. (Leedy P. D., 1997). If it is unclear to the reader as to why certain procedures were done, then clearly explain why: This lineage was chosen because it was derived from normal lung tissue of a 12-week-old male fetus and therefore was intended to be similar to the lung tissue of patients. A strong study design, in addition to including experiments that will most likely verify your hypothesis, should consider data in which the hypothesis is least likely to be verified as well. Such experiments and results may be even more instructive than those that are likely to verify your hypothesis. If experiments produce anomalous results, then further tests should be designed to investigate and eliminate these results. Ideally, experiments should be designed that provide unambiguous results that answer the main question of the text Include some details about how the study was well randomized. Again if your method of randomizing is well known, then great detail is not necessary: A randomized crossover trial was used as study design... The experimental design was a 4 x 4 factorial in complete randomized blocks, with four replications. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] There are unlimited possible topics for research papers, and the research and methods used to address the questions of these papers are equally varied. Some possible topics of Engineering research papers might include studying the wear characteristics of building materials; innovations in electronic circuitry or neural networks; improving algorithms for computer graphics functions, improving plans of escape on passenger airlines; evaluating and improving an emergency fire-response system on an oil tanker; improving GPS and other monitoring systems of illegal logging in the Amazon; understanding the signal pathway of certain human cells; designing and improving insulators for heavy-duty electrical power lines. The methods and procedures used for each of these problems require a wide variety of methods that are not easily categorized. Add to this, the variety of types of research done in the Physical Sciences, Social Sciences and Humanities, and it becomes difficult to provide precise general rules that apply in all cases to writing the methods sections. Yet, despite the wide variety of research methods, some general patterns can be seen across in most fields of study. We will review some of these common features below and end the chapter considering some of the differences seen across these areas of study. The main purpose of the method section is to report on what experiments, simulations, interviews, analysis of proofs, surveys, modeling, or fieldwork was done to answer the main question or hypothesis of the introduction. Depending upon your field of study, this section is sometimes identified as the Materials and Methods, the Experimental Design, Theory, Protocol, or Procedure. In section three, we review the sections of a research paper in their typical chronological order, beginning with the title and abstract in chapter 8, and ending with the discussion, yet, most authors do not write their paper in this same chronological order. In fact, after creating their tables and figures, they begin by writing the materials and method section and then results, and not the abstract and introduction. Since you will be very familiar with the content of this section, being the most concrete section of your paper, and since many of the protocols of this section are well known and have been previously published, and since the methods section does not require you to interpret the meaning of the results but simply report what was done, you may be like most authors who find this section the easiest to write. My own editing experience supports this claim with the material and method section having the fewest number of errors compared to other sections of a paper. Nonetheless, journal editors commonly reject papers due to errors in the method section. So, great care and attention need to be given to accuracy and detail of the method section. Journal editors and referees may criticize a method section for several reasons. While you cannot anticipate every particular criticism of a referee, you should at least be able to address the following shortcomings: a failure to elaborate on experimental assumptions and design; the experiments are not verifiable or reproducible; the text is confusing; incorrect technical specifications; numbers do not add up; insufficient number of experiment repetitions; too much irrelevant information; too little description of anomalous experiments and results; no discussion of limits of the apparatus and equipment or precautions taken to avoid limitations; statistical analysis that are inadequate, or dubious choices in the study design. This chapter focuses on some typical features found in a variety of methods sections in a wide range of studies and fields. Knowing some general guidelines, features and patterns of the methods section before you begin writing will make the task easier. In addition, this chapter focuses on several common English trouble spots of the Methods section. Organization The organization pattern of the materials section typically follows the chronological order of your experiments, analysis of proofs or field work, but there may be some sections within the chronological scheme that use a most-to-least-important structure. For instance, while the overall methods section may be organized chronologically, for a complex topic under a certain sub heading that has more than one paragraph, a most-to-least important structure may used to organize this section. If for example, numerous variables were measured together, then it is common to report the most important results first, followed by less important results. Another possible organizational pattern is general to specific. Subheadings are commonly used to indicate the organizational order of the methods section. We will consider subheadings later, but for now, note some typical organizational subheadings found in biomedical papers in Table 1 Table 1 Animal Studies Clinical Studies Materials Animals Preparation Study Design Interventions Methods of Measurement Calculations Analysis of Data Study Participants Inclusion Exclusion Criteria Study Design Interventions Methods of Measurement Calculations Analysis of Data The best guide for organizing your materials section will be provided either by the journal to whom you will submit your paper or one of the style guides mentioned below. You can find guidelines for organizing the methods section at the journals webpage in a section called guidelines for authors or information for authors. Some journals will specify their expectations in great detail, others will name a few minor guidelines and others will simply refer the authors to a certain text such as the CBE Manual for Authors, The Publication Manual of the American Psychological Association, the Chicago Manual of Style, MLA Handbook for Writers of Research Papers, the AMA Handbook of Style or the IEE Editorial Style Manual. If the journal does not specify guidelines for subheadings, consider one these more general style manuals affiliated with your field of study. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] Numbers There are some common rules regarding numbers that represent quantitative data in research papers. Knowing these rules will be helpful for writing the material and method section as well as other sections of the paper: Represent numbers under eleven using the word: eleven, nine, five, etc, whereas for numbers above eleven use digits: 12, 136, 1,200, etc. Use numerals even for numbers below ten when comparing with numbers above ten: A total of 5 out of 24 of the respondents dropped out of the study. Be careful with convention of using commas with numbers. Brazil as well as other countries in the world use a comma (virgula) with numbers where a decimal (ponto) point is used in the US: 3.5 % NOT: 3,5 % Be careful with compound nouns that report numbers. All words preceding the head noun must be singular since they function like adjectives. In English, adjectives are always singular: A 36-day-old rat. NOT: a 36 day s old rat. A three-month old infant NOT: a three month s old infant Do not begin a sentence with a digit; instead use the word form for the number in question. Fifty-six rats were used. NOT: 56 rats were used. Do not confuse certain words dealing with quantity and distance: Lower/lesser; further/farther Lower = below another quantitative measurement: Lower temperatures were recorded for sample B. Lesser = not so great or important as something else; applied more to abstract concepts. Although this economic plan had serious flaws, it was the lesser of two evils. Farther = a greater measurable distance than another. Farther down the mountain, the vegetation turns to grassland. Further = to a greater degree than something else; applies more to abstract concepts. Further studies are needed to understand the mating habits of this mollusk. The terms twice vs. two times have essentially the same meaning, except that twice is favored for being shorter. The specimens were disrupted by sonication two times for 45 s at 5  C. The specimens were disrupted by sonication twice for 45 s at 5  C. Use the term circa with historical dates, but not with measurements. The temple was destroyed circa 1432 BCE. NOT: Circa 542 birds were sighted. NOT: Circa 2ml was added to the buffer. Note below that certain journals such as Science Magazine advise against using such imprecise expressions as a three-fold rise, an eight-orders-of-magnitude increase, two-fold increase, two times as much , but instead prefer the author to give a more precise numerical percentage (Science/AAAS: Science Magazine 2009): Avoid using "-fold" because expressions such as "20-fold smaller" are imprecise; use percentages, proportions, orders of magnitude, or "factor of" instead. (Exception: Usage such as "1000-fold excess" is appropriate.) When describing a decade use this form: In the 1970s During the 1980s NOT: In the 70s NOT: In the Seventies NOT: in the 70s Ordinals, such as first, eleventh, ninety-second , among others, are used far more commonly in English than in some languages. Consequently, it is worth investing your time to learn their form, especially if you plan to do research in an English speaking country, where they are used regularly to record certain quantitative data. Do not confuse their form: 23 rd NOT: 23th 2 nd NOT: 2st Eleventh, twelfth, thirteenth, NOT: eleventeen, twelveteen, Use the short numerical form rather than the longer word form in when discussing centuries: Then 19 th Century NOT: The nineteenth Century Use the percent symbol (%) whenever a numeral accompanies it: A total of .053 % NOT: .053 percent http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] Qualitative Methods of Social Science and Arts and Humanities papers A scholar or researcher from the Social Sciences or Arts and Humanities may not find the information provided thus far not entirely useful for the type of research they do, nor papers they write. Consequently, some points are made below on the differences between Physical Science versus Social Science and Arts and Humanities methods. Social Sciences While the methods section of a Social Science text often resemble the quantitative model of Physical Science papers, they may also incorporate a mix of quantitative and qualitative data or be solely based on qualitative research and data. Likewise, some Physical Science papers are a mix of quantitative and qualitative research. This change from quantitative to qualitative methods in recent decades reflects a growing disenchantment among Social Scientists with the limits of quantitative data and experimental models of the Physical Sciences, as well as a greater appreciation for qualitative data in understanding certain social phenomena. Instead of the hard numerical data and methods of Physical Science, Social Scientists focus more on soft verbal qualitative data for significant social and behavior trends, revealing these trends may involve observations, taped-interviews, surveys, and even researcher engagement and dialogue with the target community, and other soft data and methods. In general terms, the Physical sciences deal with numerical data, while the Social Sciences and Arts and Humanities deal more with verbal data. Such differences in data require different paradigms of research. Since qualitative research operates in an entirely different paradigm than the Physical Sciences, you should not squander precious space trying to justify your choice of qualitative methods by doing an in-depth literature review on the history of qualitative research. Researchers in your field will know the history of qualitative research methods and will not need to be convinced of their value. Those researchers from the Physical Sciences who may happen to read your paper will either be compelled by the results of your study or not, but lengthy justifications may have little impact on swaying such readers. So do not be tempted to dress your research in a quasi-objective scientific manner: instead, rest confident that your work addresses topics that would be poorly served by a strict scientific model. The data of qualitative research in most cases are fairly straightforward narrative responses from the subjects of the study. In qualitative studies, there will be less focus on the methodical and precise measurements of the Physical Sciences, and more painstaking attention is given to thick description and deep contextualization of the subjects of the study. While qualitative data can now be processed by software resembling those of the Physical Sciences, many qualitative researchers primarily rely on simply spreading out surveys and other data on the living room floor, and meticulously sorting, performing multiple re-readings and interpretations to compile results. Likewise, qualitative researchers are not concerned with providing the kind of elaborate details about the method used as can be found in the methods of a Physical Science paper. Again, the story that is told with the results will be more compelling than the software or other techniques used to compile or analyze the data. Unlike in the Physical Sciences, the qualitative researcher does not need to provide precise elaboration of their method because they are not claiming that their work can be precisely reproduced. In fact, it is clear that another researcher asking the same questions in a survey, for example, will most likely get a different answer ( Wolcott, H. F. 2009). Novice authors of qualitative research should avoid the urge to justify their method section by steeping it in a highly technical or contrived scientific guise: no amount of justification will convince certain skeptics. The strongest proof of the method is a unique perspective resulting from fairly simple methods. This new perspective will succeed if it resonates with the reader and provides new and richer insight into the phenomena at hand. Organization and Study Design The following section is indebted to (Leedy P. D., 1997). Below I have paraphrased his description of the organization and study design of qualitative research. Qualitative research can involve various methods. I begin with a summary of case studies and ethnography and follow with a summary of some of the other common qualitative methods commonly used. Case studies focus on one phenomena or subject. Their goals may be to learn about a specific and unique subject, or they may seek to learn more about a larger group by focusing on one person as an exemplar. They may aim simply to describe in detail a certain phenomenon, or they may attempt to evaluate it as well. The primary goal is to describe certain phenomenon from the perspective of the participants. A case study, may involve, for example, learning how residents of a psychiatric residential site experience life in their community. Typically, researchers spend extended periods of time in the study site, primarily watching people in their own territory interacting with them in their own language, on their own terms (Leedy P. D., 1997). The researchers often interact with the people studied and become personally involved with the people and phenomenon studied. Another common qualitative study involving observation is ethnography (Leedy P. D., 1997). As opposed to the more singular focus of a case study, ethnography typically involves a larger focus on a group and its culture. While ethnography originally developed in Anthropology, it is commonly found in education, psychology and sociology. While a culture was once defined as practices of a large populations of people, currently it is not uncommon to see studies at the micro level considering the culture of a coffee shop, or culture of a graffiti artists. Data Collection Case studies may involve a certain amount of quantitative data as well as qualitative data. Various quantitative measurements such as medical tests, academic achievement tests, can be incorporated into the study. Yet the researchers primary means of data collection will be engaging the subject in conversations, or observing them interacting in the study site. The focus is in understanding how a phenomenon is experienced by the subjects of the study. As with case studies, the data collection for ethnography involves fieldwork at a specific site, involving conversations with community members as well as observations of group interactions. (Leedy). While the study originally begins with a focus on a narrowly defined set of questions, these questions may evolve and be redefined as the researcher is further immersed in understanding the culture studied. Likewise, as this happens, the interviews and observations will become more focused from a new perspective. (Leedy) Ethnographic data collection may involve a combination of a data sets. The researchers themselves may participate in certain events to gain a certain perspective. Unlike the random sampling procedure of quantitative studies, ethnographers may intentionally choose a certain person to be interviewed with the explicit purpose of gaining a unique insights from them. The questions of the interviews will tend to also be open-ended to allowing the study subject maximum freedom to answer. In addition, ethnographic data collection may involve examining various artifacts including letters, journals and diaries, as well as legal documents , such as internal communication of an organization, and objects such as artwork, music lyrics, drawings, and posters. The researcher may use an audio or video record as well as extensive notes in a journal. The primary data sources (interviews and observations of subjects) may be combined with secondary data such as questionnaires and other documents such as student test scores or census reports. Data Analysis There are two common types of data analysis for case studies and ethnography (Leedy). The first type, according to Leedy involves searching for patterns, themes, structures or concepts in the data. This first approach does not attempt to interpret the meaning of the data, but simply reports the patterns observed. This first approach may strive to create a more objective and neutral tone of language as seen in quantitative studies. A second approach commonly used to analyze the data involves more explicit evaluation of the data (Leedy P. D., 1997). This approach may be more apt to rely on intuition and judgment in analyzing the data. The authors of such studies may be less concerned about appearing objective and neutral in tone, and more willing to use literature or drama to bring the reader closer to the life experience of the subject of the study. While case studies are more focused on analyzing the meaning of a specific phenomenon for a particular person, ethnographers will analyze the meaning of their data as it has meaning to a group in relation to its culture. The analysis may involve slow careful readings of interviews and thoughtful summaries of their meaning. Such analysis will be repeated again and again until layers of meaning develop and begin to suggest a larger connected perspective. Authors of ethnographies and case studies will typically quote some event or dialogue that is emblematic of culture or specific phenomenon studied. The authors summarize and highlight certain points or assertions that are embodied in such quotes. Such assertions are the outcome of lengthy and rigorous examining, categorizing, analyzing and synthesizing the data. In addition to a case study or ethnography, there are numerous types of qualitative research methods used in a wide variety of studies, including phenomenological-hermeneutical, grounded theory, critical theory, action network, dialectical, constructivist, and postmodernist. These different approaches have different goals and fundamental assumptions. As Leedy points out, Phenomenological-hermenutical studies typically focus on topics that are meaningful to the authors, relying solely on interviews of small groups purposefully chosen for their unique perspectives, focusing on their analysis on certain phrases of the respondents considered heavily laden with meaning. Critical theory, on the other hand, is explicitly committed to supporting a certain disempowered community. For example, the methodology of Participatory Rural Appraisal and the Antigonish Movement is heavily influenced by Paulo Freires educational philosophy, which assumes that rural community development depends upon active, empowered, and informed community members. Action-network research is another method that aims to address practical problems, but more typically is used to evaluate programs and policies, possibly in a school, institution, or other social organization. Some type of action is initiated then the outcome is studied with the intention of finding practical and immediate solutions. Aside from the differences in methods and goals, these various approaches have much in common with case studies and ethnography: repeated cycles of careful reflection and interpretation of social situations. Arts and Humanities Research papers from the Arts and Humanities are even further removed from the preoccupation with hard data of the Physical Sciences. The data of Humanities papers may involve multiple close readings, both analyzing and interpreting the meaning of a philosophical text, painting, musical score, poem, historical artifact, or cultural practice. The heart of a Humanities paper resembles qualitative research in that it may involve numerous cycles of examining and interpreting, and then examining and re-interpreting, adding each time nuanced levels of understanding and depth to the papers topic. In recent decades, Humanities paper have re-examined classic texts as well as cultural phenomena through various methods and interpretive approaches including novel perspectives of post-colonial discourse, hermeneutics, discourse analysis, postmodernism, deconstruction, post-structuralism, as well as analysis of class, race or gender. Depending upon the journal, a Humanities paper can be quite freeform compared to more formulaic Physical Science papers. You may not find the distinct sections of the standard IMRAD paper in a humanities paper, nor the elaborate materials and methods section like in Physical Science papers. However, there may be a parallel discussion about the materials examined and the methods used to examine the material. The success of a Humanities paper is determined more by the compelling logic of its interpretations and arguments as well as creative use of language and reasoning than by empirical data as in Physical Science papers. For example, a history paper will need to elaborate the method of collecting data. Documentation of primary and secondary sources will be a major focus as well as clear and persuasive interpretations of the data. Despite differences between papers from Social Science, Humanities and Physical Sciences, all three types of papers share a common structure and characteristic of further explicating certain unknown ideas and phenomena, providing new methods and means of addressing certain problems, as well as contributing new perspectives to their field of study. ======================================================================== In this chapter, we reviewed various topics relevant to the materials and method section of research papers, in the next chapter, we will review various topics critical to creating a well structured and coherent results section of a research paper. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] Tense of Methods Section As previously mentioned, the materials and method section is mostly written in the past tense and passive voice . Note the differences between the passive and active voice below. Active voice: In a sentence formed in the active voice, the subject performs the action of the verb: We dried and stored the samples. (subject) (verb) Passive voice: In a sentence written in the passive voice, the subject is the recipient of the action of the verb: Samples were dried and stored. (subject) (verb) The past passive tense is frequently used in the method section. The past tense is used because the experiments are finished and done. The passive voice is used because it places the focus on what was done and not who did something: Samples were plated and store . NOT: We plated and stored samples. The passive voice is traditionally used in methods sections of research papers. Occasionally the passive voice is used with a by-phrase naming the agent of the action as well: A census was administered by the department of Anthropology of USP . On the other hand, increasingly more writing style guidebooks recommend using the active voice in research papers. Despite the general preference of the active voice in general writing guidebooks, most of the Physical Sciences continue, for good reasons, to use the passive voice since it places the focus on what was done to something, but not who did something to something. In addition, a series of sentences using the active voice could be monotonous: We sorted and weighed the samples. Then we freeze dried them and then we stored them for 2 weeks. Next we thawed out the samples in.... Russey points out, there is no need to wax poetic. Readers expect to put up with a multitude of bland, impersonal, passive constructions in this section, although you should try not to build every sentence according to the tiresome was done model. Alternative formulations supply welcome variety. (Russey, W. E., Ebel, H. F., Bliefert, C. 2006). For example, consider such alternatives to the passive voice: It proved advantageous to... This was accomplished by... In this way it became possible http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] Figures and Tables Figures and Tables allow authors to present complex data in a simple visual display that allows the reader to understand results far easier than by a narrative description. Since Figures and Tables are time-consuming to create, and costly to publish, one of the first things you will need to determine whether you need to use them instead of a narrative description. If the results are simple and straight forward and easily described in a few sentences, then figures and tables are unnecessary. However, if you have multiple variables and numerous readings of these values, then figures and tables are needed. Likewise, if you are using figures and tables you should be sure that you do not repeat the same information in a table that can already be viewed in a given figure. Another common error is describing in detail in a text what can be seen clearly in figures or tables. While a certain amount of description may be necessary and inevitable, strive not to repeat what can readily seen in the tables and figures. Figures include anything in a research paper that is not a table, text, or formula. To create figures and tables, you should begin by reading the guidelines for authors provided by the journal you are targeting. We cannot review here all the various technical details related to creating various figures and tables since they could easily fill a book by themselves, but instead, we will look at a few issues related to the language of figures and tables. While there are many good guidebooks that provide extensive coverage of the technical details involved in creating figures and tables, I recommend The Art of Scientific Writing (Matthews, J. R., 2007). Every figure should be accompanied by the term Figure followed by a decimal point and a number: Figure.1, Figure.2, etc. You can write out the entire word figure or provide it as an abbreviation: fig. 1, for example. While you have a choice here to abbreviate or not, it is more common in a citation to abbreviate. Figures for longer texts such as dissertations and books may also have two numbers. The first number designates the chapter or subdivision of a text, while the next number, followed by a dash (-) designates the figure number: Chapter 1: Fig. 1-1, Fig. 1-2, Fig. 1-3, Fig. 1-4, etc. Chapter 2: Fig. 2-1, fig. 2-2, Fig. 2-3, etc Whatever form you choose, be consistent throughout the text: Fig. 1, Fig. 2, Fig. 3, etc. NOT: figure 1, Fig 2, Figure. 3.0, figure four, etc. This marker should be accompanied by a short description of the figure, which is known as a caption and functions much like the title of a book or research paper. It should be brief and without verbs. Yet even though it is not a complete sentence it should be followed by a period: Fig. 1. I mmunohistochemical staining for KDZ1 in non-tumoral and tumoral cells. If the caption does not sufficiently describe the figure for the reader, authors commonly include a legend to supplement the caption. A legend provides additional text that may explain certain results, methods, parameters and measurements that may be needed to clarify the figure: Figure 1 . RP-HPLC profiles of the crude Gly-Cys-Phe-NH 2 (10 m g) resulting from traditional SPPS ( A ), SPPS at 60 C using conventional heating ( B ) and microwave- assisted SPPS ( C ). Gly-D-Cys-L-Phe-NH 2 ( D ). RP-HPLC iden tification of the isomer present in B spiked by D ( E ). Analytical conditions : Column: Vydac C 18 , solvent A: 0.1% TFA/H 2 O; solvent B: 90% ACN/H 2 O containing 0.09% TFA, l : 210 nm, flow rate: 1.0 mL/min, linear gradient: 0 to 66% B in 33 min. Components identified by LC/ESI-MS: 1 = desired LLL peptide; 2 = analogue Gly-Cys-Phe-Phe-NH 2 ; 3 = peptide isomer LDL Again, legends should be as brief as possible. As mentioned in chapter 8, gapping can be used to shorten captions and legend of figures by simply omitting non-essential prepositions, articles and other words to create a telegraphic style. See chapter 8 for examples. While figures and tables typically appear at the end of a paper in the results or discussion section, they are often the first part of a paper to be created by the author. Just as a picture is worth a thousand words, strong figures provide a visual summary of the data that quickly communicate the main findings as well as or better than lengthy description may. Consequently, it is logical that the author begins by creating figures and tables since they display the heart of the research and define the direction of the papers story. Ultimately, figures and tables should be able to stand-alone: the reader should be able to understand them without referring to the text. Since figures and tables are such unique visual tools used to powerfully and efficiently communicate the core meaning of a study, it is essential that they are carefully crafted to communicate the message as clearly as possible. Take as much time as possible to revise them so that they seem as clear and cogent as possible. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] The most common tense form used in the results section is the past tense. Results are reported in the past tense since the experiments are completed. X increased but Y remained constant. ` However, the present tense is also common in the results section since you will need to discuss factual details that are continuously true. The present tense describes general unchanging laws of nature as well as patterns and behaviors that are generally consistent and unchanging like laws of nature: Water freezes at 0 celsius. The State Park of Serra do Mar is located in the State of Sao Paulo. Capybaras live close to some body of water and even mate in water. Scavenging, or necrophagy, is a carnivorous feeding behaviour in which a predator consumes corpses or carrion that were not killed to be eaten by the predator or others of its species (Wikipedia). Vocabulary for Describing Data Certain words are commonly used in the results section to describe the degree of intensity of phenomena. Below in Table 1 you will find adverbs, nouns and adjectives categorized according to a numerical percentage of frequency or intensity. Some words can describe sounds (faint, blaring, muted); health conditions (robust, feeble); evaluations of importance (inconsequential, substantial); sensations (faint); colors (dim, pale, subdued). Also note that in some contexts, some of these words have additional subjective negative connotations and should be used with this in mind (paltry, trivial, trifling, feeble, pitiful, meager, utterly, inordinately, extremely, merely). Study the meaning of these words. If words like never seem too basic to you, then study less commonly known words like plethora, seldom, markedly, hardly, perfused, and barely. Note that few X means a lesser amount than a few X and also connotes an insufficiency. Also note that these words can be used in adjective as well as adverb form: substantial, substantially. While these words are commonly used to report the results, their meaning can be subjective and unclear. As Le Brun points out what is fast today is slow in tomorrows research (Lebrun, 2007). To avoid ambiguity, these words are typically combined with precise numerical values: a fast thristor is less clear than a 20Ghz thristor (Lebrun, 2007). Note some examples below: Inflation increased considerably during the second (12.7%) and third (11.6%) quarter of 2009. NOT: Inflation increased considerably during the second and third quarter of 2009. The enamel wear seen in protocol 2 was significantly higher than that observed for protocol 3, for both layers (t =5.737, p NOT: The enamel wear seen in protocol 2 was significantly higher than that observed for protocol 3, for both layers. Note that in English, unlike in Portuguese, adverbs are typically placed before the verb they modify: The respondents (13%) occasionally complained about noise from the nearby airport. However, when used to stress something, adverbs can follow after the verb. This pattern in English is also the opposite of Portuguese: The sleep of some respondents due to the noise was reduced considerably. While there is no simple formula for choosing appropriate words, you should be aware of the different meanings and connotations these words carry. Journal editors and referees often question the particular words chosen by an author to describe the results and data, so it is worth your trouble to study and be careful with words choice in describing data. Table 1 (Woops! By posting here, I lost the formatting and table columns. Hope you can make sense of this by noting the degrees represented by various minus (-) and plus signs (++++) Vocabulary Describing Degree Intensity 0-10% 10-40% 40-70% 70-90% 90-100% (-) never none empty ====== faint almost never barely dim few X hardly immaterial in short supply incidental inconsequential inconsiderable insignificant irrelevant lacking mere miniscule muted negligible pale paltry pitiful rarely scant scarcely seldom slightly subdued trifling trivial (+) a few X a smattering of at times as little as every so often from time to time in some measure infrequently intermittently minor now and then occasionally once in awhile on occasion partly periodically quite rather scattered some sometimes spasmodically sporadically to a lesser degree to a lesser degree to a point to lesser extent to name a few (++) a greater number of a large part a majority of customarily fairly common habitually moderately oftentimes predominant preponderance quite common rather common regularly routinely some sometimes somewhat the bulk of to a certain degree to some degree to some extent (+++) a great deal of a plethora of X a rash of X an abundance of X considerably copious amounts countless frequently greatly highly innumerable intensely major multitude of myriad notable noteworthy numerous often plentiful significantly strongly substantially to a great extent typically widely widespread worldwide (++++) absolutely accutely almost full blaringly completely entirely deeply exceedingly exceptionally extremely filled fully highly keenly inordinately markedly mostly nearly all overwhelmingly perfused profoundly rife with saturated sorely thoroughly totally utmost utterly vastly wholly without exception Exercise 3 Choose the correct words to complete the sentences below. 1. Phosphate run-off into nearby rivers from farming fertilizers increased (500-fold) ___________(considerably/hardly), resulting in a ________ (plethora/scarcity) of algae blooms in the pond. 2. Since the reception towers were blocked by hundreds miles of rainforest trees, only a _______ (faint/strong) signal could be heard. 3. A ___________ (negligible/) (.5%) number of study participants reported negative side effects from the drug. 4. The addition of gravel to the cement had little effect on the samples strength; likewise, the resistance was _______(hardly/considerably) affected. 5. A very ______(slight/marked) increase (.03) was recorded, but this increase _________ (fully/barely) had an affect. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html]] Writing the discussion section of a research paper Outline Beginning the Discussion Middle of the Discussion Taking Credit For Accomplishments of the Study Indicating the Novelty of the Study Noting Similarity in Findings Noting Differences in Findings Explaining Why Certain Results Were Obtained Concluding the Discussion Discussing Limitations Possible Applications of the Findings A Call for Future Studies Concluding Statement Acknowledgements The quality of the writing of the discussion will heavily influence whether a journal accepts a paper for publication; consequently, great care should be taken in writing this section(Goldbort, R., 2006). While there are several common patterns typically followed in discussions, there are also a wide variety of forms. This lack of structure makes the discussion the most challenging section to write. One danger in such a broad undefined structure is that it can result in a rambling verbose discussion. Consequently, journal editors commonly find many unnecessary details in this section. While revising the English of hundreds of research papers, I have found the greatest number of stylistic and grammatical errors in the discussion section. Perhaps this is because authors struggle with the lack of structure as well as the complexities of interpreting and synthesizing their findings in relation to the larger field. Consequently, I suspect that the authors pay less attention to grammar and style issues in this chapter because they are overwhelmed by other issues. By using the common rhetorical patterns of the discussion reviewed in this chapter as a guide, you should be able to avoid some of the confusion and lack of structure of the discussion section. Before reviewing specific topics and patterns, some general features of discussions should be pointed out. One distinct feature of the discussion section is that it is characterized by a series of points , rather than facts as in the results section (Swales and Feaks, 2004). These points are interpretive rather than descriptive as in the factual reporting in the results section. Another general feature of the discussion section is that compared to the results section, it tends to be: more abstract, general, theoretical, related to the real world, concerned with practical applications and implications, as well as engaged in dialogue with the larger field of study (Swales and Feaks, 2004). The discussion section is where you will draw out, delineate and consolidate the meaning of the results, as well as tactfully dialogue with the broader community of your field and attempt to build community consensus on the meaning of your findings (Swales and Feaks, 2004) It should also be pointed out that while the result section will present more concrete and specific quantitative data, the discussion should present more general comments about the findings, introduced by formulaic phrases such as these: In general, we saw that... Overall, we observed that... On average, we found that.... By and large, we found that... On the whole, we found that... We found that X tends to... In addition to considering the general features of discussions mentioned above, it may be helpful to think of the discussion as a story, and like other clear and coherent stories, the discussion has a beginning, middle and end (Zeiger, 1999) In the beginning of the story, you will introduce the reader to your original purpose, and then name your major findings and present results that support these findings. In the middle, you may show how other work supports your findings; report unexpected results; report on the novelty of the your work; explain conflicting results; suggest why your results are the way they are; explain how results of other studies do not agree with your findings, as well as defending your proposed answer against other possible answers to your main research question. At the end of the story, you may also discuss the limits of the method and validity of the assumptions as well as describing applications or implications of your findings. There are also three common devices discussed in chapter 9 that can be used to give coherency to the various topics of the discussion. First you can guide the reader from one topic to the next by using topic sentences. Second, you can use subheadings to identify the general outline for the reader. Third, you can repeat key ideas to connect one paragraph to the next. See chapter 9 for more details about topic sentences, subheadings and repeating key ideas to create coherency. Beginning the Discussion There are three common patterns used to begin a discussion. The first pattern begins the discussion by addressing the statement of purpose or question that directed the study (Zieger, 1999). In this study, we determined that asymptomatic cigarette smokers exhale more H2O2 than healthy nonsmokers. We found that multiplex ELISAs are more precise, cost effective and labor saving compared to conventional ELISAs. The second pattern is to restate the original research question or statement of purpose, followed by the main findings. This study aimed to determine whether asymptomatic cigarette smokers exhale more H2O2 than healthy nonsmokers. We determined that asymptomatic cigarette smokers exhale more H2O2 than healthy nonsmokers The objective of this study is to compare results of conventional ELISAs with the results of multiplex ELISAs. We found that multiplex ELISAs are more precise, cost-effective and labor-saving compared to conventional ELISAs. A third common pattern includes a brief summary of the context of the research, followed by the findings. This pattern is preferred since it is less blunt than beginning with naming the findings in the first sentence. It is also quickly places the work in a larger meaningful context without the detail of the introduction. This can be as short as one sentence or two sentences at most. Previous studies have found that ...... However we found that.... If you choose one of these three popular patterns, you will need to follow by reporting the major findings and then immediately provide the results that support these findings. Note that major findings that you will list in the discussion are not the same as the results. The major findings will be a general summary and synthesis of the data. Findings are more general interpretations of results. The results will be a more elaborate set of data obtained from your experiments. You will need to report as much of your results that will justify your findings to the reader and no more than this. (Zieger, 1999) It should be mentioned that other less common strategies could also be used for beginning the discussion. Another pattern could be to restate the original research question or statement of purpose, followed by a brief summary of the method, followed by the findings. In addition to these common patterns, a wide range of patterns can be found in discussion sections of actual published papers, including a review of the literature; stating economic and social importance of the topic; and reflecting on the site of the study (Swales and Feaks, 2004). You may consider different ways to begin the discussion, depending on the nature of your paper and the results you found. You can choose a pattern that makes your discussion sound most compelling. For example, it may be important to discuss the method that you used because this method is what distinguishes your work from previous studies. Likewise, you may wish to focus on the site location of your study if it seems particularly relevant to your findings. The point is that whatever way you begin the discussion, you should choose a strategy that best suits presenting your unique work. However, the first two patterns mentioned above are the most commonly used and are considered highly effective since they clearly guide the reader by going directly to the purpose of the study, followed by the main findings. (Zieger, 1999) While you have a certain choice and flexibility in beginning the discussion, there are some strategies that you should avoid: do not create a second introduction, nor repeat what you should have reported in detail in the results. A second introduction can be confusing to the reader, as well as a waste of print space. The only case where you may consider writing another introduction would be when you reader may be confused by the complexity of the results. A brief introduction may help re-orient the reader in this case. The results should have been summarized in the results section. While a certain amount of repetition of the results is inevitable and even necessary, the discussion should restate results in general terms as an entry-point into interpreting and making some general points about the results. (Matthews, J. R., 2007). This beginning section may be presented, ideally, in as little as one paragraph. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] @font-face { font-family: "Arial"; }@font-face { font-family: "Courier New"; }@font-face { font-family: "Times"; }@font-face { font-family: "Wingdings"; }@font-face { font-family: "Verdana"; }@font-face { font-family: "Tahoma"; }@font-face { font-family: "Gill Sans"; }@font-face { font-family: "MS Gothic"; }p.MsoNormal, li.MsoNormal, div.MsoNormal { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }h1 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 14pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-style: italic; }h2 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; line-height: 150%; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 16pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-style: italic; }h3 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }h4 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; line-height: 150%; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 48pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-style: italic; }h5 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 14pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: normal; }h6 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 24pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoHeading7, li.MsoHeading7, div.MsoHeading7 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 28pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; }p.MsoHeading8, li.MsoHeading8, div.MsoHeading8 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 10pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; }p.MsoHeading9, li.MsoHeading9, div.MsoHeading9 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt 0.25in; line-height: 150%; page-break-after: avoid; font-size: 20pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; }p.MsoNormalIndent, li.MsoNormalIndent, div.MsoNormalIndent { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt 0.5in; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoFootnoteText, li.MsoFootnoteText, div.MsoFootnoteText { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 10pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoCommentText, li.MsoCommentText, div.MsoCommentText { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 10pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoHeader, li.MsoHeader, div.MsoHeader { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoFooter, li.MsoFooter, div.MsoFooter { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoCaption, li.MsoCaption, div.MsoCaption { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; }span.MsoFootnoteReference { vertical-align: super; }span.MsoCommentReference { }p.MsoEndnoteText, li.MsoEndnoteText, div.MsoEndnoteText { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: justify; font-size: 10pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoList, li.MsoList, div.MsoList { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt 0.25in; text-indent: -0.25in; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoListBullet, li.MsoListBullet, div.MsoListBullet { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: justify; font-size: 10pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoList2, li.MsoList2, div.MsoList2 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt 0.5in; text-indent: -0.25in; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoListBullet2, li.MsoListBullet2, div.MsoListBullet2 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt 0.5in; text-indent: -0.25in; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoTitle, li.MsoTitle, div.MsoTitle { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: center; line-height: 200%; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; font-style: italic; }p.MsoBodyText, li.MsoBodyText, div.MsoBodyText { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 48pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; font-style: italic; }p.MsoBodyTextIndent, li.MsoBodyTextIndent, div.MsoBodyTextIndent { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: justify; text-indent: 27.75pt; font-size: 14pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; }p.MsoBodyText2, li.MsoBodyText2, div.MsoBodyText2 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; color: black; }p.MsoBodyText3, li.MsoBodyText3, div.MsoBodyText3 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; line-height: 150%; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-style: italic; }p.MsoBodyTextIndent2, li.MsoBodyTextIndent2, div.MsoBodyTextIndent2 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt 28.35pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoBodyTextIndent3, li.MsoBodyTextIndent3, div.MsoBodyTextIndent3 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt 0.25in; line-height: 150%; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }a:link, span.MsoHyperlink { color: blue; text-decoration: underline; }a:visited, span.MsoHyperlinkFollowed { color: purple; text-decoration: underline; }strong { }em { }p.MsoDocumentMap, li.MsoDocumentMap, div.MsoDocumentMap { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; background: none repeat scroll 0% 0% navy; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoCommentSubject, li.MsoCommentSubject, div.MsoCommentSubject { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 10pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; }p.MsoAcetate, li.MsoAcetate, div.MsoAcetate { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 8pt; font-family: Tahoma; }span.Heading1Char { font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; font-style: italic; }span.Heading2Char { font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; font-style: italic; }span.Heading3Char { font-family: Times; font-weight: bold; }span.Heading4Char { font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; font-style: italic; }span.Heading5Char { font-family: Arial; }span.Heading6Char { font-family: Times; font-weight: bold; }span.Heading7Char { font-family: Times; font-weight: bold; }span.Heading8Char { font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; }span.Heading9Char { font-family: Times; font-weight: bold; }span.BodyTextIndentChar { font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; }span.EndnoteTextChar { }span.BodyText2Char { font-family: Arial; color: black; }span.BodyTextIndent2Char { }span.BodyTextChar { font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; font-style: italic; }span.FooterChar { }span.FootnoteTextChar { font-family: Courier; }span.BodyTextIndent3Char { font-family: Times; }span.BodyText3Char { font-family: Times; font-style: italic; }span.HeaderChar { font-family: Times; }p.Text, li.Text, div.Text { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: justify; text-indent: 10.1pt; line-height: 105%; font-size: 10pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }span.DocumentMapChar { font-family: Helvetica; background: none repeat scroll 0% 0% navy; }span.cesartextoresposta1 { font-family: Verdana; color: black; font-weight: normal; }span.TitleChar { font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; font-style: italic; }p.Byline, li.Byline, div.Byline { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 48pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; font-weight: bold; font-style: italic; }span.CommentTextChar { font-family: Times; }span.CommentSubjectChar { font-family: Times; font-weight: bold; }span.BalloonTextChar { font-family: Tahoma; }div.Section1 { page: Section1; }ol { margin-bottom: 0in; }ul { margin-bottom: 0in; } Middle of the Discussion The beginning of the discussion includes renaming initial research questions and stating the main findings and naming the results that support your findings followed by the middle section of the discussion. The organization of this middle section is typically organized from most to least important topics. This section will take up the great majority of the discussion. Below we will consider several possible topics that may be relevant to your discussion. As in the beginning of the discussion, several of these topics are optional: the nature of your paper and the findings will determine whether you need to address these topics, as well as the degree of importance of each topic. Taking Credit For Accomplishments of the Study The first topic we will consider is taking credit for the accomplishments of your study, followed by an in depth consideration of hedging. Often one sentence can summarize the accomplishments of a study: In this study , we showed that postnatal neuroretinas contained retinal stem cells which are part of the radial glia population. Here we show that over the past 20 years, all the trends in the Sun that could have had an in?uence on the Earths climate have been in the opposite direction to that required to explain the observed rise in global mean temperatures. Since accomplishments commonly add to what has been extensively studied in your field, it is also common to acknowledge and cite the accomplishments of previous studies . Indicating the Novelty the Study It is also optional to point out the novelty of the study. This should have been done in the introduction where you indicate how your study fills a neglected niche in your area of study. If you want to mention this again, you may name what has been done previously and note how your work adds to this. You may have seen this phrase commonly used to introduce the novelty of a study: For the first time we report that... Some guidebooks advise against using this type of sentence since it is possible that the same or similar research exists in the literature in another country in English or some other language. If however you feel the need to make such a claim, you may choose a more cautious hedged version of this sentence: To the best of our knowledge, this is the first study to... Additionally, the following phrases can be used to indicate that your findings are a novel solution to a long-standing problem: These results provide insight into the issue of X. These results further explicate the issue of X. These findings shed light on the issue of X. These findings cast light on the issue of X. In order to report very dramatic solutions to former problems in the field, you may use the following phrases and sentences. However, read the section on hedging in the discussion section that follows. Use these types of sentences carefully and with discretion: These are groundbreaking findings in regards to the origins of X. These findings represent a sea change in regards to the origins of X. These findings overturn the conventional paradigm explaining the origin of X. Other phrases can also be used to express that a new direction can be taken after considering the new findings: In light of these findings, it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. Considering these findings it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. Taking into account these findings it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. In view of these findings, it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. Do not literally translate similar expressions from Portuguese: Based on these findings, it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. NOT: With base in these findings, it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. NOT: Based these findings, it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. Consequently , it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. In this regard, it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. In this respect , it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. NOT: In this way, it seems reasonable to modify our approach to X. NOT: In this line... NOT: In this perspective... Exercise 1 Revise the sentences below involving phrases used to highlight. 1. This brings up a whole bunch of questions about the defective mechanism. 2. These findings point the need for further understanding of X. 3. These findings show why its important to look at XYZ. Noting Similarities in Findings As mentioned above, taking credit for your accomplishments, may involve reporting studies with similar findings as yours. When discussing findings that are similar to those of yours, it is typical to use sentences like these: These findings are consistent with other studies. (Farias, 2007) These results agree with those of other researchers. (1, 2, 5, 7) Our results were similar to those of Olivera et al. These results concur with other studies. (6, 9) We share the view of Smith and Jones in regards to this issue. Regarding our results, we subscribe to the common belief that X causes Y. Our results confirmed the findings of Wilson et al. (5) Turner and colleagues suggest that X causes Y, likewise or findings suggest the same. However, do not literally translate the typical phrases used in Portuguese to express this idea of agreement because they are not correct in English: These findings are consistent with other studies. (1, 2, 5, 7) NOT: These findings according with other studies. NOT: These findings are in concordance to other studies. NOT: These findings collaborate to other studies. NOT: These findings combine to other studies. Note that the verbs collaborate, concordance, combine and may look like certain words in Portuguese verbs, but in English their meaning is different. See the section on false cognates in chapter 3 for more information on this topic. Note that certain comparative words such as when and as are unnecessary and can be omitted in comparisons: X was more effective than Y in removing the contaminants. X was more effective in removing the contaminants compared to Y. NOT: X was more effective in removing the contaminants when compared to Y. NOT: X was more effective in removing the contaminants as compared to Y. Also be careful not to misuse the verb observe when reporting results. You can obtain results but not observe results: We obtained similar results as Martinelli et al. NOT: W e observed similar results as Martinelli et al. Noting Differences in Findings In addition to reporting on studies with similar findings as yours, you may also be a need to discuss differences of your findings with other studies. A good strategy would involve acknowledging the findings of other studies while explaining why your finds are more accurate or appropriate: Although Smith et al. report that this adhesive was sufficiently hydrophobic, our findings indicate otherwise. There are several possible explanations for this. There are several ways to express differences, discrepancies or disagreements. First, simply add the word not to the sentences above: Our results were not consistent with other studies (1,3,5). Our results did not concur with other studies (1,3,5). Alternately, consider these sentences for expressing differences: Our findings are at variance with Jones et al. Our findings differed from Jones et al. (1,3,5). We found that x cause y, as opposed to Jones et al (1999). Albeit Preston and others found that x caused y, our results suggest the contrary. Even though it is widely believed that x causes y; nevertheless our findings offer a compelling alternative. These findings raise the issue as to whether Farias is correct in claiming that X causes Y. Our results raise a question as to whether Farias is correct in claiming that X causes Y. (Note the similarity to the Portuguese: Gera uma pergunta) Our results call into question Fariass claim that X causes Y. Our results put into question Fariass claim that X causes Y. (less formal) Our results raised doubts about Fariass claim that X causes Y. Be careful with common phrases that have different meaning, but look similar. For example, in contrast is probably the most commonly used phrase in research papers to point out differences in findings: In contrast to Smith et al., we found this method to be effective. Contrary to means conflicting with or counter to and it often appears as a collocation as in the boldface words below: Contrary to popular belief, pre-school children do not seem to be as physically active as previously thought. On (or quite ) the contrary is used to intensify a denial of what has just been implied or stated: Despite the extra-support, students performed not better than the control. On the contrary, roughly 23% performed even worse. To the contrary with the opposite meaning or implication: Despite medical advice to the contrary , many people believed this homeopathic medicine could help them. In chapter 7, we recommended using the active voice, especially in case where the passive voice is vague or confusing. In the discussion section in general where it is common to interpret findings, and especially in cases where you are disagreeing with the findings of others, you can use the active voice and the subject pronoun we to indicate clearly and strongly that this is the opinion of your group and not a universally accepted truth. Note this pattern below: Notwithstanding the findings of previous studies, we propose conversely that x causes y. NOT: Notwithstanding the findings of previous studies, it has been shown conversely that x causes y. Notice some other examples of formulaic sentences using the subject pronoun we and the active voice: Contrary to Jones et al, we argue this outcome is more precise. As opposed to Jones et al, we argue that... Some authors have told me that they were taught early on in their writing career to never use the pronoun we in scientific papers . While there may be several places in a research paper such as the methods section where the passive voice is prescribed, the active voice can, and sometimes should, be used throughout the text, particularly in the introduction, results, and discussion. For example, high impact journals such as Science and Nature prescribe using the active voice whenever possible to be more direct and clear. Explaining Why Certain Results Were Obtained Another possible topic for the discussion is reporting why certain results were obtained. This may include explaining unexpected findings, which can be major or minor. This could involve a certain amount of speculation as to why you obtained these unexpected findings: The lack of relation between infertility and cocaine abuse were unexpected. We propose three possible explanations. First... You may also need to name results obtained that do not support your main finding. This may involve showing how these results in fact may not conflict with your main findings. Sometimes a direct and simple declaration of inexplicable findings is appropriate: We simply do not have a good explanation for having found poorer soils at 300 m altitude on less steep slopes of the Coastal Atlantic Forest. http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] @font-face { font-family: "Arial"; }@font-face { font-family: "Times"; }@font-face { font-family: "Verdana"; }@font-face { font-family: "Verdana"; }@font-face { font-family: "Gill Sans"; }@font-face { font-family: "Times-Roman"; }p.MsoNormal, li.MsoNormal, div.MsoNormal { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: Times; }p.MsoFooter, li.MsoFooter, div.MsoFooter { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoEndnoteText, li.MsoEndnoteText, div.MsoEndnoteText { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: justify; font-size: 10pt; font-family: "Times New Roman"; }p.MsoBodyTextIndent, li.MsoBodyTextIndent, div.MsoBodyTextIndent { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; text-align: justify; text-indent: 27.75pt; font-size: 14pt; font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; }p.MsoBodyText2, li.MsoBodyText2, div.MsoBodyText2 { margin: 0in 0in 0.0001pt; font-size: 12pt; font-family: Arial; color: black; }span.BodyTextIndentChar { font-family: Arial; font-weight: bold; }span.EndnoteTextChar { }span.BodyText2Char { font-family: Arial; color: black; }span.FooterChar { }.MsoChpDefault { font-size: 10pt; }div.WordSection1 { page: WordSection1; }ol { margin-bottom: 0in; }ul { margin-bottom: 0in; } Concluding the Discussion The great majority of the discussion section should be devoted to interpreting the meaning of the results, which also involves strengthening these interpretations by synthesizing them with other related studies from the field that support them. After completing this task, it is common to conclude the discussion. It is recommended that you do not abruptly end the discussion by simply calling for further studies (Zeiger, 1999). A stronger conclusion could also mention limitations of the study; speculate on implications for possible future applications and finally, make specific recommendations related to future studies, as well as restating the major findings of the study. Discussing Limitations Discussing the limits of the studies method or the validity of the results is optional, but a fairly common practice. Although you may think that discussing the limitations of your study is counter-productive to the overall goal of consolidating your interpretation of the results, there are instances where acknowledging the obvious limits of a study could deflate criticisms of the reader and journal editor and ultimately make your claims more compelling (Swales, 2004). If you choose to name limitations, consider focusing on what can be concluded from the data and not the overall weakness of study as in the example below: The positive effects attributed to the dance/movement therapy in this case study of an Multiple Sclerosis patient may be viewed with caution. Some implications of the findings of this single study may not be generalized to a broader cross section of this population . Comparable investigations using an equivalent methodology must be undertaken, with a large sample of MS patients, before more conclusive inferences can be made. Imagine some of the most critical objections your reader may have, and then thoroughly addressing them, is a very powerful strategy that may work to deflate much of the criticism of your work. If you are so close to your work you may sometimes have trouble imagining criticism, yet it can help if you imagine yourself as a reader who is invested in a different outcome than what your paper implies. What might be their response? You can consider at least three general types of objections. ( Alley, M. 1996) . First, is your paper focused on a single cause-effect relation? Consider addressing or at least acknowledging other research that considers other possible causes for your topic. Second, are there other counterexamples to your thesis in the literature? Consider acknowledging them. Third, is it possible that the reader may question the definition of the terms of your work? Consider addressing this as well. See chapter 14 on Qualifying language, more specifically concession clauses. Such acknowledgment of another perspective might be as simple as the sentence below: Notwithstanding contrary evidence of other studies, we conclude that X plays a role in the development of Y. Although other researches propose alternative mixtures, we chose X as the most representative sample for this task. Possible Applications of the Findings Another optional topic for the conclusion of the discussion is speculating about applications of the findings. Note how the boldface words are qualified and modest: These results may have practical applications for algorithms involving large networks of low-performance hardware equipped with wireless communication. Despite the minor limits of this study, we believe our findings may contribute to innovations in the field of industrial recycling of concrete slag waste. A Call for Future Studies Another optional topic for the conclusion involves calling for future studies. This is also a hedging strategy that acknowledges the limits of the study and proposes the need for further studies. Such strategies typically look like these examples: These shortcomings of our study suggest the need to delve deeper into this issue in future studies . Further studies will be necessary to determine whether long-term Zanokrik use may indeed reduce the risk of endometrial carcinoma. Future studies will be necessary to determine the actual reasons for the recent decline in annual SIB mortality. More studies are needed to determine whether these unexpected positive effects are due to a placebo effect. These ambiguous elements in our findings will need to be investigated further in future studies. Women with advanced maternal age have an increased risk of stillbirth, but further studies are needed to determine the causes. More data are required to determine if these results are unique to this particular group of participants. These findings only highlight the need for further studies. Do not confuse farther and further in this type of sentence: farther refers to greater concrete measurable distance, whereas further refers to a greater degree in regards to abstract concepts. See chapter 7 on commonly confused words for further explanation and examples. A call for future studies that names specific recommendations will be more interesting and compelling than a general one: General: Future studies will be needed to further understand this drug. Specific: In regards to future research , well-conducted randomized controlled trials will be essential to establish the effectiveness of Serizone in depressed adolescents. Concluding Statement Ending the paper with a call for future studies can be somewhat dull and anti-climatic. A stronger ending would rename the main finding. As in the examples below: Overall, people who consumed high amounts of saturated fats had 36% higher relative rates of pancreatic cancer compared with those who consumed low amounts (BBC News, 2009) In conclusion, we found an easy method for the synthesis of compounds derived from 1,2,4-triazoles with good performance through the use of agents such as EDC and HOBT. The operational simplicity of this method and the good yield of the products make it valuable. Additionally, this reaction eliminates the use of toxic reagents such as lead tetraacetate or phosphorus oxychloride with each reaction. We propose a procedure that can be used in the synthesis of new compounds with pharmacological activity ( Gildardo Rivera , 2009). Note that the concluding statement is often a single statement summarizing the main findings of your study. Miller recommends that the concluding statements are as general as possible, paraphrasing and simplyfing the specific numerical data and technical language that may have been used in the methods or analytic sections of the text, providing the reader with the most general outline of the work, as well as connecting to more real world applications and considerations (Miller, J. E., 2004). You can use some of the formulaic phrases below to form your own concluding statement. Our findings highlight the importance of.... In conclusion, we found that... In summary, we found that... Overall, we conclude that... Acknowledgements The acknowledgement section is typically used to thank anyone who made a meaningful or substantial contribution to the paper. In the acknowledgments, you may wish to thank a sponsor such as FAPESP or CNPq for providing funding. You may also wish to thank other researchers, technicians, lab mates, or anyone who contributed to your paper. This may include someone who loaned you equipment, provided critical feedback on the paper, or even revised the English of the text. You should read your target journals guideline for authors for specifications for writing the acknowledgments. You may find some guidelines like these: The Acknowledgments page: Include brief statements about granting agencies, important aid received from institutions, and any potential conflicts of interest (as detailed in the LO Ethics statement section 3.4 and 3.4.1). Thank anyone who made a substantial contribution to the work (e.g., data collection, analysis, or writing or editing assistance) but who did not fulfill the authorship criteria, along with their specific contributions. You are responsible for ensuring that all persons named in the Acknowledgments section know and agree to being identified there (since it may be interpreted as endorsement of the data or conclusions). If the journal does not provide guidelines, you might read acknowledgements from other papers for ideas on how to write yours or you may consider using some of the common formulaic sentences found in this acknowledgement: We wish to thank Professors Ted E. Bear and A. Nony Mous for their careful reading and feedback on the paper. We also want to thank Dr. H. Simpson for assisting with DNA sequencing and bioinformatics analysis. We also want acknowledge that this work would not be possible without the generous funding and support of FAPESP (The State of Sao Paulo Research Foundation). Finally, we wish to thank Jim Hesson of Academic English Solutions for revising the English. Exercise 2 In this chapter, we have reviewed numerous formulaic sentences that are commonly used in a research paper. For practice in using these phrases correctly, try correcting the various errors below involving formulaic phrases from research papers. 1. Some economists have pointed that low inflation is not necessarily a good thing. 2. Although to a low extent, the disruption was related to worker experience. 3. Technical advances in the last years have drastically improved the efficiency and capability for storing food. 4. Pesticides have been used everywhere more and more. 5. These conductors have a role on the final outcome. 6. It remains unknown whether they have an effect in skin cancer. 7. The former were feed a supplement in their diet, while the ladder were not. 8. The present evidences support a role of polyamines in X-disease. 9. With relation to X, we found that... 10. In the last decades, numerous studies have shown that x causes y 11. One of such factors is the influences of weathers fluctuations. 12. TRIR spectroscopy is especially sensitive to compounds with carbonyl ligands and permits an insight into the problem of X. 13. As said before, these findings are not consistent with the literature. 14. Our findings put a little more light on this issue. 15. The problem of X needs a deep understanding of Y. This chapter reviewed some typical rhetorical conventions of the discussion section of research papers. If you have done the exercises and studied carefully, you should notice an improvement in your ability to write research papers in English. If you have read through quickly, you may want to go back and review whatever sections you did not study carefully. While everything you have read here, may not be applicable to your field of study or writing. In that case, take what is useful and simply disregard the rest. In time, hopefully writing will even become a pleasurable experience. If you are going to make research or academia your profession, ultimately, you a great deal of your time will be devoted to writing, particularly in English. Hopefully the lessons you learned here will serve you while writing your own papers. Enjoy the adventure and good luck with publishing! http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] Tips for Responding to an Editor's Request for a Revision of a Manuscript What do you do when you submit your paper to a journal, and you receive a letter asking you to revise and resubmit it? As a copyeditor, I have read a fair amount of these messages to various authors. And sometimes the authors of the reviewed paper complain quite bitterly that the editors/referees are being outlandish and unfair in the criticism. Admittedly, an occasional referee may be too harsh, critical, arrogant or unprofessional in the tone of their message. Why w ould they do this? Who knows why people in general may do rude things, no less a journal editor or referee who should show professional etiquette. Yet more importantly, I feel your response to such messages should take the higher road, being generous, calm and diplomatic as possible, and not stooping to the same level by writing back angry insulting comments in response. I recommend a cautious diplomatic response because your ultimate goal is to get the paper published, and if they are just asking you to make some reasonable changes, it is not worth responding to the rude comments of the referees. Another reason I recommend a moderate diplomatic response, is because I have also seen situations where the authors respond to what they perceived as an insult or slight by the referee, but when I read the message of the referee, I saw no such slight. Perhaps it is easy to misread an insult where there is none if English is not your native tongue. Also, I think this may occur because authors are very close to their research, having put their blood, sweat, and tears into the work, so when they hear criticism of something they are generally pleased with, if not quite proud of, they may be overly sensitive when they expected a more positive reception from the editor, and so they may not be able to hear nuance in the criticism, and instead of hearing the positive, they hear only the negative, which is all perfectly natural and understandable. I have seen some cases where authors are quite defensive about a studys shortcomings pointed out by the referee, yet the authors will assume it is a nationalistic differences between the authors and the referees. I have heard many accusations about referees from developed nations not respecting the research from certain developing nations. While there may be some truths to these claims, I think there is also quite a lot of defensive reactivity when authors receive critical comments. As Swales and Feak recommend, it may be best to just read the comments, and let some time pass before responding. Not much is too be gained by a vitriolic response. Most of these referees are volunteering to do this work, so I think they mostly have good intentions, yet perhaps they may not realize their tone is overly harsh or possibly arrogant. I think sometimes it is most difficult for a junior researcher who may be submitting their first research paper, and they may have inadvertently brought unrealistic expectations, believing their work is beyond criticism and without problems. In most cases journal editors can be quite positive about a paper, but they seem to be nitpicking when they go on and on for pages pointing out every minor error they see. Although this may be tough on some egos, ultimately, I think they have the best intentions and want the final research to meet high standards. You can even see such attention to detailed criticism as a compliment ultimately, since they are showing a certain care and concern. And even in cases where ultimately the comments of are referee are entirely irrelevant, incorrect, impolite, biased and prejudices, I still recommend using cautious comments like this in response: While we have fully considered referee Bs comments about X, we respectfully disagree and wish to refer him to recent studies demonstrating X. OR: We politely beg to differ with referee As criticism of our method. We wish to note that our method is fully consistent with the literature on this method. Here are some general guidelines for corresponding with the journal editor quoted directly from Navigating Academia: Writing Supporting Genres (John M. Swales, Christine Feak): 1. Remember that an invitation to revise is usually a positive sign. So do not take criticisms personally. 2. Read the editors letter and reviewers comments carefully. 3. If the editor suggests getting help with the English, choose someone who has some understanding of you research area as well as a good knowledge of the language. 4. Respond to each of the major comments. (Minor ones such as spelling corrections or corrections to references do not need detailed commentary). 5. In your response, help the editor by using detailed references to the text such as p. 2 first para. 6. Thank people for useful suggestions but do not automatically defer to the editor or reviewers. If you disagree with a comment, explain why. 7. If you have made additional changes not suggested by the reviewers briefly explain what they are and why you have made them. 8. If you have been asked to revise and resubmit, do so as quickly as convenient. 9. Explain what you are doing about any page charges or fees, if this is appropriate. 10. If you do not plan to revise, inform the editor of you decision. Other issues to think about include, careful consideration of what the editors want you to change, and whether you chances of being accepted for publication are good after these changes are made. As Annesley puts it, "...Some rejection letters (Example 2) offer an opportunity to resubmit. You still have your foot in the door, but you need to carefully consider whether there is a realistic chance that you can improve the paper to the reviewers' satisfaction. After finding numerous deficiencies, reviewers sometimes stop providing comments because their recommendations are clear by the time they are partway through the paper. If you decide to resubmit, it is possible that (1) the reviewers already have a poisoned view of the work and (2) you will receive additional criticisms of your work when the reviewers look at other parts of the paper they did not read carefully during the first round of reviews. The third example is also a revise-and-resubmit letter, but it tells you that the paper should be acceptable after you have satisfactorily responded to the reviewers' comments. In that case, it is in your best interests to improve the paper and send it back with minimal delay." Another point to consider is what issues are worth defending and insisting upon. Again, as Annesley points out, "If your scientific paper is typical, the reviewers will ask you to make more than one modification. Some changes you will agree are worthwhile, some you will think are irrelevant, and some you will disagree with. Even if you do not fully agree with the reviewers on some points, you need to choose your battles wisely. If a change to a sentence or paragraph requested by the reviewer does not affect the intended meaning, do your best to make the change. It does not hurt you and sends the message that you took their suggestions seriously; however, if you believe that a requested change will negatively affect the paper, go ahead and respectfully disagree. It is your name on the title page. But do not respond by stating that the reviewer is wrong without allowing the reviewer, wherever possible, to save face. Explain where the reviewer may have misinterpreted the section and that you want to keep the text intact. You might find, however, that as you explain the rationale for keeping the text as is, some of the wording and logic you use to respond to the reviewer might be worth adding to the paragraph in question to help the reader better understand the paper." From: http://www.clinchem.org/ content/57/4/551.full For further consideration also see: http:// eprints.nottingham.ac.uk/859/2/ How_to_reply_to _referees.pdf If you the journal editors request a review of the English of your paper, consider our service which provides a full guarantee that your paper will not be rejected due to the English: http:// www.academicenglishsolutions.co m/AES/Editing.html Finally, I am very curious to hear your experiences and suggestions about responding to editors requests to have your papers revised. Do you have any advice for the readers's here? http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] I am sharing an amusing series of Tweets called Overly Honest Methods. This post may be particularly funny for people in the natural and physical sciences, but there may be a little humor in there for everyone. Hope you enjoy: https://twitter.com/search?q=OverlyHonestMethods http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] If you are applying for a science job in the US, you should follow certain conventions employers expect from applicants. Although I usually give advice on writing scientific manuscripts, I have been getting queries lately on resumes and cover letters. I am not familiar with conventions for applying for jobs in other countries, but I have seen people applying for jobs in the US without using a cover letter. If you simply send a resume for a job without a cover letter, it is highly unlikely that an employer will respond to you. Introducing yourself with a cover letter is standard practice in the US. If you are not sure about the form of the cover letter, you will need to write a letter in which you point out 2-3 things in your resume that are relevant to the job you are applying to. Also, point out 2-3 things in your personality or educational history that is relevant to this job. You can use phrases like, "As can be seen in my resume, I worked for 2 years as a....".  The cover letter serves as a bridge to connect your general lists of skills and experience found on your resume by pointing out how you are particularly suited for a certain job. While it's critical to use a cover letter to point out your skills, work history and expertise, I also believe it is critical to mention personality features that make you suitable for the job. You may be surprised to know that many companies and HR directors are very interested in your personality and whether it will fit in with their team. While it's common for all applicants to have impressive technical skills, not everyone has the right personality for particular companies. Most companies can train you on the job if your skills don't fully match, but changing a personality is much trickier. So if you have the right personality, point this out too. Companies are fearful of hiring someone who is difficult, someone who may make others dread coming to work, so you should reassure them of how your personality is right for the job. Phrases like "I work well in teams", "I am considerate of others", "I am a good team player", "I work hard to be respectful and get along with my colleagues", etc., can be helpful. I should also mention that e rrors in cover letters or CVs, no matter how minor they may seem, are considered unprofessional; consequently, I would polish and improve your CV as much as possible. For expert advice on writing a cover letter for a job in science, I recommend Writing a Winning Cover Letter by John K Borchardt on Science Careers from Science Magazine. Below is an excerpt: The Match "An effective cover letter doesn't just emphasize your best qualities; it also shows how well those qualities are likely to mesh with the open position. Applicants should begin by reading advertisements for faculty positions carefully and be sure that their background and goals are appropriate for the position in question. You lose credibility if you can't make a case that you fit the ad, says Whitmire.If the cover letter is to be effective, it must definitely be tailored to the particular institution. There's no excuse for not writing a cover letter that shows how your education, experience, and interests fit with what the institution is seeking, warns Julia Miller Vick, co-author of the Academic Job Search Handbook (University of Pennsylvania Press, July 2001). Not doing this would reflect laziness, observes Horvitz. At best, adds Vick, a form letter or one that is generic doesn't accomplish much and leaves how the application is reviewed completely up to the reviewing committee." At worst, a generic cover letter can make you seem undesirable. While many people applying for academic positions tend to think that the review process is an evaluation of their previous work--how good is it?--the issue that is as important is the match," says Whitmire. "How will this person fit in here? The former is necessary, but the decision to interview will often be made upon research area or some other measure of fit to the department's needs at that moment in time. For the complete article click on the link below: http://sciencecareers.sciencemag.org/career_magazine/previous_issues/articles/2006_10_27/nodoi.10341484552738357724 For writing resumes (CVs) consider Tips for a Successful CV by Sarah A. Webb, (October 27, 2006) also from Science Careers from Science Magazine: Here is an excerpt: Basic CV do's and don'ts (for U.S. audiences)* Do: Include all relevant contact information: address, e-mail address, phone number, cell phone number. Include a comprehensive listing of professional experiences. Proofread for correct spelling and grammar. Use relatively simple and consistent formatting. Organize the document so that a reader can find important information quickly. Use reverse chronological order throughout the document. List all publications in the same reference style. Be sure references are up-to-date and that your references know about jobs you're applying for. Get feedback from colleagues, mentors, and career advisers. Don't: Use complicated formatting. Include certain personal information such as your Social Security number, date of birth, marital status, or number of children. Include information about unrelated hobbies or interests that doesn't show professional experience or qualifications. Pad your CV with extra words or spacing to make it appear longer. *Standards vary elsewhere, so get local advice. For the complete story click on the link below: http://sciencecareers.sciencemag.org/career_magazine/previous_issues/articles/2006_10_27/nodoi.10341484552738357724 Also simply do a search online for "form of cover letter" for more information on this topic. If you need a revision of your cover letter, resume, research paper or dissertation, check out our website for more information about our editing service or online classes by Skype: http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html Also keep in touch,  you can add us as a connection on Linkedin by submitting this email address: jim@AcademicEnglishSolutions.com http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] 1. ARRANGE FOR HOUSING Make arrangements to either move directly into housing (dormitory, apartment, sublet) or live somewhere temporarily, such as a hotel, or apartment sublet, while you search for permanent housing. Most universities provide temporary housing, but you need to make arrangements with them before you come. Contact the international student adviser office by email to get help in advance. If you plan to rent off-campus, explore the neighborhood before you rent. Is it safe? is it close to your classes and lab? Close to public transportation? Is it served by the university's own system? If you can't check these things out in-person, try to learn as much as possible from websites. For example, you can access transportation maps online, as well as maps that display high crime rate areas of cities and towns. Also look for other nearby conveniences such as a laundromat, post office, supermarket, convenience stores, banks, parks, libraries, coffee shops, or other services you may want to live near. Google map typically displays business and buildings located in a certain area. Yelp is an extremely useful website ( http://www.yelp.com ) that can be used to find any type of business in a particular area, and it can be used to find directions. You can find excellent reviews on Yelp by customers, which can give you a quick idea about whether you want to shop in a particular store or eat in a particular restaurant.  Craigslist is a great means of finding housing. If you have never heard of it in your country, you should know that it is a very popular website and service used in the US.  If you plan to stay less than a year, search for "sublets" or "short-term housing" 2. MEET WITH THE INTERNATIONAL STUDENT ADVISER Schedule an appointment after you arrive. Come prepared. Bring list of questions and ask for whatever information you need. Ask when the next student orientation sessions will be held. There will be three different sessions worth attending: -- One for all new students -- One especially for international students, and -- One to show all new students how to use the library. For graduate students, there will be mandatory academic orientation for you department, division, or school. Some orientation sessions are optional, but you should attend all you can. They are valuable and will save you time and effort later. 3. GET YOUR UNIVERSITY ID AND E-MAIL ACCOUNT Be sure to check your university e-mail account regularly. It is how faculty, staff and advisers will contact you for all university matters. if you maintain other e-mail accounts, such as those with Gmail or Hotmail, then you may wishy to forward their mail to your university account or your university mail to them. Whatever you choose, you should have a regular, easy way to check your official university account. 4. SET UP A LOCAL CELL-PHONE ACCOUNT Having a phone as soon as possible will be a great convenience that will allow you to make calls in your apartment search, as well as call utility companies (electric, gas, heat, internet, etc. See #7 below).  You will also need a phone to record names and numbers of new contacts (students, professors, adviser, administrators, etc.) as well as to give your number to others. So many business transactions are done by phone in the US, rather than by visiting some office. So this is important to take care of as soon as possible. Carefully check the different plans various phone companies offer; they vary greatly. Also, if you have a phone from your country, it will likely not function in the US as the technical specifications differ. Also, once you get a computer and internet account, you may want to use Skype for free international chats with your family and friends back home. 5. GET a SSIN, SSN, or ITIN. If you are not eligible to apply for a Social Security Number (SSN) as most international students are not, you are eligible to apply for an Individual Taxpayer Identification number (ITIN). An ITIN cannot be used like the SSN to apply for work, but it can be used as an identification card which will be helpful on rental applications, setting up a bank account, and other financial accounts. Here is the website for the Individual Taxpayer Identification number (ITIN): http://www.irs.gov/Individuals/Revised-Application-Standards-for-ITINs Here is a link to the online application: http://www.irs.gov/file_source/pub/irs-pdf/fw7.pdf 6. SET UP A LOCAL BANK ACCOUNT You will need an ID to open an account. You can use your ID from the university you will attend. You can also use an Individual Taxpayer Identification number mentioned above. You can also use a driver's license. Consider getting an international driver's license before you come to the US. Depsoit cash or traveler's checks in your new account so you have funds available immediately in your account. Your banks should treat a deposit of traveler's checks the same as a deposit of cash. That's why you should bring $2,000 or more in such checks, unless you can use a credit card or bankcard from home to withdraw that amount from a local teller machine (ATM, ABM) After you get your account, you can order personalized checks You can also order an ATM card for withdrawing cash from an automated teller machine.  ATM is the typical name used to refer to these machines located near business for quick cash withdrawals. You can also get the routing number from your bank, which is required for international wire transfers. If your funding agency in your native country intends to send you money, you will need this number to complete the transaction. This is critical for your regular survival, paying bills, purchasing food, paying rent, etc., etc. You can also purchase a debit card from your bank. 7. SET UP UTILITY ACCOUNTS FOR YOUR NEW APARTMENT. Utilites are all the services including electric, gas, water, phone, internet, TV and other services you will need in your new home. After you sign a lease to secure an apartment, you will need to call each utility company to get service in your name. You will need to let them know the date that you wish service to start. If you delay in this process, you may have no service (lights, electric, heat, phone, etc) for several days which can be quite challenging. In some cases, your new apartment may include the cost of utilities in the rent, but you should find this out as soon as possible. Typically, water or trash collection services are included in the rental fee, but not electricity or heat. Utility companies may require that you give a "security deposit" (money which can be used by the company if you decided to leave without paying). This is common if you don't have a long credit history in the US. Also, you will want to call the utility companies even before you move into your new apartment, and schedule that service be turned for the first day that you move into your new place. 8. MAKE A LIST OF EMERGENCY PHONE NUMBERS. You may want to store number in a notebook or phone under "in case of emergency" in case you were found unconscious and unable to communicate with a doctor or police. You can place numbers of your family and friends there. You may also want to have numbers to your consulate, university police, international student adviser, your doctor, your adviser, emergency numbers to your utility company (phone, electric) as well as bank. You can print out this list and keep in a place that is easily accessible. The general number for most emergencies is 911. This will connect you with the police, fire department, and ambulance service. 9. APPLY FOR A CREDIT CARD Sometimes it is difficult to get a credit card from major credit card companies in the US for international students who don't have a long credit history. In this case, it may be easier for someone to get card from Target, Walmart, a gas station such as Exxon. These cards can only be used in these stores, but once you establish good credit, you can then apply for a major credit card. A debit card is another option since it is easy to get from your bank. Unlike a credit card, it takes money directly from your bank account, but can be used like a credit card. One drawback is that they do not build your credit history. 10. TOUR YOUR NEW SCHOOL AND CITY Ask in the office of the international students if the school provides tours. These are quite common. You can also ask if they have self-guided tours and maps if you don't want to go with a group. Ask about safety issues if you school is located in an area with crime. Learn about the local supermarkets and shopping options. Keep and open mind about the food you find. While you may not find foods like those from your country, if you are flexible, you may find that they local food is of good quality and very tasty as well. Many practices that may be common in your country may be different in the US, so be attentive and again, be flexible. Learn about the local restaurants, post office, pharmacy, laundry mat, tailor, dry cleaner, shoe repair, clothing stores, computer, TV, stereo and electronic shops, public library, museums, parks, pools, bars, night clubs, coffee shops, liquor stores, malls, churches, meditation and yoga centers, gyms and fitness centers, hospitals, clinics, doctors, fire department, police station, bicycle shop, recreation and sporting goods equipment shops. Also, if you want to learn about the credibility and quality of service provided by any particular business, read about them on Yelp ( http://www.yelp.com ). You can find excellent reviews by customers, which can give you a quick idea about whether you want to shop in a particular store or eat in a particular restaurant. Yelp can also be used to find any type of business in a particular area, and it can be used to find directions. You can download this app for your phone on iTunes. If your are planning to stay a short time, consider buying slightly used or "second hand" furniture, clothes or other items that you can easily sell or give away when you move back to your country. This will save you lots of money. You can find many good deals on items at Craig's list (craigslist.org), as well as at stores like the GoodWill, and Salvation Army and any general "thrift shop".  Craig's list is a popular place to find jobs, apartments and buy a wide variety of used merchandise at inexpensive prices. You can also find many inexpensive good quality items at "tag sales", "garage sales" or "lawn sales". These are impromptu sales where people place items outside their home in the garage or on their lawn, and the prices are usually quite cheap. You can bargain and ask for a lower price, and often these are run by students who just want to get rid of their things at very low prices. You can also look for "flea markets". Also stores like IKEA, and Target generally have some fairly inexpensive furniture and other items. You can find good deals on furniture, computers, clothes, cars, etc. You can also learn about days that local museums are free, and restaurants that have "all you can eat" for one fee, as other means to save money. Universities will also have many free entertainment venues including music, speakers, movies, etc. You can also contact us at Academic English Solutions if you need to improve your English proficiency or take classes to prepare for the TOEFL, academic writing. We will also help you with communicate with advisers or international student officers in the US, revising your correspondence if needed, and offering practical advice. If any of the 10 items listed above are not clear, we can clarify and advise your further. We can give you basic and practical information related to the most universities in the US, as well as practical tips and suggestions on how to navigate life in the US. Contact us if you are having trouble organizing your visit, we can work as a liaison to connect you with the appropriate person, or explain certain customs or procedures common to the US. We also offer a wide variety of online English classes: http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/English_Classes.html In addition, we revise the English of scientific manuscripts, dissertations, and other academic texts. Read more about our editing service here: http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/Editing.html Contact us to schedule a free demonstration class online: http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html While I have added several of my own tips above, I  wish to gratefully acknowledge that the top ten suggestions mentioned here are primarily a paraphrasing of Succeeding as an International Student in the United States and Canada, by Charles Lipson. I highly recommend this book for anyone planning to do research or study in the US. It has many more practical tips. Here is a link to Amazon where you can find it at a discounted price: http://www.amazon.com/Succeeding-International-Student-Chicago-Academic/dp/0226484793/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8qid=1383320213sr=8-1keywords=succeeding+as+an+international+student+in+the+united+states+and+canada http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] My book, English for Research Papers: A Handbook for Brazilian Authors, is now available at Amazon, and I just wanted to invite you to review it there. Here is a link to the book: http://www.amazon.com/English-Research-Papers-Handbook-Brazilian-ebook/dp/B00GPT0FXW/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8qid=1384714433sr=8-1keywords=english+for+research+papers+a+handbook+for+brazilian+authors http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] I would be very grateful if you could repost and share this message with your connections, colleagues and students who might find my book useful. Below is a link to the book, English for Research Papers: A Handbook for Brazilian Authors. Muito obrigado! http://www.amazon.com/ English-Research-Papers-Handboo k-Brazilian-ebook/dp/ B00GPT0FXW/ ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8qid=13847953 03sr=8-1keywords=english+for +research+papers+a+handbook+fo r+brazilian+authors http://www.academicenglishsolutions.com/AES/home.html ]] 